<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<refset setid="iwslt2014-tst2010" srclang="german" trglang="english" refid="ref">
<doc docid="805" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/robert_gupta.html</url>
<description>Robert Gupta, violinist with the LA Philharmonic, talks about a violin lesson he once gave to a brilliant, schizophrenic musician -- and what he learned. Called back onstage later, Gupta plays his own transcription of the prelude from Bach's Cello Suite No. 1.</description>
<keywords>arts,brain,education,entertainment,live music,music,violin</keywords>
<talkid>805</talkid>
<title>Robert Gupta: Music is medicine, music is sanity</title>
<seg id="1"> One day, Los Angeles Times columnist Steve Lopez was walking along the streets of downtown Los Angeles when he heard beautiful music. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And the source was a man, an African-American man, charming, rugged, homeless, playing a violin that only had two strings. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And I'm telling a story that many of you know, because Steve's columns became the basis for a book, which was turned into a movie, with Robert Downey Jr. acting as Steve Lopez, and Jamie Foxx as Nathaniel Anthony Ayers, the Juilliard-trained double bassist whose promising career was cut short by a tragic affliction with paranoid schizophrenia. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Nathaniel dropped out of Juilliard, he suffered a complete breakdown, and 30 years later he was living homeless on the streets of Skid Row in downtown Los Angeles. </seg>
<seg id="5"> I encourage all of you to read Steve's book or to watch the movie to understand not only the beautiful bond that formed between these two men, but how music helped shape that bond, and ultimately was instrumental -- if you'll pardon the pun -- in helping Nathaniel get off the streets. </seg>
<seg id="6"> I met Mr. Ayers in 2008, two years ago, at Walt Disney Concert Hall. </seg>
<seg id="7"> He had just heard a performance of Beethoven's First and Fourth symphonies, and came backstage and introduced himself. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He was speaking in a very jovial and gregarious way about Yo-Yo Ma and Hillary Clinton and how the Dodgers were never going to make the World Series, all because of the treacherous first violin passage work in the last movement of Beethoven's Fourth Symphony. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And we got talking about music, and I got an email from Steve a few days later saying that Nathaniel was interested in a violin lesson with me. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now, I should mention that Nathaniel refuses treatment because when he was treated it was with shock therapy and Thorazine and handcuffs, and that scar has stayed with him for his entire life. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But as a result now, he is prone to these schizophrenic episodes, the worst of which can manifest themselves as and then disappearing for days, wandering the streets of Skid Row, exposed to its horrors, with the torment of his own mind unleashed upon him. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And Nathaniel was in such a state of agitation when we started our first lesson at Walt Disney Concert Hall -- he had a kind of manic glint in his eyes, he was lost. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And he was talking about invisible demons and smoke, and how someone was poisoning him in his sleep. </seg>
<seg id="14"> And I was afraid, not for myself, but I was afraid that I was going to lose him, that he was going to sink into one of his states, and that I would ruin his relationship with the violin if I started talking about scales and arpeggios and other exciting forms of didactic violin pedagogy. </seg>
<seg id="15"> So, I just started playing. </seg>
<seg id="16"> And I played the first movement of the Beethoven Violin Concerto. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And as I played, I understood that there was a profound change occurring in Nathaniel's eyes. </seg>
<seg id="18"> It was as if he was in the grip of some invisible pharmaceutical, a chemical reaction, for which my playing the music was its catalyst. </seg>
<seg id="19"> And Nathaniel's manic rage was transformed into understanding, a quiet curiosity and grace. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And in a miracle, he lifted his own violin and he started playing, by ear, certain snippets of violin concertos which he then asked me to complete -- Mendelssohn, Tchaikovsky, Sibelius. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And we started talking about music, from Bach to Beethoven and Brahms, Bruckner, all the B's, from Bartók, all the way up to Esa-Pekka Salonen. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And I understood that he not only had an encyclopedic knowledge of music, but he related to this music at a personal level. </seg>
<seg id="23"> He spoke about it with the kind of passion and understanding that I share with my colleagues in the Los Angeles Philharmonic. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And through playing music and talking about music, this man had transformed from the paranoid, disturbed man that had just come from walking the streets of downtown Los Angeles to the charming, erudite, brilliant, Juilliard-trained musician. </seg>
<seg id="25"> Music is medicine. Music changes us. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And for Nathaniel, music is sanity. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Because music allows him to take his thoughts and delusions and shape them through his imagination and his creativity, into reality. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And that is an escape from his tormented state. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And I understood that this was the very essence of art. </seg>
<seg id="30"> This was the very reason why we made music, that we take something that exists within all of us at our very fundamental core, our emotions, and through our artistic lens, through our creativity, we're able to shape those emotions into reality. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And the reality of that expression reaches all of us and moves us, inspires and unites us. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And for Nathaniel, music brought him back into a fold of friends. </seg>
<seg id="33"> The redemptive power of music brought him back into a family of musicians that understood him, that recognized his talents and respected him. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And I will always make music with Nathaniel, whether we're at Walt Disney Concert Hall or on Skid Row, because he reminds me why I became a musician. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Bruno Giussani: Thank you. Thanks. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Robert Gupta. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Robert Gupta: I'm going to play something that I shamelessly stole from cellists. </seg>
<seg id="39"> So, please forgive me. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="790" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_barber_how_i_fell_in_love_with_a_fish.html</url>
<description>Chef Dan Barber squares off with a dilemma facing many chefs today: how to keep fish on the menu. With impeccable research and deadpan humor, he chronicles his pursuit of a sustainable fish he could love, and the foodie's honeymoon he's enjoyed since discovering an outrageously delicious fish raised using a revolutionary farming method in Spain.</description>
<keywords>agriculture,biology,environment,food,health</keywords>
<talkid>790</talkid>
<title>Dan Barber: How I fell in love with a fish</title>
<seg id="1"> So, I've known a lot of fish in my life. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I've loved only two. </seg>
<seg id="3"> That first one, it was more like a passionate affair. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It was a beautiful fish: flavorful, textured, meaty, a bestseller on the menu. </seg>
<seg id="5"> What a fish. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Even better, it was farm-raised to the supposed highest standards of sustainability. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So you could feel good about selling it. </seg>
<seg id="8"> I was in a relationship with this beauty for several months. </seg>
<seg id="9"> One day, the head of the company called and asked if I'd speak at an event about the farm's sustainability. </seg>
<seg id="10"> "Absolutely," I said. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Here was a company trying to solve what's become this unimaginable problem for us chefs: How do we keep fish on our menus? </seg>
<seg id="12"> For the past 50 years, we've been fishing the seas like we clear-cut forests. </seg>
<seg id="13"> It's hard to overstate the destruction. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Ninety percent of large fish, the ones we love -- the tunas, the halibuts, the salmons, swordfish -- they've collapsed. </seg>
<seg id="15"> There's almost nothing left. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So, for better or for worse, aquaculture, fish farming, is going to be a part of our future. </seg>
<seg id="17"> A lot of arguments against it: Fish farms pollute -- most of them do anyway -- and they're inefficient. Take tuna, a major drawback. </seg>
<seg id="18"> It's got a feed conversion ratio of 15 to one. </seg>
<seg id="19"> That means it takes fifteen pounds of wild fish to get you one pound of farm tuna. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Not very sustainable. </seg>
<seg id="21"> It doesn't taste very good either. </seg>
<seg id="22"> So here, finally, was a company trying to do it right. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I wanted to support them. </seg>
<seg id="24"> The day before the event, I called the head of P.R. for the company. </seg>
<seg id="25"> Let's call him Don. </seg>
<seg id="26"> "Don," I said, "just to get the facts straight, you guys are famous for farming so far out to sea, you don't pollute." </seg>
<seg id="27"> "That's right," he said. "We're so far out, the waste from our fish gets distributed, not concentrated." </seg>
<seg id="28"> And then he added, "We're basically a world unto ourselves. </seg>
<seg id="29"> That feed conversion ratio? 2.5 to one," he said. </seg>
<seg id="30"> "Best in the business." </seg>
<seg id="31"> 2.5 to one, great. </seg>
<seg id="32"> "2.5 what? What are you feeding?" </seg>
<seg id="33"> "Sustainable proteins," he said. </seg>
<seg id="34"> "Great," I said. Got off the phone. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And that night, I was lying in bed, and I thought: What the hell is a sustainable protein? </seg>
<seg id="36"> So the next day, just before the event, I called Don. </seg>
<seg id="37"> I said, "Don, what are some examples of sustainable proteins?" </seg>
<seg id="38"> He said he didn't know. He would ask around. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Well, I got on the phone with a few people in the company; no one could give me a straight answer until finally, I got on the phone with the head biologist. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Let's call him Don too. </seg>
<seg id="41"> "Don," I said, "what are some examples of sustainable proteins?" </seg>
<seg id="42"> Well, he mentioned some algaes and some fish meals, and then he said chicken pellets. </seg>
<seg id="43"> I said, "Chicken pellets?" </seg>
<seg id="44"> He said, "Yeah, feathers, skin, bone meal, scraps, dried and processed into feed." </seg>
<seg id="45"> I said, "What percentage of your feed is chicken?" </seg>
<seg id="46"> Thinking, you know, two percent. </seg>
<seg id="47"> "Well, it's about 30 percent," he said. </seg>
<seg id="48"> I said, "Don, what's sustainable about feeding chicken to fish?" </seg>
<seg id="49"> There was a long pause on the line, and he said, "There's just too much chicken in the world." </seg>
<seg id="50"> I fell out of love with this fish. </seg>
<seg id="51"> No, not because I'm some self-righteous, goody-two shoes foodie. </seg>
<seg id="52"> I actually am. </seg>
<seg id="53"> No, I actually fell out of love with this fish because, I swear to God, after that conversation, the fish tasted like chicken. </seg>
<seg id="54"> This second fish, it's a different kind of love story. </seg>
<seg id="55"> It's the romantic kind, the kind where the more you get to know your fish, you love the fish. </seg>
<seg id="56"> I first ate it at a restaurant in southern Spain. </seg>
<seg id="57"> A journalist friend had been talking about this fish for a long time. </seg>
<seg id="58"> She kind of set us up. </seg>
<seg id="59"> It came to the table a bright, almost shimmering, white color. </seg>
<seg id="60"> The chef had overcooked it. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Like twice over. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Amazingly, it was still delicious. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Who can make a fish taste good after it's been overcooked? </seg>
<seg id="64"> I can't, but this guy can. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Let's call him Miguel -- actually his name is Miguel. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And no, he didn't cook the fish, and he's not a chef, at least in the way that you and I understand it. </seg>
<seg id="67"> He's a biologist at Veta La Palma. </seg>
<seg id="68"> It's a fish farm in the southwestern corner of Spain. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It's at the tip of the Guadalquivir river. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Until the 1980s, the farm was in the hands of the Argentinians. </seg>
<seg id="71"> They raised beef cattle on what was essentially wetlands. </seg>
<seg id="72"> They did it by draining the land. </seg>
<seg id="73"> They built this intricate series of canals, and they pushed water off the land and out into the river. </seg>
<seg id="74"> Well, they couldn't make it work, not economically. </seg>
<seg id="75"> And ecologically, it was a disaster. </seg>
<seg id="76"> It killed like 90 percent of the birds, which, for this place, is a lot of birds. </seg>
<seg id="77"> And so in 1982, a Spanish company with an environmental conscience purchased the land. </seg>
<seg id="78"> What did they do? </seg>
<seg id="79"> They reversed the flow of water. </seg>
<seg id="80"> They literally flipped the switch. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Instead of pushing water out, they used the channels to pull water back in. </seg>
<seg id="82"> They flooded the canals. </seg>
<seg id="83"> They created a 27,000-acre fish farm -- bass, mullet, shrimp, eel -- and in the process, Miguel and this company completely reversed the ecological destruction. </seg>
<seg id="84"> The farm's incredible. </seg>
<seg id="85"> I mean, you've never seen anything like this. </seg>
<seg id="86"> You stare out at a horizon that is a million miles away, and all you see are flooded canals and this thick, rich marshland. </seg>
<seg id="87"> I was there not long ago with Miguel. </seg>
<seg id="88"> He's an amazing guy, like three parts Charles Darwin and one part Crocodile Dundee. </seg>
<seg id="89"> Okay? There we are slogging through the wetlands, and I'm panting and sweating, got mud up to my knees, and Miguel's calmly conducting a biology lecture. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Here, he's pointing out a rare Black-shouldered Kite. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Now, he's mentioning the mineral needs of phytoplankton. </seg>
<seg id="92"> And here, here he sees a grouping pattern that reminds him of the Tanzanian Giraffe. </seg>
<seg id="93"> It turns out, Miguel spent the better part of his career in the Mikumi National Park in Africa. </seg>
<seg id="94"> I asked him how he became such an expert on fish. </seg>
<seg id="95"> He said, "Fish? I didn't know anything about fish. </seg>
<seg id="96"> I'm an expert in relationships." </seg>
<seg id="97"> And then he's off, launching into more talk about rare birds and algaes and strange aquatic plants. </seg>
<seg id="98"> And don't get me wrong, that was really fascinating, you know, the biotic community unplugged, kind of thing. </seg>
<seg id="99"> It's great, but I was in love. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And my head was swooning over that overcooked piece of delicious fish I had the night before. </seg>
<seg id="101"> So I interrupted him. I said, "Miguel, what makes your fish taste so good?" </seg>
<seg id="102"> He pointed at the algae. </seg>
<seg id="103"> "I know, dude, the algae, the phytoplankton, the relationships: It's amazing. </seg>
<seg id="104"> But what are your fish eating? </seg>
<seg id="105"> What's the feed conversion ratio?" </seg>
<seg id="106"> Well, he goes on to tell me it's such a rich system that the fish are eating what they'd be eating in the wild. </seg>
<seg id="107"> The plant biomass, the phytoplankton, the zooplankton, it's what feeds the fish. </seg>
<seg id="108"> The system is so healthy, it's totally self-renewing. </seg>
<seg id="109"> There is no feed. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Ever heard of a farm that doesn't feed its animals? </seg>
<seg id="111"> Later that day, I was driving around this property with Miguel, and I asked him, I said, "For a place that seems so natural, unlike like any farm I'd ever been at, how do you measure success?" </seg>
<seg id="112"> At that moment, it was as if a film director called for a set change. </seg>
<seg id="113"> And we rounded the corner and saw the most amazing sight: thousands and thousands of pink flamingos, a literal pink carpet for as far as you could see. </seg>
<seg id="114"> "That's success," he said. </seg>
<seg id="115"> "Look at their bellies, pink. </seg>
<seg id="116"> They're feasting." </seg>
<seg id="117"> Feasting? I was totally confused. </seg>
<seg id="118"> I said, "Miguel, aren't they feasting on your fish?" </seg>
<seg id="119"> "Yes," he said. </seg>
<seg id="120"> "We lose 20 percent of our fish and fish eggs to birds. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Well, last year, this property had 600,000 birds on it, more than 250 different species. </seg>
<seg id="122"> It's become, today, the largest and one of the most important private bird sanctuaries in all of Europe." </seg>
<seg id="123"> I said, "Miguel, isn't a thriving bird population like the last thing you want on a fish farm?" </seg>
<seg id="124"> He shook his head, no. </seg>
<seg id="125"> He said, "We farm extensively, not intensively. </seg>
<seg id="126"> This is an ecological network. </seg>
<seg id="127"> The flamingos eat the shrimp. </seg>
<seg id="128"> The shrimp eat the phytoplankton. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So the pinker the belly, the better the system." </seg>
<seg id="130"> Okay, so let's review: a farm that doesn't feed its animals, and a farm that measures its success on the health of its predators. </seg>
<seg id="131"> A fish farm, but also a bird sanctuary. </seg>
<seg id="132"> Oh, and by the way, those flamingos, they shouldn't even be there in the first place. </seg>
<seg id="133"> They brood in a town 150 miles away, where the soil conditions are better for building nests. </seg>
<seg id="134"> Every morning, they fly 150 miles into the farm. </seg>
<seg id="135"> And every evening, they fly 150 miles back. </seg>
<seg id="136"> They do that because they're able to follow the broken white line of highway A92. </seg>
<seg id="137"> No kidding. </seg>
<seg id="138"> I was imagining a "March of the Penguins" thing, so I looked at Miguel. </seg>
<seg id="139"> I said, "Miguel, do they fly 150 miles to the farm, and then do they fly 150 miles back at night? </seg>
<seg id="140"> Do they do that for the children?" </seg>
<seg id="141"> He looked at me like I had just quoted a Whitney Houston song. </seg>
<seg id="142"> He said, "No; they do it because the food's better." </seg>
<seg id="143"> I didn't mention the skin of my beloved fish, which was delicious -- and I don't like fish skin; I don't like it seared, I don't like it crispy. </seg>
<seg id="144"> It's that acrid, tar-like flavor. </seg>
<seg id="145"> I almost never cook with it. </seg>
<seg id="146"> Yet, when I tasted it at that restaurant in southern Spain, it tasted not at all like fish skin. </seg>
<seg id="147"> It tasted sweet and clean, like you were taking a bite of the ocean. </seg>
<seg id="148"> I mentioned that to Miguel, and he nodded. </seg>
<seg id="149"> He said, "The skin acts like a sponge. </seg>
<seg id="150"> It's the last defense before anything enters the body. </seg>
<seg id="151"> It evolved to soak up impurities." </seg>
<seg id="152"> And then he added, "But our water has no impurities." </seg>
<seg id="153"> OK. A farm that doesn't feed its fish, a farm that measures its success by the success of its predators. </seg>
<seg id="154"> And then I realized when he says, "A farm that has no impurities," he made a big understatement, because the water that flows through that farm comes in from the Guadalquivir River. </seg>
<seg id="155"> It's a river that carries with it all the things that rivers tend to carry these days: chemical contaminants, pesticide runoff. </seg>
<seg id="156"> And when it works its way through the system and leaves, the water is cleaner than when it entered. </seg>
<seg id="157"> The system is so healthy, it purifies the water. </seg>
<seg id="158"> So, not just a farm that doesn't feed its animals, not just a farm that measures its success by the health of its predators, but a farm that's literally a water purification plant -- and not just for those fish, but for you and me as well. </seg>
<seg id="159"> Because when that water leaves, it dumps out into the Atlantic. </seg>
<seg id="160"> A drop in the ocean, I know, but I'll take it, and so should you, because this love story, however romantic, is also instructive. </seg>
<seg id="161"> You might say it's a recipe for the future of good food, whether we're talking about bass or beef cattle. </seg>
<seg id="162"> What we need now is a radically new conception of agriculture, one in which the food actually tastes good. </seg>
<seg id="163"> But for a lot people, that's a bit too radical. </seg>
<seg id="164"> We're not realists, us foodies; we're lovers. </seg>
<seg id="165"> We love farmers' markets, we love small family farms, we talk about local food, we eat organic. </seg>
<seg id="166"> And when you suggest these are the things that will ensure the future of good food, someone, somewhere stands up and says, "Hey guy, I love pink flamingos, but how are you going to feed the world?" </seg>
<seg id="167"> How are you going to feed the world? </seg>
<seg id="168"> Can I be honest? </seg>
<seg id="169"> I don't love that question. </seg>
<seg id="170"> No, not because we already produce enough calories to more than feed the world. </seg>
<seg id="171"> One billion people will go hungry today. </seg>
<seg id="172"> One billion -- that's more than ever before -- because of gross inequalities in distribution, not tonnage. </seg>
<seg id="173"> Now, I don't love this question because it's determined the logic of our food system for the last 50 years. </seg>
<seg id="174"> Feed grain to herbivores, pesticides to monocultures, chemicals to soil, chicken to fish, and all along agribusiness has simply asked, "If we're feeding more people more cheaply, how terrible could that be?" </seg>
<seg id="175"> That's been the motivation, it's been the justification: it's been the business plan of American agriculture. </seg>
<seg id="176"> We should call it what it is: a business in liquidation, a business that's quickly eroding ecological capital that makes that very production possible. </seg>
<seg id="177"> That's not a business, and it isn't agriculture. </seg>
<seg id="178"> Our breadbasket is threatened today, not because of diminishing supply, but because of diminishing resources. </seg>
<seg id="179"> Not by the latest combine and tractor invention, but by fertile land; not by pumps, but by fresh water; not by chainsaws, but by forests; and not by fishing boats and nets, but by fish in the sea. </seg>
<seg id="180"> Want to feed the world? </seg>
<seg id="181"> Let's start by asking: How are we going to feed ourselves? </seg>
<seg id="182"> Or better: How can we create conditions that enable every community to feed itself? </seg>
<seg id="183"> To do that, don't look at the agribusiness model for the future. </seg>
<seg id="184"> It's really old, and it's tired. </seg>
<seg id="185"> It's high on capital, chemistry and machines, and it's never produced anything really good to eat. </seg>
<seg id="186"> Instead, let's look to the ecological model. </seg>
<seg id="187"> That's the one that relies on two billion years of on-the-job experience. </seg>
<seg id="188"> Look to Miguel, farmers like Miguel. </seg>
<seg id="189"> Farms that aren't worlds unto themselves; farms that restore instead of deplete; farms that farm extensively instead of just intensively; farmers that are not just producers, but experts in relationships. </seg>
<seg id="190"> Because they're the ones that are experts in flavor, too. </seg>
<seg id="191"> And if I'm going to be really honest, they're a better chef than I'll ever be. </seg>
<seg id="192"> You know, I'm okay with that, because if that's the future of good food, it's going to be delicious. </seg>
<seg id="193"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="783" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/gary_flake_is_pivot_a_turning_point_for_web_exploration.html</url>
<description>Gary Flake demos Pivot, a new way to browse and arrange massive amounts of images and data online. Built on breakthrough Seadragon technology, it enables spectacular zooms in and out of web databases, and the discovery of patterns and links invisible in standard web browsing.</description>
<keywords>data,demo,interface design,technology,web</keywords>
<talkid>783</talkid>
<title>Gary Flake: is Pivot a turning point for web exploration?</title>
<seg id="1"> If I can leave you with one big idea today, it's that the whole of the data in which we consume is greater that the sum of the parts, and instead of thinking about information overload, what I'd like you to think about is how we can use information so that patterns pop and we can see trends that would otherwise be invisible. </seg>
<seg id="2"> So what we're looking at right here is a typical mortality chart organized by age. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This tool that I'm using here is a little experiment. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It's called Pivot, and with Pivot what I can do is I can choose to filter in one particular cause of deaths -- say, accidents. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And, right away, I see there's a different pattern that emerges. </seg>
<seg id="6"> This is because, in the mid-area here, people are at their most active, and over here they're at their most frail. </seg>
<seg id="7"> We can step back out again and then reorganize the data by cause of death, seeing that circulatory diseases and cancer are the usual suspects, but not for everyone. </seg>
<seg id="8"> If we go ahead and we filter by age -- say 40 years or less -- we see that accidents are actually the greatest cause that people have to be worried about. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And if you drill into that, it's especially the case for men. </seg>
<seg id="10"> So you get the idea that viewing information, viewing data in this way, is a lot like swimming in a living information info-graphic. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And if we can do this for raw data, why not do it for content as well? </seg>
<seg id="12"> So what we have right here is the cover of every single Sports Illustrated ever produced. </seg>
<seg id="13"> It's all here; it's all on the web. </seg>
<seg id="14"> You can go back to your rooms and try this after my talk. </seg>
<seg id="15"> With Pivot, you can drill into a decade. </seg>
<seg id="16"> You can drill into a particular year. </seg>
<seg id="17"> You can jump right into a specific issue. </seg>
<seg id="18"> So I'm looking at this; I see the athletes that have appeared in this issue, the sports. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I'm a Lance Armstrong fan, so I'll go ahead and I'll click on that, which reveals, for me, all the issues in which Lance Armstrong's been a part of. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Now, if I want to just kind of take a peek at these, I might think, "Well, what about taking a look at all of cycling?" </seg>
<seg id="21"> So I can step back, and expand on that. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And I see Greg LeMond now. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And so you get the idea that when you navigate over information this way -- going narrower, broader, backing in, backing out -- you're not searching, you're not browsing. </seg>
<seg id="24"> You're doing something that's actually a little bit different. </seg>
<seg id="25"> It's in between, and we think it changes the way information can be used. </seg>
<seg id="26"> So I want to extrapolate on this idea a bit with something that's a little bit crazy. </seg>
<seg id="27"> What we're done here is we've taken every single Wikipedia page and we reduced it down to a little summary. </seg>
<seg id="28"> So the summary consists of just a little synopsis and an icon to indicate the topical area that it comes from. </seg>
<seg id="29"> I'm only showing the top 500 most popular Wikipedia pages right here. </seg>
<seg id="30"> But even in this limited view, we can do a lot of things. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Right away, we get a sense of what are the topical domains that are most popular on Wikipedia. </seg>
<seg id="32"> I'm going to go ahead and select government. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Now, having selected government, I can now see that the Wikipedia categories that most frequently correspond to that are Time magazine People of the Year. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So this is really important because this is an insight that was not contained within any one Wikipedia page. </seg>
<seg id="35"> It's only possible to see that insight when you step back and look at all of them. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Looking at one of these particular summaries, I can then drill into the concept of Time magazine Person of the Year, bringing up all of them. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So looking at these people, I can see that the majority come from government; some have come from natural sciences; some, fewer still, have come from business -- there's my boss -- and one has come from music. </seg>
<seg id="38"> And interestingly enough, Bono is also a TED Prize winner. </seg>
<seg id="39"> So we can go, jump, and take a look at all the TED Prize winners. </seg>
<seg id="40"> So you see, we're navigating the web for the first time as if it's actually a web, not from page-to-page, but at a higher level of abstraction. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And so I want to show you one other thing that may catch you a little bit by surprise. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I'm just showing the New York Times website here. </seg>
<seg id="43"> So Pivot, this application -- I don't want to call it a browser; it's really not a browser, but you can view web pages with it -- and we bring that zoomable technology to every single web page like this. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So I can step back, pop right back into a specific section. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Now the reason why this is important is because, by virtue of just viewing web pages in this way, I can look at my entire browsing history in the exact same way. </seg>
<seg id="46"> So I can drill into what I've done over specific time frames. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Here, in fact, is the state of all the demo that I just gave. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And I can sort of replay some stuff that I was looking at earlier today. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And, if I want to step back and look at everything, I can slice and dice my history, perhaps by my search history -- here, I was doing some nepotistic searching, looking for Bing, over here for Live Labs Pivot. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And from these, I can drill into the web page and just launch them again. </seg>
<seg id="51"> It's one metaphor repurposed multiple times, and in each case it makes the whole greater than the sum of the parts with the data. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So right now, in this world, we think about data as being this curse. </seg>
<seg id="53"> We talk about the curse of information overload. </seg>
<seg id="54"> We talk about drowning in data. </seg>
<seg id="55"> What if we can actually turn that upside down and turn the web upside down, so that instead of navigating from one thing to the next, we get used to the habit of being able to go from many things to many things, and then being able to see the patterns that were otherwise hidden? </seg>
<seg id="56"> If we can do that, then instead of being trapped in data, we might actually extract information. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And, instead of dealing just with information, we can tease out knowledge. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And if we get the knowledge, then maybe even there's wisdom to be found. </seg>
<seg id="59"> So with that, I thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="785" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/james_cameron_before_avatar_a_curious_boy.html</url>
<description>James Cameron's big-budget films create unreal worlds all their own. In this personal talk, he reveals his childhood fascination with the fantastic -- from reading science fiction to deep-sea diving -- and how it ultimately drove the success of his blockbuster hits "Aliens," "The Terminator," "Titanic" and "Avatar."</description>
<keywords>adventure,entertainment,film,nature,oceans,storytelling,technology,writing</keywords>
<talkid>785</talkid>
<title>James Cameron: Before Avatar ... a curious boy</title>
<seg id="1"> I grew up on a steady diet of science fiction. </seg>
<seg id="2"> In high school, I took a bus to school an hour each way every day. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And I was always absorbed in a book, science fiction book, which took my mind to other worlds, and satisfied, in a narrative form, this insatiable sense of curiosity that I had. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And you know, that curiosity also manifested itself in the fact that whenever I wasn't in school I was out in the woods, hiking and taking "samples" -- frogs and snakes and bugs and pond water -- and bringing it back, looking at it under the microscope. </seg>
<seg id="5"> You know, I was a real science geek. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But it was all about trying to understand the world, understand the limits of possibility. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And my love of science fiction actually seemed mirrored in the world around me, because what was happening, this was in the late '60s, we were going to the moon, we were exploring the deep oceans. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Jacques Cousteau was coming into our living rooms with his amazing specials that showed us animals and places and a wondrous world that we could never really have previously imagined. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So, that seemed to resonate with the whole science fiction part of it. </seg>
<seg id="10"> And I was an artist. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I could draw. I could paint. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And I found that because there weren't video games and this saturation of CG movies and all of this imagery in the media landscape, I had to create these images in my head. </seg>
<seg id="13"> You know, we all did, as kids having to read a book, and through the author's description, put something on the movie screen in our heads. </seg>
<seg id="14"> And so, my response to this was to paint, to draw alien creatures, alien worlds, robots, spaceships, all that stuff. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I was endlessly getting busted in math class doodling behind the textbook. </seg>
<seg id="16"> That was -- the creativity had to find its outlet somehow. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And an interesting thing happened: The Jacques Cousteau shows actually got me very excited about the fact that there was an alien world right here on Earth. </seg>
<seg id="18"> I might not really go to an alien world on a spaceship someday -- that seemed pretty darn unlikely. </seg>
<seg id="19"> But that was a world I could really go to, right here on Earth, that was as rich and exotic as anything that I had imagined from reading these books. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So, I decided I was going to become a scuba diver at the age of 15. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And the only problem with that was that I lived in a little village in Canada, 600 miles from the nearest ocean. </seg>
<seg id="22"> But I didn't let that daunt me. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I pestered my father until he finally found a scuba class in Buffalo, New York, right across the border from where we live. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And I actually got certified in a pool at a YMCA in the dead of winter in Buffalo, New York. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And I didn't see the ocean, a real ocean, for another two years, until we moved to California. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Since then, in the intervening 40 years, I've spent about 3,000 hours underwater, and 500 hours of that was in submersibles. </seg>
<seg id="27"> And I've learned that that deep-ocean environment, and even the shallow oceans, are so rich with amazing life that really is beyond our imagination. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Nature's imagination is so boundless compared to our own meager human imagination. </seg>
<seg id="29"> I still, to this day, stand in absolute awe of what I see when I make these dives. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And my love affair with the ocean is ongoing, and just as strong as it ever was. </seg>
<seg id="31"> But when I chose a career as an adult, it was filmmaking. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And that seemed to be the best way to reconcile this urge I had to tell stories with my urges to create images. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And I was, as a kid, constantly drawing comic books, and so on. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So, filmmaking was the way to put pictures and stories together, and that made sense. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And of course the stories that I chose to tell were science fiction stories: "Terminator," "Aliens" and "The Abyss." </seg>
<seg id="36"> And with "The Abyss," I was putting together my love of underwater and diving with filmmaking. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So, you know, merging the two passions. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Something interesting came out of "The Abyss," which was that to solve a specific narrative problem on that film, which was to create this kind of liquid water creature, we actually embraced computer generated animation, CG. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And this resulted in the first soft-surface character, CG animation that was ever in a movie. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And even though the film didn't make any money -- barely broke even, I should say -- I witnessed something amazing, which is that the audience, the global audience, was mesmerized by this apparent magic. </seg>
<seg id="41"> You know, it's Arthur Clarke's law that any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic. </seg>
<seg id="42"> They were seeing something magical. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And so that got me very excited. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And I thought, "Wow, this is something that needs to be embraced into the cinematic art." </seg>
<seg id="45"> So, with "Terminator 2," which was my next film, we took that much farther. </seg>
<seg id="46"> Working with ILM, we created the liquid metal dude in that film. The success hung in the balance on whether that effect would work. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And it did, and we created magic again, and we had the same result with an audience -- although we did make a little more money on that one. </seg>
<seg id="48"> So, drawing a line through those two dots of experience came to, "This is going to be a whole new world," this was a whole new world of creativity for film artists. </seg>
<seg id="49"> So, I started a company with Stan Winston, my good friend Stan Winston, who is the premier make-up and creature designer at that time, and it was called Digital Domain. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And the concept of the company was that we would leapfrog past the analog processes of optical printers and so on, and we would go right to digital production. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And we actually did that and it gave us a competitive advantage for a while. </seg>
<seg id="52"> But we found ourselves lagging in the mid '90s in the creature and character design stuff that we had actually founded the company to do. </seg>
<seg id="53"> So, I wrote this piece called "Avatar," which was meant to absolutely push the envelope of visual effects, of CG effects, beyond, with realistic human emotive characters generated in CG, and the main characters would all be in CG, and the world would be in CG. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And the envelope pushed back, and I was told by the folks at my company that we weren't going to be able to do this for a while. </seg>
<seg id="55"> So, I shelved it, and I made this other movie about a big ship that sinks. </seg>
<seg id="56"> You know, I went and pitched it to the studio as "'Romeo and Juliet' on a ship: "It's going to be this epic romance, passionate film." </seg>
<seg id="57"> Secretly, what I wanted to do was I wanted to dive to the real wreck of "Titanic." </seg>
<seg id="58"> And that's why I made the movie. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And that's the truth. Now, the studio didn't know that. </seg>
<seg id="60"> But I convinced them. I said, "We're going to dive to the wreck. We're going to film it for real. </seg>
<seg id="61"> We'll be using it in the opening of the film. </seg>
<seg id="62"> It will be really important. It will be a great marketing hook." </seg>
<seg id="63"> And I talked them into funding an expedition. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Sounds crazy. But this goes back to that theme about your imagination creating a reality. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Because we actually created a reality where six months later, I find myself in a Russian submersible two and a half miles down in the north Atlantic, looking at the real Titanic through a view port. </seg>
<seg id="66"> Not a movie, not HD -- for real. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Now, that blew my mind. </seg>
<seg id="68"> And it took a lot of preparation, we had to build cameras and lights and all kinds of things. </seg>
<seg id="69"> But, it struck me how much this dive, these deep dives, was like a space mission. </seg>
<seg id="70"> You know, where it was highly technical, and it required enormous planning. </seg>
<seg id="71"> You get in this capsule, you go down to this dark hostile environment where there is no hope of rescue if you can't get back by yourself. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And I thought like, "Wow. I'm like, living in a science fiction movie. </seg>
<seg id="73"> This is really cool." </seg>
<seg id="74"> And so, I really got bitten by the bug of deep-ocean exploration. </seg>
<seg id="75"> Of course, the curiosity, the science component of it -- it was everything. It was adventure, it was curiosity, it was imagination. </seg>
<seg id="76"> And it was an experience that Hollywood couldn't give me. </seg>
<seg id="77"> Because, you know, I could imagine a creature and we could create a visual effect for it. But I couldn't imagine what I was seeing out that window. </seg>
<seg id="78"> As we did some of our subsequent expeditions, I was seeing creatures at hydrothermal vents and sometimes things that I had never seen before, sometimes things that no one had seen before, that actually were not described by science at the time that we saw them and imaged them. </seg>
<seg id="79"> So, I was completely smitten by this, and had to do more. </seg>
<seg id="80"> And so, I actually made a kind of curious decision. </seg>
<seg id="81"> After the success of "Titanic," I said, "OK, I'm going to park my day job as a Hollywood movie maker, and I'm going to go be a full-time explorer for a while." </seg>
<seg id="82"> And so, we started planning these And we wound up going to the Bismark, and exploring it with robotic vehicles. </seg>
<seg id="83"> We went back to the Titanic wreck. </seg>
<seg id="84"> We took little bots that we had created that spooled a fiber optic. </seg>
<seg id="85"> And the idea was to go in and do an interior survey of that ship, which had never been done. </seg>
<seg id="86"> Nobody had ever looked inside the wreck. They didn't have the means to do it, so we created technology to do it. </seg>
<seg id="87"> So, you know, here I am now, on the deck of Titanic, sitting in a submersible, and looking out at planks that look much like this, where I knew that the band had played. </seg>
<seg id="88"> And I'm flying a little robotic vehicle through the corridor of the ship. </seg>
<seg id="89"> When I say, "I'm operating it," but my mind is in the vehicle. </seg>
<seg id="90"> I felt like I was physically present inside the shipwreck of Titanic. </seg>
<seg id="91"> And it was the most surreal kind of deja vu experience I've ever had, because I would know before I turned a corner what was going to be there before the lights of the vehicle actually revealed it, because I had walked the set for months when we were making the movie. </seg>
<seg id="92"> And the set was based as an exact replica on the blueprints of the ship. </seg>
<seg id="93"> So, it was this absolutely remarkable experience. </seg>
<seg id="94"> And it really made me realize that the telepresence experience -- that you actually can have these robotic avatars, then your consciousness is injected into the vehicle, into this other form of existence. </seg>
<seg id="95"> It was really, really quite profound. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And it may be a little bit of a glimpse as to what might be happening some decades out as we start to have cyborg bodies for exploration or for other means in many sort of post-human futures that I can imagine, as a science fiction fan. </seg>
<seg id="97"> So, having done these expeditions, and really beginning to appreciate what was down there, such as at the deep ocean vents where we had these amazing, amazing animals -- they're basically aliens right here on Earth. </seg>
<seg id="98"> They live in an environment of chemosynthesis. </seg>
<seg id="99"> They don't survive on sunlight-based system the way we do. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And so, you're seeing animals that are living next to a 500-degree-Centigrade You think they can't possibly exist. </seg>
<seg id="101"> At the same time I was getting very interested in space science as well -- again, it's the science fiction influence, as a kid. </seg>
<seg id="102"> And I wound up getting involved with the space community, really involved with NASA, sitting on the NASA advisory board, planning actual space missions, going to Russia, going through the pre-cosmonaut biomedical protocols, and all these sorts of things, to actually go and fly to the international space station with our 3D camera systems. </seg>
<seg id="103"> And this was fascinating. </seg>
<seg id="104"> But what I wound up doing was bringing space scientists with us into the deep. </seg>
<seg id="105"> And taking them down so that they had access -- astrobiologists, planetary scientists, people who were interested in these extreme environments -- taking them down to the vents, and letting them see, and take samples and test instruments, and so on. </seg>
<seg id="106"> So, here we were making documentary films, but actually doing science, and actually doing space science. </seg>
<seg id="107"> I'd completely closed the loop between being the science fiction fan, you know, as a kid, and doing this stuff for real. </seg>
<seg id="108"> And you know, along the way in this journey of discovery, I learned a lot. </seg>
<seg id="109"> I learned a lot about science. But I also learned a lot Now you think director has got to be a leader, leader of, captain of the ship, and all that sort of thing. </seg>
<seg id="110"> I didn't really learn about leadership until I did these expeditions. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Because I had to, at a certain point, say, "What am I doing out here? </seg>
<seg id="112"> Why am I doing this? What do I get out of it?" </seg>
<seg id="113"> We don't make money at these damn shows. </seg>
<seg id="114"> We barely break even. There is no fame in it. </seg>
<seg id="115"> People sort of think I went away between "Titanic" and "Avatar" and was buffing my nails someplace, sitting at the beach. </seg>
<seg id="116"> Made all these films, made all these documentary films for a very limited audience. </seg>
<seg id="117"> No fame, no glory, no money. What are you doing? </seg>
<seg id="118"> You're doing it for the task itself, for the challenge -- and the ocean is the most challenging environment there is -- for the thrill of discovery, and for that strange bond that happens when a small group of people form a tightly knit team. </seg>
<seg id="119"> Because we would do these things with 10, 12 people, working for years at a time, sometimes at sea for two, three months at a time. </seg>
<seg id="120"> And in that bond, you realize that the most important thing is the respect that you have for them and that they have for you, that you've done a task that you can't explain to someone else. </seg>
<seg id="121"> When you come back to the shore and you say, "We had to do this, and the fiber optic, and the attentuation, and the this and the that, all the technology of it, and the difficulty, the human-performance aspects of working at sea," you can't explain it to people. It's that thing that maybe cops have, or people in combat that have gone through something together and they know they can never explain it. </seg>
<seg id="122"> Creates a bond, creates a bond of respect. </seg>
<seg id="123"> So, when I came back to make my next movie, which was "Avatar," I tried to apply that same principle of leadership, which is that you respect your team, and you earn their respect in return. </seg>
<seg id="124"> And it really changed the dynamic. </seg>
<seg id="125"> So, here I was again with a small team, in uncharted territory, doing "Avatar," coming up with new technology that didn't exist before. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Tremendously exciting. </seg>
<seg id="127"> Tremendously challenging. </seg>
<seg id="128"> And we became a family, over a four-and-half year period. </seg>
<seg id="129"> And it completely changed how I do movies. </seg>
<seg id="130"> So, people have commented on how, "Well, you know, you brought back the ocean organisms and put them on the planet of Pandora." </seg>
<seg id="131"> To me, it was more of a fundamental way of doing business, the process itself, that changed as a result of that. </seg>
<seg id="132"> So, what can we synthesize out of all this? </seg>
<seg id="133"> You know, what are the lessons learned? </seg>
<seg id="134"> Well, I think number one is curiosity. </seg>
<seg id="135"> It's the most powerful thing you own. </seg>
<seg id="136"> Imagination is a force that can actually manifest a reality. </seg>
<seg id="137"> And the respect of your team is more important than all the laurels in the world. </seg>
<seg id="138"> I have young filmmakers come up to me and say, "Give me some advice for doing this." </seg>
<seg id="139"> And I say, "Don't put limitations on yourself. </seg>
<seg id="140"> Other people will do that for you -- don't do it to yourself, don't bet against yourself, and take risks." </seg>
<seg id="141"> NASA has this phrase that they like: "Failure is not an option." </seg>
<seg id="142"> But failure has to be an option in art and in exploration, because it's a leap of faith. </seg>
<seg id="143"> And no important endeavor that required innovation was done without risk. </seg>
<seg id="144"> You have to be willing to take those risks. </seg>
<seg id="145"> So, that's the thought I would leave you with, is that in whatever you're doing, failure is an option, but fear is not. Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="767" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/bill_gates.html</url>
<description>At TED2010, Bill Gates unveils his vision for the world's energy future, describing the need for "miracles" to avoid planetary catastrophe and explaining why he's backing a dramatically different type of nuclear reactor. The necessary goal? Zero carbon emissions globally by 2050.</description>
<keywords>business,energy,global issues,invention,science,technology</keywords>
<talkid>767</talkid>
<title>Bill Gates on energy: Innovating to zero!</title>
<seg id="1"> I'm going to talk today about energy and climate. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And that might seem a bit surprising because my full-time work at the Foundation is mostly about vaccines and seeds, about the things that we need to invent and deliver to help the poorest two billion live better lives. </seg>
<seg id="3"> But energy and climate are extremely important to these people -- in fact, more important than to anyone else on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The climate getting worse means that many years, their crops won't grow: There will be too much rain, not enough rain, things will change in ways that their fragile environment simply can't support. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And that leads to starvation, it leads to uncertainty, it leads to unrest. </seg>
<seg id="6"> So, the climate changes will be terrible for them. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Also, the price of energy is very important to them. </seg>
<seg id="8"> In fact, if you could pick just one thing to lower the price of, to reduce poverty, by far you would pick energy. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Now, the price of energy has come down over time. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Really advanced civilization is based on advances in energy. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The coal revolution fueled the Industrial Revolution, and, even in the 1900s we've seen a very rapid decline in the price of electricity, and that's why we have refrigerators, air-conditioning, we can make modern materials and do so many things. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And so, we're in a wonderful situation with electricity in the rich world. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But, as we make it cheaper -- and let's go for making it twice as cheap -- we need to meet a new constraint, and that constraint has to do with CO2. </seg>
<seg id="14"> CO2 is warming the planet, and the equation on CO2 is actually a very straightforward one. </seg>
<seg id="15"> If you sum up the CO2 that gets emitted, that leads to a temperature increase, and that temperature increase leads to some very negative effects: the effects on the weather; perhaps worse, the indirect effects, in that the natural ecosystems can't adjust to these rapid changes, and so you get ecosystem collapses. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Now, the exact amount of how you map from a certain increase of CO2 to what temperature will be and where the positive feedbacks are, there's some uncertainty there, but not very much. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And there's certainly uncertainty about how bad those effects will be, but they will be extremely bad. </seg>
<seg id="18"> I asked the top scientists on this several times: Do we really have to get down to near zero? </seg>
<seg id="19"> Can't we just cut it in half or a quarter? </seg>
<seg id="20"> And the answer is that until we get near to zero, the temperature will continue to rise. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And so that's a big challenge. </seg>
<seg id="22"> It's very different than saying "We're a twelve-foot-high truck trying to get under a ten-foot bridge, and we can just sort of squeeze under." </seg>
<seg id="23"> This is something that has to get to zero. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Now, we put out a lot of carbon dioxide every year, over 26 billion tons. </seg>
<seg id="25"> For each American, it's about 20 tons; for people in poor countries, it's less than one ton. </seg>
<seg id="26"> It's an average of about five tons for everyone on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="27"> And, somehow, we have to make changes that will bring that down to zero. </seg>
<seg id="28"> It's been constantly going up. </seg>
<seg id="29"> It's only various economic changes that have even flattened it at all, so we have to go from rapidly rising to falling, and falling all the way to zero. </seg>
<seg id="30"> This equation has four factors, a little bit of multiplication: So, you've got a thing on the left, CO2, that you want to get to zero, and that's going to be based on the number of people, the services each person's using on average, the energy on average for each service, and the CO2 being put out per unit of energy. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So, let's look at each one of these and see how we can get this down to zero. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Probably, one of these numbers is going to have to get pretty near to zero. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Now that's back from high school algebra, but let's take a look. </seg>
<seg id="34"> First, we've got population. </seg>
<seg id="35"> The world today has 6.8 billion people. </seg>
<seg id="36"> That's headed up to about nine billion. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Now, if we do a really great job on new vaccines, health care, reproductive health services, we could lower that by, perhaps, 10 or 15 percent, but there we see an increase of about 1.3. </seg>
<seg id="38"> The second factor is the services we use. </seg>
<seg id="39"> This encompasses everything: the food we eat, clothing, TV, heating. </seg>
<seg id="40"> These are very good things: getting rid of poverty means providing these services to almost everyone on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And it's a great thing for this number to go up. </seg>
<seg id="42"> In the rich world, perhaps the top one billion, we probably could cut back and use less, but every year, this number, on average, is going to go up, and so, over all, that will more than double the services delivered per person. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Here we have a very basic service: Do you have lighting in your house to be able to read your homework? </seg>
<seg id="44"> And, in fact, these kids don't, so they're going out and reading their school work under the street lamps. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Now, efficiency, E, the energy for each service, here finally we have some good news. </seg>
<seg id="46"> We have something that's not going up. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Through various inventions and new ways of doing lighting, through different types of cars, different ways of building buildings -- there are a lot of services where you can bring Some individual services even bring it down by 90 percent. </seg>
<seg id="48"> There are other services like how we make fertilizer, or how we do air transport, where the rooms for improvement are far, far less. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And so, overall here, if we're optimistic, we may get a reduction of a factor of three to even, perhaps, a factor of six. </seg>
<seg id="50"> But for these first three factors now, we've gone from 26 billion to, at best, maybe 13 billion tons, and that just won't cut it. </seg>
<seg id="51"> So let's look at this fourth factor -- this is going to be a key one -- and this is the amount of CO2 put out per each unit of energy. </seg>
<seg id="52"> And so the question is: Can you actually get that to zero? </seg>
<seg id="53"> If you burn coal, no. </seg>
<seg id="54"> If you burn natural gas, no. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Almost every way we make electricity today, except for the emerging renewables and nuclear, puts out CO2. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And so, what we're going to have to do at a global scale, is create a new system. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And so, we need energy miracles. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Now, when I use the term "miracle," I don't mean something that's impossible. </seg>
<seg id="59"> The microprocessor is a miracle. The personal computer is a miracle. </seg>
<seg id="60"> The Internet and its services are a miracle. </seg>
<seg id="61"> So, the people here have participated in the creation of many miracles. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Usually, we don't have a deadline, where you have to get the miracle by a certain date. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Usually, you just kind of stand by, and some come along, some don't. </seg>
<seg id="64"> This is a case where we actually have to drive at full speed and get a miracle in a pretty tight timeline. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Now, I thought, "How could I really capture this? </seg>
<seg id="66"> Is there some kind of natural illustration, some demonstration that would grab people's imagination here?" </seg>
<seg id="67"> I thought back to a year ago when I brought mosquitos, and somehow people enjoyed that. </seg>
<seg id="68"> It really got them involved in the idea of, you know, there are people who live with mosquitos. </seg>
<seg id="69"> So, with energy, all I could come up with is this. </seg>
<seg id="70"> I decided that releasing fireflies would be my contribution to the environment here this year. </seg>
<seg id="71"> So here we have some natural fireflies. </seg>
<seg id="72"> I'm told they don't bite; in fact, they might not even leave that jar. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Now, there's all sorts of gimmicky solutions like that one, but they don't really add up to much. </seg>
<seg id="74"> We need solutions -- either one or several -- that have unbelievable scale and unbelievable reliability, and, although there's many directions people are seeking, I really only see five that can achieve the big numbers. </seg>
<seg id="75"> I've left out tide, geothermal, fusion, biofuels. </seg>
<seg id="76"> Those may make some contribution, and if they can do better than I expect, so much the better, but my key point here is that we're going to have to work on each of these five, and we can't give up any of them because they look daunting, because they all have significant challenges. </seg>
<seg id="77"> Let's look first at the burning fossil fuels, either burning coal or burning natural gas. </seg>
<seg id="78"> What you need to do there, seems like it might be simple, but it's not, and that's to take all the CO2, after you've burned it, going out the flue, pressurize it, create a liquid, put it somewhere, and hope it stays there. </seg>
<seg id="79"> Now we have some pilot things that do this at the 60 to 80 percent level, but getting up to that full percentage, that will be very tricky, and agreeing on where these CO2 quantities should be put will be hard, but the toughest one here is this long-term issue. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Who's going to be sure? </seg>
<seg id="81"> Who's going to guarantee something that is literally billions of times larger than any type of waste you think of in terms of nuclear or other things? </seg>
<seg id="82"> This is a lot of volume. </seg>
<seg id="83"> So that's a tough one. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Next would be nuclear. </seg>
<seg id="85"> It also has three big problems: Cost, particularly in highly regulated countries, is high; the issue of the safety, really feeling good about nothing could go wrong, that, even though you have these human operators, that the fuel doesn't get used for weapons. </seg>
<seg id="86"> And then what do you do with the waste? </seg>
<seg id="87"> And, although it's not very large, there are a lot of concerns about that. </seg>
<seg id="88"> So three very tough problems that might be solvable, and so, should be worked on. </seg>
<seg id="89"> The last three of the five, I've grouped together. </seg>
<seg id="90"> These are what people often refer to as the renewable sources. </seg>
<seg id="91"> And they actually -- although it's great they don't require fuel -- they have some disadvantages. </seg>
<seg id="92"> One is that the density of energy gathered in these technologies is dramatically less than a power plant. </seg>
<seg id="93"> This is energy farming, so you're talking about many square miles, thousands of time more area than you think of as a normal energy plant. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Also, these are intermittent sources. </seg>
<seg id="95"> The sun doesn't shine all day, it doesn't shine every day, and, likewise, the wind doesn't blow all the time. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And so, if you depend on these sources, you have to have some way of getting the energy during those time periods that it's not available. </seg>
<seg id="97"> So, we've got big cost challenges here, we have transmission challenges: for example, say this energy source is outside your country; you not only need the technology, but you have to deal with the risk of the energy coming from elsewhere. </seg>
<seg id="98"> And, finally, this storage problem. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And, to dimensionalize this, I went through and looked at all the types of batteries that get made -- for cars, for computers, for phones, for flashlights, for everything -- and compared that to the amount of electrical energy the world uses, and what I found is that all the batteries we make now could store less than 10 minutes of all the energy. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And so, in fact, we need a big breakthrough here, something that's going to be a factor of 100 better than the approaches we have now. </seg>
<seg id="101"> It's not impossible, but it's not a very easy thing. </seg>
<seg id="102"> Now, this shows up when you try to get the intermittent source to be above, say, 20 to 30 percent of what you're using. </seg>
<seg id="103"> If you're counting on it for 100 percent, you need an incredible miracle battery. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Now, how we're going to go forward on this -- what's the right approach? </seg>
<seg id="105"> Is it a Manhattan Project? What's the thing that can get us there? </seg>
<seg id="106"> Well, we need lots of companies working on this, hundreds. </seg>
<seg id="107"> In each of these five paths, we need at least a hundred people. </seg>
<seg id="108"> And a lot of them, you'll look at and say, "They're crazy." That's good. </seg>
<seg id="109"> And, I think, here in the TED group, we have many people who are already pursuing this. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Bill Gross has several companies, including one called eSolar that has some great solar thermal technologies. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Vinod Khosla's investing in dozens of companies that are doing great things and have interesting possibilities, and I'm trying to help back that. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Nathan Myhrvold and I actually are backing a company that, perhaps surprisingly, is actually taking the nuclear approach. </seg>
<seg id="113"> There are some innovations in nuclear: modular, liquid. </seg>
<seg id="114"> And innovation really stopped in this industry quite some ago, so the idea that there's some good ideas laying around is not all that surprising. </seg>
<seg id="115"> The idea of TerraPower is that, instead of burning a part of uranium -- the one percent, which is the U235 -- we decided, "Let's burn the 99 percent, the U238." </seg>
<seg id="116"> It is kind of a crazy idea. </seg>
<seg id="117"> In fact, people had talked about it for a long time, but they could never simulate properly whether it would work or not, and so it's through the advent of modern supercomputers that now you can simulate and see that, yes, with the right material's approach, this looks like it would work. </seg>
<seg id="118"> And, because you're burning that 99 percent, you have greatly improved cost profile. </seg>
<seg id="119"> You actually burn up the waste, and you can actually use as fuel all the leftover waste from today's reactors. </seg>
<seg id="120"> So, instead of worrying about them, you just take that. It's a great thing. </seg>
<seg id="121"> It breathes this uranium as it goes along, so it's kind of like a candle. </seg>
<seg id="122"> You can see it's a log there, often referred to as a traveling wave reactor. </seg>
<seg id="123"> In terms of fuel, this really solves the problem. </seg>
<seg id="124"> I've got a picture here of a place in Kentucky. </seg>
<seg id="125"> This is the leftover, the 99 percent, where they've taken out the part they burn now, so it's called depleted uranium. </seg>
<seg id="126"> That would power the U.S. for hundreds of years. </seg>
<seg id="127"> And, simply by filtering seawater in an inexpensive process, you'd have enough fuel for the entire lifetime of the rest of the planet. </seg>
<seg id="128"> So, you know, it's got lots of challenges ahead, but it is an example of the many hundreds and hundreds of ideas that we need to move forward. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So let's think: How should we measure ourselves? </seg>
<seg id="130"> What should our report card look like? </seg>
<seg id="131"> Well, let's go out to where we really need to get, and then look at the intermediate. </seg>
<seg id="132"> For 2050, you've heard many people talk about this 80 percent reduction. </seg>
<seg id="133"> That really is very important, that we get there. </seg>
<seg id="134"> And that 20 percent will be used up by things going on in poor countries, still some agriculture, hopefully we will have cleaned up forestry, cement. </seg>
<seg id="135"> So, to get to that 80 percent, the developed countries, including countries like China, will have had to switch their electricity generation altogether. </seg>
<seg id="136"> So, the other grade is: Are we deploying this zero-emission technology, have we deployed it in all the developed countries and we're in the process of getting it elsewhere? </seg>
<seg id="137"> That's super important. </seg>
<seg id="138"> That's a key element of making that report card. </seg>
<seg id="139"> So, backing up from there, what should the 2020 report card look like? </seg>
<seg id="140"> Well, again, it should have the two elements. </seg>
<seg id="141"> We should go through these efficiency measures to start getting reductions: The less we emit, the less that sum will be of CO2, and, therefore, the less the temperature. </seg>
<seg id="142"> But in some ways, the grade we get there, doing things that don't get us all the way to the big reductions, is only equally, or maybe even slightly less, important than the other, which is the piece of innovation on these breakthroughs. </seg>
<seg id="143"> These breakthroughs, we need to move those at full speed, and we can measure that in terms of companies, pilot projects, regulatory things that have been changed. </seg>
<seg id="144"> There's a lot of great books that have been written about this. </seg>
<seg id="145"> The Al Gore book, "Our Choice" and the David McKay book, "Sustainable Energy Without the Hot Air." </seg>
<seg id="146"> They really go through it and create a framework that this can be discussed broadly, because we need broad backing for this. </seg>
<seg id="147"> There's a lot that has to come together. </seg>
<seg id="148"> So this is a wish. </seg>
<seg id="149"> It's a very concrete wish that we invent this technology. </seg>
<seg id="150"> If you gave me only one wish for the next 50 years -- I could pick who's president, I could pick a vaccine, which is something I love, or I could pick that this thing that's half the cost with no CO2 gets invented -- this is the wish I would pick. </seg>
<seg id="151"> This is the one with the greatest impact. </seg>
<seg id="152"> If we don't get this wish, the division between the people who think short term and long term will be terrible, between the U.S. and China, between poor countries and rich, and most of all the lives of those two billion will be far worse. </seg>
<seg id="153"> So, what do we have to do? </seg>
<seg id="154"> What am I appealing to you to step forward and drive? </seg>
<seg id="155"> We need to go for more research funding. </seg>
<seg id="156"> When countries get together in places like Copenhagen, they shouldn't just discuss the CO2. </seg>
<seg id="157"> They should discuss this innovation agenda, and you'd be stunned at the ridiculously low levels of spending on these innovative approaches. </seg>
<seg id="158"> We do need the market incentives -- CO2 tax, cap and trade -- something that gets that price signal out there. </seg>
<seg id="159"> We need to get the message out. </seg>
<seg id="160"> We need to have this dialogue be a more rational, more understandable dialogue, including the steps that the government takes. </seg>
<seg id="161"> This is an important wish, but it is one I think we can achieve. </seg>
<seg id="162"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="163"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="164"> Thank you. Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="165"> Thank you. So to understand more about TerraPower, right -- I mean, first of all, can you give a sense of what scale of investment this is? </seg>
<seg id="166"> Bil Gates: To actually do the software, buy the supercomputer, hire all the great scientists, which we've done, that's only tens of millions, and even once we test our materials out in a Russian reactor to make sure that our materials work properly, then you'll only be up in the hundreds of millions. </seg>
<seg id="167"> The tough thing is building the pilot reactor; finding the several billion, finding the regulator, the location that will actually build the first one of these. </seg>
<seg id="168"> Once you get the first one built, if it works as advertised, then it's just clear as day, because the economics, the energy density, are so different than nuclear as we know it. </seg>
<seg id="169"> And so, to understand it right, this involves building deep into the ground almost like a vertical kind of column of nuclear fuel, of this sort of spent uranium, and then the process starts at the top and kind of works down? </seg>
<seg id="170"> BG: That's right. Today, you're always refueling the reactor, so you have lots of people and lots of controls that can go wrong: that thing where you're opening it up and moving things in and out, that's not good. </seg>
<seg id="171"> So, if you have very cheap fuel that you can put 60 years in -- just think of it as a log -- put it down and not have those same complexities. </seg>
<seg id="172"> And it just sits there and burns for the 60 years, and then it's done. </seg>
<seg id="173"> It's a nuclear power plant that is its own waste disposal solution. </seg>
<seg id="174"> BG: Yeah. Well, what happens with the waste, you can let it sit there -- there's a lot less waste under this approach -- then you can actually take that, and put it into another one and burn that. </seg>
<seg id="175"> And we start off actually by taking the waste that exists today, that's sitting in these cooling pools or dry casking by reactors -- that's our fuel to begin with. </seg>
<seg id="176"> So, the thing that's been a problem from those reactors is actually what gets fed into ours, and you're reducing the volume of the waste quite dramatically as you're going through this process. </seg>
<seg id="177"> I mean, you're talking to different people around the world about the possibilities here. </seg>
<seg id="178"> Where is there most interest in actually doing something with this? </seg>
<seg id="179"> BG: Well, we haven't picked a particular place, and there's all these interesting disclosure rules about anything that's called "nuclear," so we've got a lot of interest, that people from the company have been in Russia, India, China -- I've been back seeing the secretary of energy here, talking about how this fits into the energy agenda. </seg>
<seg id="180"> So I'm optimistic. You know, the French and Japanese have done some work. </seg>
<seg id="181"> This is a variant on something that has been done. </seg>
<seg id="182"> It's an important advance, but it's like a fast reactor, and a lot of countries have built them, so anybody who's done a fast reactor is a candidate to be where the first one gets built. </seg>
<seg id="183"> So, in your mind, timescale and likelihood of actually taking something like this live? </seg>
<seg id="184"> BG: Well, we need -- for one of these high-scale, electro-generation things that's very cheap, we have 20 years to invent and then 20 years to deploy. </seg>
<seg id="185"> That's sort of the deadline that the environmental models have shown us that we have to meet. </seg>
<seg id="186"> And, you know, TerraPower, if things go well -- which is wishing for a lot -- could easily meet that. </seg>
<seg id="187"> And there are, fortunately now, dozens of companies -- we need it to be hundreds -- who, likewise, if their science goes well, if the funding for their pilot plants goes well, that they can compete for this. </seg>
<seg id="188"> And it's best if multiple succeed, because then you could use a mix of these things. </seg>
<seg id="189"> We certainly need one to succeed. </seg>
<seg id="190"> In terms of big-scale possible game changes, is this the biggest that you're aware of out there? </seg>
<seg id="191"> BG: An energy breakthrough is the most important thing. </seg>
<seg id="192"> It would have been, even without the environmental constraint, but the environmental constraint just makes it so much greater. </seg>
<seg id="193"> In the nuclear space, there are other innovators. </seg>
<seg id="194"> You know, we don't know their work as well as we know this one, but the modular people, that's a different approach. </seg>
<seg id="195"> There's a liquid-type reactor, which seems a little hard, but maybe they say that about us. </seg>
<seg id="196"> And so, there are different ones, but the beauty of this is a molecule of uranium has a million times as much energy as a molecule of, say, coal, and so -- if you can deal with the negatives, which are essentially the radiation -- the footprint and cost, the potential, in terms of effect on land and various things, is almost in a class of its own. </seg>
<seg id="197"> If this doesn't work, then what? </seg>
<seg id="198"> Do we have to start taking emergency measures to try and keep the temperature of the earth stable? </seg>
<seg id="199"> BG: If you get into that situation, it's like if you've been over-eating, and you're about to have a heart attack: Then where do you go? You may need heart surgery or something. </seg>
<seg id="200"> There is a line of research on what's called geoengineering, which are various techniques that would delay the heating to buy us 20 or 30 years to get our act together. </seg>
<seg id="201"> Now, that's just an insurance policy. </seg>
<seg id="202"> You hope you don't need to do that. </seg>
<seg id="203"> Some people say you shouldn't even work on the insurance policy because it might make you lazy, that you'll keep eating because you know heart surgery will be there to save you. </seg>
<seg id="204"> I'm not sure that's wise, given the importance of the problem, but there's now the geoengineering discussion about -- should that be in the back pocket in case things happen faster, or this innovation goes a lot slower than we expect? </seg>
<seg id="205"> Climate skeptics: If you had a sentence or two to say to them, how might you persuade them that they're wrong? </seg>
<seg id="206"> BG: Well, unfortunately, the skeptics come in different camps. </seg>
<seg id="207"> The ones who make scientific arguments are very few. </seg>
<seg id="208"> Are they saying that there's negative feedback effects that have to do with clouds that offset things? </seg>
<seg id="209"> There are very, very few things that they can even say there's a chance in a million of those things. </seg>
<seg id="210"> The main problem we have here, it's kind of like AIDS. </seg>
<seg id="211"> You make the mistake now, and you pay for it a lot later. </seg>
<seg id="212"> And so, when you have all sorts of urgent problems, the idea of taking pain now that has to do with a gain later, and a somewhat uncertain pain thing -- in fact, the IPCC report, that's not necessarily the worst case, and there are people in the rich world who look at IPCC and say, "OK, that isn't that big of a deal." </seg>
<seg id="213"> The fact is it's that uncertain part that should move us towards this. </seg>
<seg id="214"> But my dream here is that, if you can make it economic, and meet the CO2 constraints, then the skeptics say, "OK, I don't care that it doesn't put out CO2, I kind of wish it did put out CO2, but I guess I'll accept it because it's cheaper than what's come before." </seg>
<seg id="215"> And so, that would be your response to the Bjorn Lomborg argument, that basically if you spend all this energy trying to solve the CO2 problem, it's going to take away all your other goals of trying to rid the world of poverty and malaria and so forth, it's a stupid waste of the Earth's resources to put money towards that when there are better things we can do. </seg>
<seg id="216"> BG: Well, the actual spending on the R&amp;D piece -- say the U.S. should spend 10 billion a year more than it is right now -- it's not that dramatic. </seg>
<seg id="217"> It shouldn't take away from other things. </seg>
<seg id="218"> The thing you get into big money on, and this, reasonable people can disagree, is when you have something that's non-economic and you're trying to fund that -- that, to me, mostly is a waste. </seg>
<seg id="219"> Unless you're very close and you're just funding the learning curve and it's going to get very cheap, I believe we should try more things that have a potential to be far less expensive. </seg>
<seg id="220"> If the trade-off you get into is, "Let's make energy super expensive," then the rich can afford that. </seg>
<seg id="221"> I mean, all of us here could pay five times as much for our energy and not change our lifestyle. </seg>
<seg id="222"> The disaster is for that two billion. </seg>
<seg id="223"> And even Lomborg has changed. </seg>
<seg id="224"> His shtick now is, "Why isn't the R&amp;D getting more discussed?" </seg>
<seg id="225"> He's still, because of his earlier stuff, still associated with the skeptic camp, but he's realized that's a pretty lonely camp, and so, he's making the R&amp;D point. </seg>
<seg id="226"> And so there is a thread of something that I think is appropriate. </seg>
<seg id="227"> The R&amp;D piece, it's crazy how little it's funded. </seg>
<seg id="228"> Well Bill, I suspect I speak on the behalf of most people here to say I really hope your wish comes true. Thank you so much. </seg>
<seg id="229"> BG: Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="837" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/tom_wujec_build_a_tower.html</url>
<description>Tom Wujec presents some surprisingly deep research into the "marshmallow problem" -- a simple team-building exercise that involves dry spaghetti, one yard of tape and a marshmallow. Who can build the tallest tower with these ingredients? And why does a surprising group always beat the average?</description>
<keywords>business,collaboration,culture,design,entertainment,psychology</keywords>
<talkid>837</talkid>
<title>Tom Wujec: Build a tower, build a team</title>
<seg id="1"> Several years ago here at TED, Peter Skillman introduced a design challenge called the marshmallow challenge. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And the idea's pretty simple: Teams of four have to build the tallest free-standing structure out of 20 sticks of spaghetti, one yard of tape, one yard of string and a marshmallow. </seg>
<seg id="3"> The marshmallow has to be on top. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And, though it seems really simple, it's actually pretty hard because it forces people to collaborate very quickly. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And so, I thought this was an interesting idea, and I incorporated it into a design workshop. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And it was a huge success. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And since then, I've conducted about 70 design workshops across the world with students and designers and architects, even the CTOs of the Fortune 50, and there's something about this exercise that reveals very deep lessons about the nature of collaboration, and I'd like to share some of them with you. </seg>
<seg id="8"> So, normally, most people begin by orienting themselves to the task. </seg>
<seg id="9"> They talk about it, they figure out what it's going to look like, they jockey for power. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Then they spend some time planning, organizing, they sketch and they lay out spaghetti. </seg>
<seg id="11"> They spend the majority of their time assembling the sticks into ever-growing structures. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And then finally, just as they're running out of time, someone takes out the marshmallow, and then they gingerly put it on top, and then they stand back, and -- ta-da! -- they admire their work. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But what really happens, most of the time, is that the "ta-da" turns into an "uh-oh," because the weight of the marshmallow causes the entire structure to buckle and to collapse. </seg>
<seg id="14"> So there are a number of people who have a lot more "uh-oh" moments than others, and among the worst are recent graduates of business school. </seg>
<seg id="15"> They lie, they cheat, they get distracted and they produce really lame structures. </seg>
<seg id="16"> And of course there are teams that have a lot more "ta-da" structures, and among the best are recent graduates of kindergarten. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And it's pretty amazing. </seg>
<seg id="18"> As Peter tells us, not only do they produce the tallest structures, but they're the most interesting structures of them all. </seg>
<seg id="19"> So the question you want to ask is: How come? Why? What is it about them? </seg>
<seg id="20"> And Peter likes to say that none of the kids spend any time trying to be CEO of Spaghetti, Inc. Right? </seg>
<seg id="21"> They don't spend time jockeying for power. </seg>
<seg id="22"> But there's another reason as well. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And the reason is that business students are trained to find the single right plan, right? </seg>
<seg id="24"> And then they execute on it. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And then what happens is, when they put the marshmallow on the top, they run out of time and what happens? </seg>
<seg id="26"> It's a crisis. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Sound familiar? Right. </seg>
<seg id="28"> What kindergarteners do differently is that they start with the marshmallow, and they build prototypes, successive prototypes, always keeping the marshmallow on top, so they have multiple times to fix when they build prototypes along the way. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Designers recognize this type of collaboration as the essence of the iterative process. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And with each version, kids get instant feedback about what works and what doesn't work. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So the capacity to play in prototype is really essential, but let's look at how different teams perform. </seg>
<seg id="32"> So the average for most people is around 20 inches; business schools students, about half of that; lawyers, a little better, but not much better than that, kindergarteners, better than most adults. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Who does the very best? </seg>
<seg id="34"> Architects and engineers, thankfully. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Thirty-nine inches is the tallest structure I've seen. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And why is it? Because they understand triangles and self-reinforcing geometrical patterns are the key to building stable structures. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So CEOs, a little bit better than average, but here's where it gets interesting. </seg>
<seg id="38"> If you put you put an executive admin. on the team, they get significantly better. </seg>
<seg id="39"> It's incredible. You know, you look around, you go, "Oh, that team's going to win." </seg>
<seg id="40"> You can just tell beforehand. And why is that? </seg>
<seg id="41"> Because they have special skills of facilitation. </seg>
<seg id="42"> They manage the process, they understand the process. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And any team who manages and pays close attention to work will significantly improve the team's performance. </seg>
<seg id="44"> Specialized skills and facilitation skills are the combination that leads to strong success. </seg>
<seg id="45"> If you have 10 teams that typically perform, you'll get maybe six or so that have standing structures. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And I tried something interesting. </seg>
<seg id="47"> I thought, let's up the ante, once. </seg>
<seg id="48"> So I offered a 10,000 dollar prize of software to the winning team. </seg>
<seg id="49"> So what do you think happened to these design students? </seg>
<seg id="50"> What was the result? </seg>
<seg id="51"> Here's what happened: Not one team had a standing structure. </seg>
<seg id="52"> If anyone had built, say, a one inch structure, they would have taken home the prize. </seg>
<seg id="53"> So, isn't that interesting? That high stakes have a strong impact. </seg>
<seg id="54"> We did the exercise again with the same students. </seg>
<seg id="55"> What do you think happened then? </seg>
<seg id="56"> So now they understand the value of prototyping. </seg>
<seg id="57"> So the same team went from being the very worst to being among the very best. </seg>
<seg id="58"> They produced the tallest structures in the least amount of time. </seg>
<seg id="59"> So there's deep lessons for us about the nature of incentives and success. </seg>
<seg id="60"> So, you might ask: Why would anyone actually spend time writing a marshmallow challenge? </seg>
<seg id="61"> And the reason is, I help create digital tools and processes to help teams build cars and video games and visual effects. </seg>
<seg id="62"> And what the marshmallow challenge does is it helps them identify the hidden assumptions. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Because, frankly, every project has its own marshmallow, doesn't it? </seg>
<seg id="64"> The challenge provides a shared experience, a common language, a common stance to build the right prototype. </seg>
<seg id="65"> And so, this is the value of the experience, of this so simple exercise. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And those of you who are interested may want to go to MarshmallowChallenge.com. </seg>
<seg id="67"> It's a blog that you can look at how to build the marshmallows. </seg>
<seg id="68"> There's step-by-step instructions on this. </seg>
<seg id="69"> There are crazy examples from around the world of how people tweak and adjust the system. </seg>
<seg id="70"> There's world records that are on this as well. </seg>
<seg id="71"> And the fundamental lesson, I believe, is that design truly is a contact sport. </seg>
<seg id="72"> It demands that we bring all of our senses to the task, and that we apply the very best of our thinking, our feeling and our doing to the challenge that we have at hand. </seg>
<seg id="73"> And sometimes, a little prototype of this experience is all that it takes to turn us from an "uh-oh" moment to a "ta-da" moment. </seg>
<seg id="74"> And that can make a big difference. </seg>
<seg id="75"> Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="824" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/michael_specter_the_danger_of_science_denial.html</url>
<description>Vaccine-autism claims, "Frankenfood" bans, the herbal cure craze: All point to the public's growing fear of science and reason, says Michael Specter. He warns the trend spells disaster for human progress.</description>
<keywords>global issues,medicine,religion,science,writing</keywords>
<talkid>824</talkid>
<title>Michael Specter: The danger of science denial</title>
<seg id="1"> Let's pretend right here we have a machine. </seg>
<seg id="2"> A big machine, a cool, TED-ish machine, and it's a time machine. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And everyone in this room has to get into it. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And you can go backwards, you can go forwards; you cannot stay where you are. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And I wonder what you'd choose, because I've been asking my friends this question a lot lately and they all want to go back. </seg>
<seg id="6"> I don't know. They want to go back before there were automobiles or Twitter or "American Idol." </seg>
<seg id="7"> I don't know. </seg>
<seg id="8"> I'm convinced that there's some sort of pull to nostalgia, to wishful thinking. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And I understand that. </seg>
<seg id="10"> I'm not part of that crowd, I have to say. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I don't want to go back, and it's not because I'm adventurous. </seg>
<seg id="12"> It's because possibilities on this planet, they don't go back, they go forward. </seg>
<seg id="13"> So I want to get in the machine, and I want to go forward. </seg>
<seg id="14"> This is the greatest time there's ever been on this planet by any measure that you wish to choose: health, wealth, mobility, opportunity, declining rates of disease ... </seg>
<seg id="15"> There's never been a time like this. </seg>
<seg id="16"> My great-grandparents died, all of them, by the time they were 60. </seg>
<seg id="17"> My grandparents pushed that number to 70. </seg>
<seg id="18"> My parents are closing in on 80. </seg>
<seg id="19"> So there better be a nine at the beginning of my death number. </seg>
<seg id="20"> But it's not even about people like us, because this is a bigger deal than that. </seg>
<seg id="21"> A kid born in New Delhi today can expect to live as long as the richest man in the world did 100 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Think about that, it's an incredible fact. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And why is it true? </seg>
<seg id="24"> Smallpox. Smallpox killed billions of people on this planet. </seg>
<seg id="25"> It reshaped the demography of the globe in a way that no war ever has. </seg>
<seg id="26"> It's gone. It's vanished. </seg>
<seg id="27"> We vanquished it. Puff. </seg>
<seg id="28"> In the rich world, diseases that threatened millions of us just a generation ago no longer exist, hardly. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Diphtheria, rubella, polio ... </seg>
<seg id="30"> does anyone even know what those things are? </seg>
<seg id="31"> Vaccines, modern medicine, our ability to feed billions of people, those are triumphs of the scientific method. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And to my mind, the scientific method -- trying stuff out, seeing if it works, changing it when it doesn't -- is one of the great accomplishments of humanity. </seg>
<seg id="33"> So that's the good news. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Unfortunately, that's all the good news because there are some other problems, and they've been mentioned many times. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And one of them is that despite all our accomplishments, a billion people go to bed hungry in this world every day. </seg>
<seg id="36"> That number's rising, and it's rising really rapidly, and it's disgraceful. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And not only that, we've used our imagination to thoroughly trash this globe. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Potable water, arable land, rainforests, oil, gas: they're going away, and they're going away soon, and unless we innovate our way out of this mess, we're going away too. </seg>
<seg id="39"> So the question is: Can we do that? And I think we can. </seg>
<seg id="40"> I think it's clear that we can make food that will feed billions of people without raping the land that they live on. </seg>
<seg id="41"> I think we can power this world with energy that doesn't also destroy it. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I really do believe that, and, no, it ain't wishful thinking. </seg>
<seg id="43"> But here's the thing that keeps me up at night -- one of the things that keeps me up at night: We've never needed progress in science more than we need it right now. Never. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And we've also never been in a position to deploy it properly in the way that we can today. </seg>
<seg id="45"> We're on the verge of amazing, amazing events in many fields, and yet I actually think we'd have to go back hundreds, 300 years, before the Enlightenment, to find a time when we battled progress, when we fought about these things more vigorously, on more fronts, than we do now. </seg>
<seg id="46"> People wrap themselves in their beliefs, and they do it so tightly that you can't set them free. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Not even the truth will set them free. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And, listen, everyone's entitled to their opinion; they're even entitled to their opinion about progress. </seg>
<seg id="49"> But you know what you're not entitled to? </seg>
<seg id="50"> You're not entitled to your own facts. Sorry, you're not. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And this took me awhile to figure out. </seg>
<seg id="52"> About a decade ago, I wrote a story about vaccines for The New Yorker. A little story. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And I was amazed to find opposition: opposition to what is, after all, the most effective public health measure in human history. </seg>
<seg id="54"> I didn't know what to do, so I just did what I do: I wrote a story and I moved on. </seg>
<seg id="55"> And soon after that, I wrote a story about genetically engineered food. </seg>
<seg id="56"> Same thing, only bigger. </seg>
<seg id="57"> People were going crazy. </seg>
<seg id="58"> So I wrote a story about that too, and I couldn't understand why people thought this was "Frankenfoods," why they thought moving molecules around in a specific, rather than a haphazard way, was trespassing on nature's ground. </seg>
<seg id="59"> But, you know, I do what I do. I wrote the story, I moved on. </seg>
<seg id="60"> I mean, I'm a journalist. </seg>
<seg id="61"> We type, we file, we go to dinner. It's fine. </seg>
<seg id="62"> But these stories bothered me, and I couldn't figure out why, and eventually I did. </seg>
<seg id="63"> And that's because those fanatics that were driving me crazy weren't actually fanatics at all. </seg>
<seg id="64"> They were thoughtful people, educated people, decent people. </seg>
<seg id="65"> They were exactly like the people in this room. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And it just disturbed me so much. </seg>
<seg id="67"> But then I thought, you know, let's be honest. </seg>
<seg id="68"> We're at a point in this world where we don't have the same relationship to progress that we used to. </seg>
<seg id="69"> We talk about it ambivalently. </seg>
<seg id="70"> We talk about it in ironic terms with little quotes around it: "progress." </seg>
<seg id="71"> Okay, there are reasons for that, and I think we know what those reasons are. </seg>
<seg id="72"> We've lost faith in institutions, in authority, and sometimes in science itself, and there's no reason we shouldn't have. </seg>
<seg id="73"> You can just say a few names and people will understand. </seg>
<seg id="74"> Chernobyl, Bhopal, the Challenger, Vioxx, weapons of mass destruction, hanging chads. </seg>
<seg id="75"> You know, you can choose your list. </seg>
<seg id="76"> There are questions and problems with the people we used to believe were always right, so be skeptical. </seg>
<seg id="77"> Ask questions, demand proof, demand evidence. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Don't take anything for granted. </seg>
<seg id="79"> But here's the thing: When you get proof, you need to accept the proof, and we're not that good at doing that. </seg>
<seg id="80"> And the reason that I can say that is because we're now in an epidemic of fear like one I've never seen and hope never to see again. </seg>
<seg id="81"> About 12 years ago, there was a story published, a horrible story, that linked the epidemic of autism to the measles, mumps and rubella vaccine shot. </seg>
<seg id="82"> Very scary. </seg>
<seg id="83"> Tons of studies were done to see if this was true. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Tons of studies should have been done; it's a serious issue. </seg>
<seg id="85"> The data came back. </seg>
<seg id="86"> The data came back from the United States, from England, from Sweden, from Canada, and it was all the same: no correlation, no connection, none at all. </seg>
<seg id="87"> It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter because we believe anecdotes, we believe what we see, what we think we see, what makes us feel real. </seg>
<seg id="88"> We don't believe a bunch of documents from a government official giving us data, and I do understand that, I think we all do. </seg>
<seg id="89"> But you know what? </seg>
<seg id="90"> The result of that has been disastrous. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Disastrous because here's a fact: The United States is one of the only countries in the world where the vaccine rate for measles is going down. </seg>
<seg id="92"> That is disgraceful, and we should be ashamed of ourselves. </seg>
<seg id="93"> It's horrible. </seg>
<seg id="94"> What kind of a thing happened that we could do that? </seg>
<seg id="95"> Now, I understand it. I do understand it. </seg>
<seg id="96"> Because, did anyone have measles here? </seg>
<seg id="97"> Has one person in this audience ever seen someone die of measles? </seg>
<seg id="98"> Doesn't happen very much. </seg>
<seg id="99"> Doesn't happen in this country at all, but it happened 160,000 times in the world last year. </seg>
<seg id="100"> That's a lot of death of measles -- 20 an hour. </seg>
<seg id="101"> But since it didn't happen here, we can put it out of our minds, and people like Jenny McCarthy can go around preaching messages of fear and illiteracy from platforms like "Oprah" and "Larry King Live." </seg>
<seg id="102"> And they can do it because they don't link causation and correlation. </seg>
<seg id="103"> They don't understand that these things seem the same, but they're almost never the same. </seg>
<seg id="104"> And it's something we need to learn, and we need to learn it really soon. </seg>
<seg id="105"> This guy was a hero, Jonas Salk. </seg>
<seg id="106"> He took one of the worst scourges of mankind away from us. </seg>
<seg id="107"> No fear, no agony. Polio -- puff, gone. </seg>
<seg id="108"> That guy in the middle, not so much. </seg>
<seg id="109"> His name is Paul Offit. </seg>
<seg id="110"> He just developed a rotavirus vaccine with a bunch of other people. </seg>
<seg id="111"> It'll save the lives of 400 to 500,000 kids in the developing world every year. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Pretty good, right? </seg>
<seg id="113"> Well, it's good, except that Paul goes around talking about vaccines and says how valuable they are and that people ought to just stop the whining. </seg>
<seg id="114"> And he actually says it that way. </seg>
<seg id="115"> So, Paul's a terrorist. </seg>
<seg id="116"> When Paul speaks in a public hearing, he can't testify without armed guards. </seg>
<seg id="117"> He gets called at home because people like to tell him that they remember where his kids go to school. </seg>
<seg id="118"> And why? Because Paul made a vaccine. </seg>
<seg id="119"> I don't need to say this, but vaccines are essential. </seg>
<seg id="120"> You take them away, disease comes back, horrible diseases. And that's happening. </seg>
<seg id="121"> We have measles in this country now. </seg>
<seg id="122"> And it's getting worse, and pretty soon kids are going to die of it again because it's just a numbers game. </seg>
<seg id="123"> And they're not just going to die of measles. </seg>
<seg id="124"> What about polio? Let's have that. Why not? </seg>
<seg id="125"> A college classmate of mine wrote me a couple weeks ago and said she thought I was a little strident. </seg>
<seg id="126"> No one's ever said that before. </seg>
<seg id="127"> She wasn't going to vaccinate her kid against polio, no way. </seg>
<seg id="128"> Fine. </seg>
<seg id="129"> Why? Because we don't have polio. And you know what? </seg>
<seg id="130"> We didn't have polio in this country yesterday. </seg>
<seg id="131"> Today, I don't know, maybe a guy got on a plane in Lagos this morning, and he's flying to LAX, right now he's over Ohio. </seg>
<seg id="132"> And he's going to land in a couple of hours, he's going to rent a car, and he's going to come to Long Beach, and he's going to attend one of these fabulous TED dinners tonight. </seg>
<seg id="133"> And he doesn't know that he's infected with a paralytic disease, and we don't either because that's the way the world works. </seg>
<seg id="134"> That's the planet we live on. Don't pretend it isn't. </seg>
<seg id="135"> Now, we love to wrap ourselves in lies. We love to do it. </seg>
<seg id="136"> Everyone take their vitamins this morning? </seg>
<seg id="137"> Echinacea, a little antioxidant to get you going. </seg>
<seg id="138"> I know you did because half of Americans do every day. </seg>
<seg id="139"> They take the stuff, and they take alternative medicines, and it doesn't matter how often we find out that they're useless. </seg>
<seg id="140"> The data says it all the time. </seg>
<seg id="141"> They darken your urine. They almost never do more than that. </seg>
<seg id="142"> It's okay, you want to pay 28 billion dollars for dark urine? </seg>
<seg id="143"> I'm totally with you. </seg>
<seg id="144"> Dark urine. Dark. </seg>
<seg id="145"> Why do we do that? Why do we do that? </seg>
<seg id="146"> Well, I think I understand, we hate Big Pharma. </seg>
<seg id="147"> We hate Big Government. We don't trust the Man. </seg>
<seg id="148"> And we shouldn't: Our health care system sucks. </seg>
<seg id="149"> It's cruel to millions of people. </seg>
<seg id="150"> It's absolutely astonishingly cold and soul-bending to those of us who can even afford it. </seg>
<seg id="151"> So we run away from it, and where do we run? </seg>
<seg id="152"> We leap into the arms of Big Placebo. </seg>
<seg id="153"> That's fantastic. I love Big Placebo. </seg>
<seg id="154"> But, you know, it's really a serious thing because this stuff is crap, and we spend billions of dollars on it. </seg>
<seg id="155"> And I have all sorts of little props here. </seg>
<seg id="156"> None of it ... ginkgo, fraud; echinacea, fraud; acai -- I don't even know what that is but we're spending billions of dollars on it -- it's fraud. </seg>
<seg id="157"> And you know what? When I say this stuff, people scream at me, and they say, "What do you care? Let people do what they want to do. </seg>
<seg id="158"> It makes them feel good." </seg>
<seg id="159"> And you know what? You're wrong. </seg>
<seg id="160"> Because I don't care if it's the secretary of HHS who's saying, "Hmm, I'm not going to take the evidence of my experts on mammograms," or some cancer quack who wants to treat his patient with coffee enemas. </seg>
<seg id="161"> When you start down the road where belief and magic replace evidence and science, you end up in a place you don't want to be. </seg>
<seg id="162"> You end up in Thabo Mbeki South Africa. </seg>
<seg id="163"> He killed 400,000 of his people by insisting that beetroot, garlic and lemon oil were much more effective than the antiretroviral drugs we know can slow the course of AIDS. </seg>
<seg id="164"> Hundreds of thousands of needless deaths in a country that has been plagued worse than any other by this disease. </seg>
<seg id="165"> Please, don't tell me there are no consequences to these things. </seg>
<seg id="166"> There are. There always are. </seg>
<seg id="167"> Now, the most mindless epidemic we're in the middle of right now is this absurd battle between proponents of genetically engineered food and the organic elite. </seg>
<seg id="168"> It's an idiotic debate. It has to stop. </seg>
<seg id="169"> It's a debate about words, about metaphors. </seg>
<seg id="170"> It's ideology, it's not science. </seg>
<seg id="171"> Every single thing we eat, every grain of rice, every sprig of parsley, every Brussels sprout has been modified by man. </seg>
<seg id="172"> You know, there weren't tangerines in the garden of Eden. </seg>
<seg id="173"> There wasn't any cantaloupe. </seg>
<seg id="174"> There weren't Christmas trees. We made it all. </seg>
<seg id="175"> We made it over the last 11,000 years. </seg>
<seg id="176"> And some of it worked, and some of it didn't. </seg>
<seg id="177"> We got rid of the stuff that didn't. </seg>
<seg id="178"> Now we can do it in a more precise way -- and there are risks, absolutely -- but we can put something like vitamin A into rice, and that stuff can help millions of people, millions of people, prolong their lives. </seg>
<seg id="179"> You don't want to do that? </seg>
<seg id="180"> I have to say, I don't understand it. </seg>
<seg id="181"> We object to genetically engineered food. </seg>
<seg id="182"> Why do we do that? </seg>
<seg id="183"> Well, the things I constantly hear are: Too many chemicals, pesticides, hormones, monoculture, we don't want giant fields of the same thing, that's wrong. </seg>
<seg id="184"> We don't companies patenting life. </seg>
<seg id="185"> We don't want companies owning seeds. </seg>
<seg id="186"> And you know what my response to all of that is? </seg>
<seg id="187"> Yes, you're right. Let's fix it. </seg>
<seg id="188"> It's true, we've got a huge food problem, but this isn't science. </seg>
<seg id="189"> This has nothing to do with science. </seg>
<seg id="190"> It's law, it's morality, it's patent stuff. </seg>
<seg id="191"> You know science isn't a company. </seg>
<seg id="192"> It's not a country. </seg>
<seg id="193"> It's not even an idea; it's a process. </seg>
<seg id="194"> It's a process, and sometimes it works and sometimes it doesn't, but the idea that we should not allow science to do its job because we're afraid, is really very deadening, and it's preventing millions of people from prospering. </seg>
<seg id="195"> You know, in the next 50 years we're going to have to grow 70 percent more food than we do right now, 70 percent. </seg>
<seg id="196"> This investment in Africa over the last 30 years. </seg>
<seg id="197"> Disgraceful. Disgraceful. </seg>
<seg id="198"> They need it, and we're not giving it to them. </seg>
<seg id="199"> And why? Genetically engineered food. </seg>
<seg id="200"> We don't want to encourage people to eat that rotten stuff, like cassava for instance. </seg>
<seg id="201"> Cassava's something that half a billion people eat. </seg>
<seg id="202"> It's kind of like a potato. </seg>
<seg id="203"> It's just a bunch of calories. It sucks. </seg>
<seg id="204"> It doesn't have nutrients, it doesn't have protein, and scientists are engineering all of that into it right now. </seg>
<seg id="205"> And then people would be able to eat it and they'd be able to not go blind. </seg>
<seg id="206"> They wouldn't starve, and you know what? </seg>
<seg id="207"> That would be nice. It wouldn't be Chez Panisse, but it would be nice. </seg>
<seg id="208"> And all I can say about this is: Why are we fighting it? </seg>
<seg id="209"> I mean, let's ask ourselves: Why are we fighting it? </seg>
<seg id="210"> Because we don't want to move genes around? </seg>
<seg id="211"> This is about moving genes around. It's not about chemicals. </seg>
<seg id="212"> It's not about our ridiculous passion for hormones, our insistence on having bigger food, better food, singular food. </seg>
<seg id="213"> This isn't about Rice Krispies, this is about keeping people alive, and it's about time we started to understand what that meant. </seg>
<seg id="214"> Because, you know something? </seg>
<seg id="215"> If we don't, if we continue to act the way we're acting, we're guilty of something that I don't think we want to be guilty of: high-tech colonialism. </seg>
<seg id="216"> There's no other way to describe what's going on here. </seg>
<seg id="217"> It's selfish, it's ugly, it's beneath us, and we really have to stop it. </seg>
<seg id="218"> So after this amazingly fun conversation, you might want to say, "So, you still want to get in this ridiculous time machine and go forward?" </seg>
<seg id="219"> Absolutely. Absolutely, I do. </seg>
<seg id="220"> It's stuck in the present right now, but we have an amazing opportunity. </seg>
<seg id="221"> We can set that time machine on anything we want. </seg>
<seg id="222"> We can move it where we want to move it, and we're going to move it where we want to move it. </seg>
<seg id="223"> We have to have these conversations and we have to think, but when we get in the time machine and we go ahead, we're going to be happy we do. </seg>
<seg id="224"> I know that we can, and as far as I'm concerned, that's something the world needs right now. </seg>
<seg id="225"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="226"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="792" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/eric_mead_the_magic_of_the_placebo.html</url>
<description>Sugar pills, injections of nothing -- studies show that, more often than you'd expect, placebos really work. At TEDMED, magician Eric Mead does a trick to prove that, even when you know something's not real, you can still react as powerfully as if it is. </description>
<keywords>entertainment,illusion,magic,medicine,play,science</keywords>
<talkid>792</talkid>
<title>Eric Mead: The magic of the placebo</title>
<seg id="1"> For some time I have been interested in the placebo effect, which might seem like an odd thing for a magician to be interested in, unless you think of it in the terms that I do, which is, "Something fake is believed in enough by somebody that it becomes something real." </seg>
<seg id="2"> In other words, sugar pills have a measurable effect in certain kinds of studies, the placebo effect, just because the person thinks that what's happening to them is a pharmaceutical or some sort of a -- for pain management, for example, if they believe it enough there is a measurable effect in the body called the placebo effect. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Something fake becomes something real because of someone's perception of it. </seg>
<seg id="4"> In order for us to understand each other, I want to start by showing you a rudimentary, very simple magic trick. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And I'm going to show you how it works. This is a trick that's been in every children's magic book since at least the 1950s. </seg>
<seg id="6"> I learned it myself from Cub Scout Magic in the 1970s. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I'll do it for you, and then I'll explain it. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And then I'll explain why I explained it. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So, here's what happens. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The knife, which you can examine; my hand, which you could examine. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I'm just going to hold the knife in my fist like this. </seg>
<seg id="12"> I'll get my sleeve back. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And to make sure nothing goes up or down my sleeve I'm just going to squeeze my wrist right here. </seg>
<seg id="14"> That way you can see that at no time can anything travel, as long as I'm squeezing there nothing can go up or down my sleeve. </seg>
<seg id="15"> And the object of this is quite simple. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I'm going to open my hand, and hopefully, if all is well, my pure animal magnetism will hold the knife. </seg>
<seg id="17"> In fact it's held so tightly in place that I can shake it, and the knife does not come off. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Nothing goes up or down my sleeve, no trickery. And you can examine everything. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Ta-da! </seg>
<seg id="20"> So, this is a trick that I often teach to young children that are interested in magic, because you can learn a great deal about deception by studying this very -- even though it's a very simple trick methodologically. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Probably many of you in the room know this trick. </seg>
<seg id="22"> What happens is this. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I hold the knife in my hand. </seg>
<seg id="24"> I say I'm going to grab hold of my wrist to make sure nothing goes up or down my sleeve, that is a lie. </seg>
<seg id="25"> The reason I'm holding onto my wrist is because that's actually the secret of the illusion. </seg>
<seg id="26"> In a moment when my hand moves from facing you to being away from you, this finger right here, my index finger is just going to shift from where it is, to a position pointing out like this. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Nice one. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Someone who didn't have a childhood is out there. </seg>
<seg id="29"> So, it goes like this, from here, right. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And as I move around my finger shifts. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And we could talk about why this is deceptive, why you don't notice there are only three fingers down here, because the mind, and the way it processes information, it doesn't count, one, two, three. It groups them. </seg>
<seg id="32"> But that's not really what this is about. Right? And then I open my hand up. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Obviously it's clinging there, not by animal magnetism, but by chicanery, my index finger being there. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And then when I close my finger, same thing, as I move back, this motion kind of covers the moving back of my finger. </seg>
<seg id="35"> I take this hand away. You give the knife out. </seg>
<seg id="36"> There is a trick you can do for your friends and neighbors. Thanks. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Now, what does that have to do with the placebo effect? </seg>
<seg id="38"> I read a study a year or so ago that really blew my mind wide open. </seg>
<seg id="39"> I'm not a doctor or a researcher, so this, to me, was an astonishing thing. </seg>
<seg id="40"> It turns out that if you administer a placebo in the form of a white pill, that's like aspirin shaped -- it's just a round white pill -- it has some certain measurable effect. </seg>
<seg id="41"> But if you change the form that you give the placebo in, like you make a smaller pill, and color it blue, and stamp a letter into it, it is actually measurably more effective. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Even though neither one of these things has any pharmaceutical -- they're sugar pills. </seg>
<seg id="43"> But a white pill is not as good as a blue pill. </seg>
<seg id="44"> What? That really flipped me out. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Turns out though, that that's not even where it stops. </seg>
<seg id="46"> If you have capsules, they're more effective than tablets in any form. </seg>
<seg id="47"> A colored capsule, that's yellow on one end and red on the other is better than a white capsule. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Dosage has something to do with this. </seg>
<seg id="49"> One pill twice a day is not as good at three pills -- I don't remember the statistic now. Sorry. </seg>
<seg id="50"> But the point is ... </seg>
<seg id="51"> ... these dosages have something to do with it. </seg>
<seg id="52"> And the form has something to do with it. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And if you want the ultimate in placebo, you've go to the needle. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Right? A syringe with some inert -- a couple CCs of some inert something, and you inject this into a patient ... </seg>
<seg id="55"> Well this is such a powerful image in their mind, it's so much stronger than the white pill. </seg>
<seg id="56"> It's a really, this graph, well I'll show it to you some other time when we have slides. </seg>
<seg id="57"> The point is the white pill is not as good as the blue pill is not as good as the capsule is not as good as the needle. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And none of it has any real pharmaceutical quality, it's only your belief that makes it real in your body and makes a stronger effect. </seg>
<seg id="59"> I wanted to see if I could take that idea and apply it to a magic trick. </seg>
<seg id="60"> And take something that is obviously a fake trick and make it seem real. </seg>
<seg id="61"> And we know from that study that when you want reality, you go to the needle. </seg>
<seg id="62"> This is a seven-inch hatpin. It's very, very sharp, and I'm going to just sterilize it a tiny bit. </seg>
<seg id="63"> This is really my flesh. This is not Damian's special-grown flesh. </seg>
<seg id="64"> That's my skin right there. This is not a Hollywood special effect. </seg>
<seg id="65"> I'm going to pierce my skin and run this needle through to the other side. </seg>
<seg id="66"> If you're queasy -- if you faint easily -- I was doing this for some friends in the hotel room last night, and some people that I didn't know, and one woman almost passed out. </seg>
<seg id="67"> So, I suggest if you get queasy easy that you look away for about the next 30 -- in fact, you know what, I'll do the first bad part behind it. </seg>
<seg id="68"> You'll get to see, you can look away too if you'd like to. </seg>
<seg id="69"> So, here is what happens, right here, the beginning of my flesh at the lower part of my arm I just make a little pierce. </seg>
<seg id="70"> I'm sorry, man. Am I freaking you out? </seg>
<seg id="71"> OK, and then just through my skin a tiny bit, and then out the other side like this. </seg>
<seg id="72"> Now, essentially we're in the same position we were in with the knife trick. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Sort of. </seg>
<seg id="74"> But you can't count my fingers right now can you? </seg>
<seg id="75"> So, let me show them to you. That's one, two three, four, five. </seg>
<seg id="76"> Yes, well... </seg>
<seg id="77"> I know what people think when they see this. </seg>
<seg id="78"> They go, "Well, he's certainly not dumb enough to stab himself through the skin to entertain us for a few minutes. </seg>
<seg id="79"> So, let me give you a little peek. </seg>
<seg id="80"> How's that look out there? Pretty good. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Yeah, I know. </seg>
<seg id="82"> And the people in the back go, "OK, I didn't really see that." </seg>
<seg id="83"> People in the satellite room are starting to move in now. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Let me give you good close look at this. </seg>
<seg id="85"> That really is my skin. That is not a Hollywood special effect. </seg>
<seg id="86"> That's my flesh, and I can twist that around. </seg>
<seg id="87"> I'm sorry. If you're getting queasy, look away, don't look at the thing. </seg>
<seg id="88"> People in the back or people on video years from now watching this will go, "Well yeah, that looks kind of neat in some sort of effect there, but if it were real he would be -- see there's a hole there and a hole there, if it were real he would be bleeding. </seg>
<seg id="89"> Well let me work up some blood for you. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Yes, there it is. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Normally now, I would take the needle out. </seg>
<seg id="92"> I would clean off my arm, and I would show you that there are no wounds. </seg>
<seg id="93"> But I think in this context and with the idea of taking something fake and making it into something real, I'm just going to leave it there, and walk off the stage. </seg>
<seg id="94"> I will be seeing you several times over the next few days. </seg>
<seg id="95"> I hope you're looking forward to that. Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="779" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_kahneman_the_riddle_of_experience_vs_memory.html</url>
<description>Using examples from vacations to colonoscopies, Nobel laureate and founder of behavioral economics Daniel Kahneman reveals how our "experiencing selves" and our "remembering selves" perceive happiness differently. This new insight has profound implications for economics, public policy -- and our own self-awareness.</description>
<keywords>brain,culture,economics,happiness,mind,philosophy,psychology,science</keywords>
<talkid>779</talkid>
<title>Daniel Kahneman: The riddle of experience vs. memory</title>
<seg id="1"> Everybody talks about happiness these days. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I had somebody count the number of books with "happiness" in the title published in the last five years and they gave up after about 40, and there were many more. </seg>
<seg id="3"> There is a huge wave of interest in happiness, among researchers. </seg>
<seg id="4"> There is a lot of happiness coaching. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Everybody would like to make people happier. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But in spite of all this flood of work, there are several cognitive traps that sort of make it almost impossible to think straight about happiness. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And my talk today will be mostly about these cognitive traps. </seg>
<seg id="8"> This applies to laypeople thinking about their own happiness, and it applies to scholars thinking about happiness, because it turns out we're just as messed up as anybody else is. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The first of these traps is a reluctance to admit complexity. </seg>
<seg id="10"> It turns out that the word "happiness" is just not a useful word anymore, because we apply it to too many different things. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I think there is one particular meaning to which we might restrict it, but by and large, this is something that we'll have to give up and we'll have to adopt the more complicated view of what well-being is. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The second trap is a confusion between experience and memory; basically, it's between being happy in your life, and being happy about your life or happy with your life. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And those are two very different concepts, and they're both lumped in the notion of happiness. </seg>
<seg id="14"> And the third is the focusing illusion, and it's the unfortunate fact that we can't think about any circumstance that affects well-being without distorting its importance. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I mean, this is a real cognitive trap. </seg>
<seg id="16"> There's just no way of getting it right. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Now, I'd like to start with an example of somebody who had a question-and-answer session after one of my lectures reported a story, and that was a story -- He said he'd been listening to a symphony, and it was absolutely glorious music and at the very end of the recording, there was a dreadful screeching sound. </seg>
<seg id="18"> And then he added, really quite emotionally, it ruined the whole experience. </seg>
<seg id="19"> But it hadn't. </seg>
<seg id="20"> What it had ruined were the memories of the experience. </seg>
<seg id="21"> He had had the experience. </seg>
<seg id="22"> He had had 20 minutes of glorious music. </seg>
<seg id="23"> They counted for nothing because he was left with a memory; the memory was ruined, and the memory was all that he had gotten to keep. </seg>
<seg id="24"> What this is telling us, really, is that we might be thinking of ourselves and of other people in terms of two selves. </seg>
<seg id="25"> There is an experiencing self, who lives in the present and knows the present, is capable of re-living the past, but basically it has only the present. </seg>
<seg id="26"> It's the experiencing self that the doctor approaches -- you know, when the doctor asks, "Does it hurt now when I touch you here?" </seg>
<seg id="27"> And then there is a remembering self, and the remembering self is the one that keeps score, and maintains the story of our life, and it's the one that the doctor approaches in asking the question, "How have you been feeling lately?" </seg>
<seg id="28"> or "How was your trip to Albania?" or something like that. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Those are two very different entities, the experiencing self and the remembering self, and getting confused between them is part of the mess about the notion of happiness. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Now, the remembering self is a storyteller. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And that really starts with a basic response of our memories -- it starts immediately. </seg>
<seg id="32"> We don't only tell stories when we set out to tell stories. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Our memory tells us stories, that is, what we get to keep from our experiences is a story. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And let me begin with one example. </seg>
<seg id="35"> This is an old study. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Those are actual patients undergoing a painful procedure. </seg>
<seg id="37"> I won't go into detail. It's no longer painful these days, but it was painful when this study was run in the 1990s. </seg>
<seg id="38"> They were asked to report on their pain every 60 seconds. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Here are two patients, those are their recordings. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And you are asked, "Who of them suffered more?" </seg>
<seg id="41"> And it's a very easy question. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Clearly, Patient B suffered more -- his colonoscopy was longer, and every minute of pain that Patient A had, Patient B had, and more. </seg>
<seg id="43"> But now there is another question: "How much did these patients think they suffered?" </seg>
<seg id="44"> And here is a surprise. </seg>
<seg id="45"> The surprise is that Patient A had a much worse memory of the colonoscopy than Patient B. </seg>
<seg id="46"> The stories of the colonoscopies were different, and because a very critical part of the story is how it ends. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And neither of these stories is very inspiring or great -- but one of them is this distinct ... </seg>
<seg id="48"> but one of them is distinctly worse than the other. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And the one that is worse is the one where pain was at its peak at the very end; it's a bad story. </seg>
<seg id="50"> How do we know that? </seg>
<seg id="51"> Because we asked these people after their colonoscopy, and much later, too, "How bad was the whole thing, in total?" </seg>
<seg id="52"> And it was much worse for A than for B, in memory. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Now this is a direct conflict between the experiencing self and the remembering self. </seg>
<seg id="54"> From the point of view of the experiencing self, clearly, B had a worse time. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Now, what you could do with Patient A, and we actually ran clinical experiments, and it has been done, and it does work -- you could actually extend the colonoscopy of Patient A by just keeping the tube in without jiggling it too much. </seg>
<seg id="56"> That will cause the patient to suffer, but just a little and much less than before. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And if you do that for a couple of minutes, you have made the experiencing self of Patient A worse off, and you have the remembering self of Patient A a lot better off, because now you have endowed Patient A with a better story about his experience. </seg>
<seg id="58"> What defines a story? </seg>
<seg id="59"> And that is true of the stories that memory delivers for us, and it's also true of the stories that we make up. </seg>
<seg id="60"> What defines a story are changes, significant moments and endings. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Endings are very, very important and, in this case, the ending dominated. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Now, the experiencing self lives its life continuously. </seg>
<seg id="63"> It has moments of experience, one after the other. </seg>
<seg id="64"> And you can ask: What happens to these moments? </seg>
<seg id="65"> And the answer is really straightforward: They are lost forever. </seg>
<seg id="66"> I mean, most of the moments of our life -- and I calculated, you know, the psychological present is said to be about three seconds long; that means that, you know, in a life there are about 600 million of them; in a month, there are about 600,000 -- most of them don't leave a trace. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Most of them are completely ignored by the remembering self. </seg>
<seg id="68"> And yet, somehow you get the sense that they should count, that what happens during these moments of experience is our life. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It's the finite resource that we're spending while we're on this earth. </seg>
<seg id="70"> And how to spend it would seem to be relevant, but that is not the story that the remembering self keeps for us. </seg>
<seg id="71"> So we have the remembering self and the experiencing self, and they're really quite distinct. </seg>
<seg id="72"> The biggest difference between them is in the handling of time. </seg>
<seg id="73"> From the point of view of the experiencing self, if you have a vacation, and the second week is just as good as the first, then the two-week vacation is twice as good as the one-week vacation. </seg>
<seg id="74"> That's not the way it works at all for the remembering self. </seg>
<seg id="75"> For the remembering self, a two-week vacation is barely better than the one-week vacation because there are no new memories added. </seg>
<seg id="76"> You have not changed the story. </seg>
<seg id="77"> And in this way, time is actually the critical variable that distinguishes a remembering self from an experiencing self; time has very little impact on the story. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Now, the remembering self does more than remember and tell stories. </seg>
<seg id="79"> It is actually the one that makes decisions because, if you have a patient who has had, say, two colonoscopies with two different surgeons and is deciding which of them to choose, then the one that chooses is the one that has the memory that is less bad, and that's the surgeon that will be chosen. </seg>
<seg id="80"> The experiencing self has no voice in this choice. </seg>
<seg id="81"> We actually don't choose between experiences, we choose between memories of experiences. </seg>
<seg id="82"> And even when we think about the future, we don't think of our future normally as experiences. </seg>
<seg id="83"> We think of our future as anticipated memories. </seg>
<seg id="84"> And basically you can look at this, you know, as a tyranny of the remembering self, and you can think of the remembering self sort of dragging the experiencing self through experiences that the experiencing self doesn't need. </seg>
<seg id="85"> I have that sense that when we go on vacations this is very frequently the case; that is, we go on vacations, to a very large extent, in the service of our remembering self. </seg>
<seg id="86"> And this is a bit hard to justify I think. </seg>
<seg id="87"> I mean, how much do we consume our memories? </seg>
<seg id="88"> That is one of the explanations that is given for the dominance of the remembering self. </seg>
<seg id="89"> And when I think about that, I think about a vacation we had in Antarctica a few years ago, which was clearly the best vacation I've ever had, and I think of it relatively often, relative to how much I think of other vacations. </seg>
<seg id="90"> And I probably have consumed my memories of that three-week trip, I would say, for about 25 minutes in the last four years. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Now, if I had ever opened the folder with the 600 pictures in it, I would have spent another hour. </seg>
<seg id="92"> Now, that is three weeks, and that is at most an hour and a half. </seg>
<seg id="93"> There seems to be a discrepancy. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Now, I may be a bit extreme, you know, in how little appetite I have for consuming memories, but even if you do more of this, there is a genuine question: Why do we put so much weight on memory relative to the weight that we put on experiences? </seg>
<seg id="95"> So I want you to think about a thought experiment. </seg>
<seg id="96"> Imagine that for your next vacation, you know that at the end of the vacation all your pictures will be destroyed, and you'll get an amnesic drug so that you won't remember anything. </seg>
<seg id="97"> Now, would you choose the same vacation? </seg>
<seg id="98"> And if you would choose a different vacation, there is a conflict between your two selves, and you need to think about how to adjudicate that conflict, and it's actually not at all obvious, because if you think in terms of time, then you get one answer, and if you think in terms of memories, you might get another answer. </seg>
<seg id="99"> Why do we pick the vacations we do is a problem that confronts us with a choice between the two selves. </seg>
<seg id="100"> Now, the two selves bring up two notions of happiness. </seg>
<seg id="101"> There are really two concepts of happiness that we can apply, one per self. </seg>
<seg id="102"> So you can ask: How happy is the experiencing self? </seg>
<seg id="103"> And then you would ask: How happy are the moments in the experiencing self's life? </seg>
<seg id="104"> And they're all -- happiness for moments is a fairly complicated process. </seg>
<seg id="105"> What are the emotions that can be measured? </seg>
<seg id="106"> And, by the way, now we are capable of getting a pretty good idea of the happiness of the experiencing self over time. </seg>
<seg id="107"> If you ask for the happiness of the remembering self, it's a completely different thing. </seg>
<seg id="108"> This is not about how happily a person lives. </seg>
<seg id="109"> It is about how satisfied or pleased the person is when that person thinks about her life. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Very different notion. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Anyone who doesn't distinguish those notions is going to mess up the study of happiness, and I belong to a crowd of students of well-being, who've been messing up the study of happiness for a long time in precisely this way. </seg>
<seg id="112"> The distinction between the happiness of the experiencing self and the satisfaction of the remembering self has been recognized in recent years, and there are now efforts to measure the two separately. </seg>
<seg id="113"> The Gallup Organization has a world poll where more than half a million people have been asked questions about what they think of their life and about their experiences, and there have been other efforts along those lines. </seg>
<seg id="114"> So in recent years, we have begun to learn about the happiness of the two selves. </seg>
<seg id="115"> And the main lesson I think that we have learned is they are really different. </seg>
<seg id="116"> You can know how satisfied somebody is with their life, and that really doesn't teach you much about how happily they're living their life, and vice versa. </seg>
<seg id="117"> Just to give you a sense of the correlation, the correlation is about .5. </seg>
<seg id="118"> What that means is if you met somebody, and you were told, "Oh his father is six feet tall," how much would you know about his height? </seg>
<seg id="119"> Well, you would know something about his height, but there's a lot of uncertainty. </seg>
<seg id="120"> You have that much uncertainty. </seg>
<seg id="121"> If I tell you that somebody ranked their life eight on a scale of ten, you have a lot of uncertainty about how happy they are with their experiencing self. </seg>
<seg id="122"> So the correlation is low. </seg>
<seg id="123"> We know something about what controls satisfaction of the happiness self. </seg>
<seg id="124"> We know that money is very important, goals are very important. </seg>
<seg id="125"> We know that happiness is mainly being satisfied with people that we like, spending time with people that we like. </seg>
<seg id="126"> There are other pleasures, but this is dominant. </seg>
<seg id="127"> So if you want to maximize the happiness of the two selves, you are going to end up doing very different things. </seg>
<seg id="128"> The bottom line of what I've said here is that we really should not think of happiness as a substitute for well-being. </seg>
<seg id="129"> It is a completely different notion. </seg>
<seg id="130"> Now, very quickly, another reason we cannot think straight about happiness is that we do not attend to the same things when we think about life, and we actually live. </seg>
<seg id="131"> So, if you ask the simple question of how happy people are in California, you are not going to get to the correct answer. </seg>
<seg id="132"> When you ask that question, you think people must be happier in California if, say, you live in Ohio. </seg>
<seg id="133"> And what happens is when you think about living in California, you are thinking of the contrast between California and other places, and that contrast, say, is in climate. </seg>
<seg id="134"> Well, it turns out that climate is not very important to the experiencing self and it's not even very important to the reflective self that decides how happy people are. </seg>
<seg id="135"> But now, because the reflective self is in charge, you may end up -- some people may end up moving to California. </seg>
<seg id="136"> And it's sort of interesting to trace what is going to happen to people who move to California in the hope of getting happier. </seg>
<seg id="137"> Well, their experiencing self is not going to get happier. </seg>
<seg id="138"> We know that. </seg>
<seg id="139"> But one thing will happen: They will think they are happier, because, when they think about it, they'll be reminded of how horrible the weather was in Ohio, and they will feel they made the right decision. </seg>
<seg id="140"> It is very difficult to think straight about well-being, and I hope I have given you a sense of how difficult it is. </seg>
<seg id="141"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="142"> Thank you. I've got a question for you. </seg>
<seg id="143"> Thank you so much. </seg>
<seg id="144"> Now, when we were on the phone a few weeks ago, you mentioned to me that there was quite an interesting result came out of that Gallup survey. </seg>
<seg id="145"> Is that something you can share since you do have a few moments left now? </seg>
<seg id="146"> Daniel Kahneman: Sure. </seg>
<seg id="147"> I think the most interesting result that we found in the Gallup survey is a number, which we absolutely did not expect to find. </seg>
<seg id="148"> We found that with respect to the happiness of the experiencing self. </seg>
<seg id="149"> When we looked at how feelings, vary with income. </seg>
<seg id="150"> And it turns out that, below an income of 60,000 dollars a year, for Americans -- and that's a very large sample of Americans, like 600,000, so it's a large representative sample -- below an income of 600,000 dollars a year... </seg>
<seg id="151"> 60,000. </seg>
<seg id="152"> DK: 60,000. </seg>
<seg id="153"> 60,000 dollars a year, people are unhappy, and they get progressively unhappier the poorer they get. </seg>
<seg id="154"> Above that, we get an absolutely flat line. </seg>
<seg id="155"> I mean I've rarely seen lines so flat. </seg>
<seg id="156"> Clearly, what is happening is money does not buy you experiential happiness, but lack of money certainly buys you misery, and we can measure that misery very, very clearly. </seg>
<seg id="157"> In terms of the other self, the remembering self, you get a different story. </seg>
<seg id="158"> The more money you earn, the more satisfied you are. </seg>
<seg id="159"> That does not hold for emotions. </seg>
<seg id="160"> But Danny, the whole American endeavor is about life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness. </seg>
<seg id="161"> If people took seriously that finding, I mean, it seems to turn upside down everything we believe about, like for example, taxation policy and so forth. </seg>
<seg id="162"> Is there any chance that politicians, that the country generally, would take a finding like that seriously and run public policy based on it? </seg>
<seg id="163"> DK: You know I think that there is recognition of the role of happiness research in public policy. </seg>
<seg id="164"> The recognition is going to be slow in the United States, no question about that, but in the U.K., it is happening, and in other countries it is happening. </seg>
<seg id="165"> People are recognizing that they ought to be thinking of happiness when they think of public policy. </seg>
<seg id="166"> It's going to take a while, and people are going to debate whether they want to study experience happiness, or whether they want to study life evaluation, so we need to have that debate fairly soon. </seg>
<seg id="167"> How to enhance happiness goes very different ways depending on how you think, and whether you think of the remembering self or you think of the experiencing self. </seg>
<seg id="168"> This is going to influence policy, I think, in years to come. </seg>
<seg id="169"> In the United States, efforts are being made to measure the experience happiness of the population. </seg>
<seg id="170"> This is going to be, I think, within the next decade or two, part of national statistics. </seg>
<seg id="171"> Well, it seems to me that this issue will -- or at least should be -- the most interesting policy discussion to track over the next few years. </seg>
<seg id="172"> Thank you so much for inventing behavioral economics. </seg>
<seg id="173"> Thank you, Danny Kahneman. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="799" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jane_mcgonigal_gaming_can_make_a_better_world.html</url>
<description>Games like World of Warcraft give players the means to save worlds, and incentive to learn the habits of heroes. What if we could harness this gamer power to solve real-world problems? Jane McGonigal says we can, and explains how.</description>
<keywords>computers,design,entertainment,gaming,global issues,play</keywords>
<talkid>799</talkid>
<title>Jane McGonigal: Gaming can make a better world</title>
<seg id="1"> I'm Jane McGonigal. I'm a game designer. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I've been making games online now for 10 years, and my goal for the next decade is to try to make it as easy to save the world in real life as it is to save the world in online games. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now, I have a plan for this, and it entails convincing more people, including all of you, to spend more time playing bigger and better games. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Right now we spend three billion hours a week playing online games. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Some of you might be thinking, "That's a lot of time to spend playing games. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Maybe too much time, considering how many urgent problems we have to solve in the real world." </seg>
<seg id="7"> But actually, according to my research at The Institute For The Future, it's actually the opposite is true. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Three billion hours a week is not nearly enough game play to solve the world's most urgent problems. </seg>
<seg id="9"> In fact, I believe that if we want to survive the next century on this planet, we need to increase that total dramatically. </seg>
<seg id="10"> I've calculated the total we need at 21 billion hours of game play every week. </seg>
<seg id="11"> So, that's probably a bit of a counterintuitive idea, so I'll say it again, let it sink in: If we want to solve problems like hunger, poverty, climate change, global conflict, obesity, I believe that we need to aspire to play games online for at least 21 billion hours a week, by the end of the next decade. </seg>
<seg id="12"> No. I'm serious. I am. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Here's why. This picture pretty much sums up why I think games are so essential to the future survival of the human species. Truly. </seg>
<seg id="14"> This is a portrait by a photographer named Phil Toledano. </seg>
<seg id="15"> He wanted to capture the emotion of gaming, so he set up a camera in front of gamers while they were playing. </seg>
<seg id="16"> And this is a classic gaming emotion. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Now, if you're not a gamer, you might miss some of the nuance in this photo. </seg>
<seg id="18"> You probably see the sense of urgency, a little bit of fear, but intense concentration, deep, deep focus on tackling a really difficult problem. </seg>
<seg id="19"> If you are a gamer, you will notice a few nuances here: the crinkle of the eyes up, and around the mouth is a sign of optimism, and the eyebrows up is surprise. </seg>
<seg id="20"> This is a gamer who is on the verge of something called an epic win. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Oh, you've heard of that. OK, good, so we have some gamers among us. </seg>
<seg id="22"> An epic win is an outcome that is so extraordinarily positive you had no idea it was even possible until you achieved it. </seg>
<seg id="23"> It was almost beyond the threshold of imagination. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And when you get there you are shocked to discover what you are truly capable of. That is an epic win. </seg>
<seg id="25"> This is a gamer on the verge of an epic win. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And this is the face that we need to see on millions of problem-solvers all over the world as we try to tackle the obstacles of the next century -- the face of someone who, against all odds is on the verge of an epic win. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Now, unfortunately this is more of the face that we see in everyday life now as we try to tackle urgent problems. </seg>
<seg id="28"> This is what I call the "I'm Not Good At Life" face, and this is actually me making it. Can you see? Yes. Good. </seg>
<seg id="29"> This is actually me making the "I'm Not Good At Life" face. </seg>
<seg id="30"> This is a piece of graffiti in my old neighborhood in Berkeley, California, where I did my PhD on why we're better in games than we are in real life. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And this is a problem that a lot of gamers have. </seg>
<seg id="32"> We feel that we are not as good in reality as we are in games. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And I don't mean just good as in successful, although that's part of it. </seg>
<seg id="34"> We do achieve more in game worlds. But I also mean good as in motivated to do something that matters, inspired to collaborate and to cooperate. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And when we're in game worlds I believe that many of us become the best version of ourselves, the most likely to help at a moment's notice, the most likely to stick with a problem as long at it takes, to get up after failure and try again. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And in real life, when we face failure, when we confront obstacles, we often don't feel that way. </seg>
<seg id="37"> We feel overcome, we feel overwhelmed, we feel anxious, maybe depressed, frustrated or cynical. </seg>
<seg id="38"> We never have those feelings when we're playing games, they just don't exist in games. </seg>
<seg id="39"> So, that's what I wanted to study when I was a graduate student. </seg>
<seg id="40"> What about games makes it impossible to feel that we can't achieve everything? </seg>
<seg id="41"> How can we take those feelings from games and apply them to real-world work? </seg>
<seg id="42"> So, I looked at games like World of Warcraft, which is really the ideal collaborative problem-solving environment. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And I started to notice a few things that make epic wins so possible in online worlds. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So, the first thing is whenever you show up in one of these online games, especially in World of Warcraft, there are lots and lots of different characters who are willing to trust you with a world-saving mission, right away. </seg>
<seg id="45"> But not just any mission, it's a mission that is perfectly matched with your current level in the game. Right? </seg>
<seg id="46"> So, you can do it. </seg>
<seg id="47"> They never give you a challenge that you can't achieve. </seg>
<seg id="48"> But it is on the verge of what you're capable of. So, you have to try hard, but there's no unemployment in World of Warcraft. </seg>
<seg id="49"> There is no sitting around wringing your hands, there's always something specific and important to be done. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And there are also tons of collaborators. </seg>
<seg id="51"> Everywhere you go, hundreds of thousands of people ready to work with you to achieve your epic mission. </seg>
<seg id="52"> That's not something that we have in real life that easily, this sense that at our fingertips are tons of collaborators. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And also there is this epic story, this inspiring story of why we're there, and what we're doing. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And then we get all this positive feedback. </seg>
<seg id="55"> You guys have heard of leveling up and plus-one strength, and plus-one intelligence. </seg>
<seg id="56"> We don't get that kind of constant feedback in real life. </seg>
<seg id="57"> When I get off this stage I'm not going to have plus-one speaking, and plus-one crazy idea, plus-20 crazy idea. </seg>
<seg id="58"> I don't get that feedback in real life. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Now, the problem with collaborative online environments like World of Warcraft is that it's so satisfying to be on the verge of an epic win all the time that we decide to spend all our time in these game worlds. </seg>
<seg id="60"> It's just better than reality. </seg>
<seg id="61"> So, so far, collectively all the World of Warcraft gamers have spent 5.93 million years solving the virtual problems of Azeroth. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Now, that's not necessarily a bad thing. </seg>
<seg id="63"> It might sound like it's a bad thing. </seg>
<seg id="64"> But to put that in context: 5.93 million years ago was when our earliest primate human ancestors stood up. </seg>
<seg id="65"> That was the first upright primate. </seg>
<seg id="66"> Okay, so when we talk about how much time we're currently investing in playing games, the only way it makes sense to even think about it is to talk about time at the magnitude of human evolution, which is an extraordinary thing. </seg>
<seg id="67"> But it's also apt. Because it turns out that by spending all this time playing games, we're actually changing what we are capable of as human beings. </seg>
<seg id="68"> We are evolving to be a more collaborative and hearty species. </seg>
<seg id="69"> This is true. I believe this. </seg>
<seg id="70"> So, consider this really interesting statistic; it was recently published by a researcher at Carnegie Mellon University: The average young person today in a country with a strong gamer culture will have spent 10,000 hours playing online games by the age of 21. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Now 10,000 hours is a really interesting number for two reasons. </seg>
<seg id="72"> First of all, for children in the United States 10,080 hours is the exact amount of time you will spend in school from fifth grade to high school graduation if you have perfect attendance. </seg>
<seg id="73"> So, we have an entire parallel track of education going on where young people are learning as much about what it takes to be a good gamer as they are learning about everything else in school. </seg>
<seg id="74"> And some of you have probably read Malcolm Gladwell's new book "Outliers." </seg>
<seg id="75"> So, you would have heard of his theory of success, the 10,000 hour theory of success. </seg>
<seg id="76"> It's based on this great cognitive science research that if we can master 10,000 hours of effortful study at anything by the age of 21, we will be virtuosos at it. </seg>
<seg id="77"> We will be as good at whatever we do as the greatest people in the world. </seg>
<seg id="78"> And so, now what we're looking at is an entire generation of young people who are virtuoso gamers. </seg>
<seg id="79"> So, the big question is, "What exactly are gamers getting so good at?" </seg>
<seg id="80"> Because if we could figure that out, we would have a virtually unprecedented human resource on our hands. </seg>
<seg id="81"> This is how many people we now have in the world who spend at least an hour a day playing online games. </seg>
<seg id="82"> These are our virtuoso gamers, 500 million people who are extraordinarily good at something. </seg>
<seg id="83"> And in the next decade we're going to have another billion gamers who are extraordinarily good at whatever that is. </seg>
<seg id="84"> If you don't know it already, this is coming. </seg>
<seg id="85"> The game industry is developing consoles that are low energy and that work with the wireless phone networks instead of broadband Internet so that gamers all over the world, particularly in India, China, Brazil, can get online. </seg>
<seg id="86"> They expect one billion more gamers in the next decade. </seg>
<seg id="87"> It will bring us up to 1.5 billion gamers. </seg>
<seg id="88"> So, I've started to think about what these games are making us virtuosos at. </seg>
<seg id="89"> Here are the four things I came up with. The first is urgent optimism. </seg>
<seg id="90"> OK, think of this as extreme self-motivation. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Urgent optimism is the desire to act immediately to tackle an obstacle, combined with the belief that we have a reasonable hope of success. </seg>
<seg id="92"> Gamers always believe that an epic win is possible, and that it is always worth trying, and trying now. </seg>
<seg id="93"> Gamers don't sit around. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Gamers are virtuosos at weaving a tight social fabric. </seg>
<seg id="95"> There's a lot of interesting research that shows that we like people better after we play a game with them, even if they've beaten us badly. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And the reason is, it takes a lot of trust to play a game with someone. </seg>
<seg id="97"> We trust that they will spend their time with us, that they will play by the same rules, value the same goal, they'll stay with the game until it's over. </seg>
<seg id="98"> And so, playing a game together actually builds up bonds and trust and cooperation. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And we actually build stronger social relationships as a result. </seg>
<seg id="100"> Blissful productivity. I love it. </seg>
<seg id="101"> You know there's a reason why the average World of Warcraft gamer plays for 22 hours a week, kind of a half-time job. </seg>
<seg id="102"> It's because we know, when we're playing a game, that we're actually happier working hard than we are relaxing, or hanging out. </seg>
<seg id="103"> We know that we are optimized, as human beings, to do hard meaningful work. </seg>
<seg id="104"> And gamers are willing to work hard all the time, if they're given the right work. </seg>
<seg id="105"> Finally: epic meaning. </seg>
<seg id="106"> Gamers love to be attached to awe-inspiring missions to human planetary-scale stories. </seg>
<seg id="107"> So, just one bit of trivia that helps put that into perspective: So, you all know Wikipedia, biggest wiki in the world. </seg>
<seg id="108"> Second biggest wiki in the world, with nearly 80,000 articles, is the World of Warcraft wiki. </seg>
<seg id="109"> Five million people use it every month. </seg>
<seg id="110"> They have compiled more information about World of Warcraft on the Internet than any other topic covered on any other wiki in the world. </seg>
<seg id="111"> They are building an epic story. </seg>
<seg id="112"> They are building an epic knowledge resource about the World of Warcraft. </seg>
<seg id="113"> Okay, so these are four superpowers that add up to one thing: Gamers are super-empowered, hopeful individuals. </seg>
<seg id="114"> These are people who believe that they are individually capable of changing the world. </seg>
<seg id="115"> And the only problem is that they believe that they are capable of changing virtual worlds and not the real world. </seg>
<seg id="116"> That's the problem that I'm trying to solve. </seg>
<seg id="117"> There's an economist named Edward Castronova. </seg>
<seg id="118"> His work is brilliant. He looks at why people are investing so much time and energy and money in online worlds. </seg>
<seg id="119"> And he says, "We're witnessing what amounts to no less than a mass exodus to virtual worlds and online game environments." </seg>
<seg id="120"> And he's an economist. So, he's rational. </seg>
<seg id="121"> And he says ... </seg>
<seg id="122"> Not like me -- I'm a game designer; I'm exuberant. </seg>
<seg id="123"> But he says that this makes perfect sense, because gamers can achieve more in online worlds than they can in real life. </seg>
<seg id="124"> They can have stronger social relationships in games than they can have in real life; they get better feedback and feel more rewarded in games than they do in real life. </seg>
<seg id="125"> So, he says for now it makes perfect sense for gamers to spend more time in virtual worlds than the real world. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Now, I also agree that that is rational, for now. </seg>
<seg id="127"> But it is not, by any means, an optimal situation. </seg>
<seg id="128"> We have to start making the real world more like a game. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So, I take my inspiration from something that happened 2,500 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="130"> These are ancient dice, made out of sheep's knuckles. Right? </seg>
<seg id="131"> Before we had awesome game controllers, we had sheep's knuckles. </seg>
<seg id="132"> And these represent the first game equipment designed by human beings. </seg>
<seg id="133"> And if you're familiar with the work of the ancient Greek historian Herodotus, you might know this history, which is the history of who invented games and why. </seg>
<seg id="134"> Herodotus says that games, particularly dice games, were invented in the kingdom of Lydia during a time of famine. </seg>
<seg id="135"> Apparently, there was such a severe famine that the king of Lydia decided that they had to do something crazy. </seg>
<seg id="136"> People were suffering. People were fighting. </seg>
<seg id="137"> It was an extreme situation, they needed an extreme solution. </seg>
<seg id="138"> So, according to Herodotus, they invented dice games and they set up a kingdom-wide policy: On one day, everybody would eat, and on the next day, everybody would play games. </seg>
<seg id="139"> And they would be so immersed in playing the dice games because games are so engaging, and immerse us in such satisfying blissful productivity, they would ignore the fact that they had no food to eat. </seg>
<seg id="140"> And then on the next day, they would play games; and on the next day, they would eat. </seg>
<seg id="141"> And according to Herodotus, they passed 18 years this way, surviving through a famine by eating on one day and playing games on the next. </seg>
<seg id="142"> Now, this is exactly, I think, how we're using games today. </seg>
<seg id="143"> We're using games to escape real-world suffering. </seg>
<seg id="144"> We're using games to get away from everything that's broken in the real environment, everything that's not satisfying about real life, and we're getting what we need from games. </seg>
<seg id="145"> But it doesn't have to end there. </seg>
<seg id="146"> This is really exciting. </seg>
<seg id="147"> According to Herodotus, after 18 years the famine wasn't getting better, so the king decided they would play one final dice game. </seg>
<seg id="148"> They divided the entire kingdom in half. </seg>
<seg id="149"> They played one dice game, and the winners of that game got to go on an epic adventure. </seg>
<seg id="150"> They would leave Lydia, and they would go out in search of a new place to live, leaving behind just enough people to survive on the resources that were available, and hopefully to take their civilization somewhere else where they could thrive. </seg>
<seg id="151"> Now, this sounds crazy, right? </seg>
<seg id="152"> But recently, DNA evidence has shown that the Etruscans, who then led to the Roman Empire, actually share the same DNA as the ancient Lydians. </seg>
<seg id="153"> And so, recently, scientists have suggested that Herodotus' crazy story is actually true. </seg>
<seg id="154"> And geologists have found evidence of a global cooling that lasted for nearly 20 years that could have explained the famine. </seg>
<seg id="155"> So, this crazy story might be true. </seg>
<seg id="156"> They might have actually saved their culture by playing games, escaping to games for 18 years, and then been so inspired, and knew so much about how to come together with games, that they actually saved the entire civilization that way. </seg>
<seg id="157"> Okay, we can do that. </seg>
<seg id="158"> We've been playing Warcraft since 1994. </seg>
<seg id="159"> That was the first real-time strategy game from the World of Warcraft series. That was 16 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="160"> They played dice games for 18 years, we've been playing Warcraft for 16 years. </seg>
<seg id="161"> I say we are ready for our own epic game. </seg>
<seg id="162"> Now, they had half the civilization go off in search of a new world, so that's where I get my 21 billion hours a week of game-play from. </seg>
<seg id="163"> Let's get half of us to agree to spend an hour a day playing games, until we solve real-world problems. </seg>
<seg id="164"> Now, I know you're asking, "How are we going to solve real world problems in games?" Well, that's what I have devoted my work to over the past few years, at The Institute For The Future. </seg>
<seg id="165"> We have this banner in our offices in Palo Alto, and it expresses our view of how we should try to relate to the future. </seg>
<seg id="166"> We do not want to try to predict the future. </seg>
<seg id="167"> What we want to do is make the future. </seg>
<seg id="168"> We want to imagine the best-case scenario outcome, and then we want to empower people to make that outcome a reality. </seg>
<seg id="169"> We want to imagine epic wins, and then give people the means to achieve the epic win. </seg>
<seg id="170"> I'm just going to very briefly show you three games that I've made that are an attempt to give people the means to create epic wins in their own futures. </seg>
<seg id="171"> So, this is World Without Oil. </seg>
<seg id="172"> We made this game in 2007. </seg>
<seg id="173"> This is an online game in which you try to survive an oil shortage. </seg>
<seg id="174"> The oil shortage is fictional, but we put enough online content out there for you to believe that it's real, and to live your real life as if we've run out of oil. So when you come to the game, you sign up, you tell us where you live, and then we give you real-time news, videos, data feeds that show you exactly how much oil costs, what's not available, how food supply is being affected, how transportation is being affected, if schools are closed, if there is rioting, and you have to figure out how you would live your real life as if this were true. And then we ask you to blog about it, to post videos, to post photos. </seg>
<seg id="175"> We piloted this game with 1,700 players in 2007, and we've tracked them for the three years since. </seg>
<seg id="176"> And I can tell you that this is a transformative experience. </seg>
<seg id="177"> Nobody wants to change how they live just because it's good for the world, or because we're supposed to. </seg>
<seg id="178"> But if you immerse them in an epic adventure and tell them, "We've run out of oil. </seg>
<seg id="179"> This is an amazing story and adventure for you to go on. </seg>
<seg id="180"> Challenge yourself to see how you would survive," most of our players have kept up the habits that they learned in this game. </seg>
<seg id="181"> So, for the next world-saving game, we decided to aim higher: bigger problem than just peak oil. </seg>
<seg id="182"> We did a game called Superstruct at The Institute For The Future. </seg>
<seg id="183"> And the premise was a supercomputer has calculated that humans have only 23 years left on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="184"> This supercomputer was called the Global Extinction Awareness System, of course. </seg>
<seg id="185"> We asked people to come online almost like a Jerry Bruckheimer movie. </seg>
<seg id="186"> You know Jerry Bruckheimer movies, you form a dream team -- you've got the astronaut, the scientist, the ex-convict, and they all have something to do to save the world. </seg>
<seg id="187"> But in our game, instead of just having five people on the dream team, we said, "Everybody's on the dream team, and it's your job to invent the future of energy, the future of food, the future of health, the future of security and the future of the social safety net." </seg>
<seg id="188"> We had 8,000 people play that game for eight weeks. </seg>
<seg id="189"> They came up with 500 insanely creative solutions that you can go online, if you Google "Superstruct," and see. </seg>
<seg id="190"> So, finally, the last game, we're launching it March 3rd. This is a game done with the World Bank Institute. </seg>
<seg id="191"> If you complete the game you will be certified by the World Bank Institute, as a Social Innovator, class of 2010. </seg>
<seg id="192"> Working with universities all over sub-Saharan Africa, and we are inviting them to learn social innovation skills. </seg>
<seg id="193"> We've got a graphic novel, we've got leveling up in skills like local insight, knowledge networking, sustainability, vision and resourcefulness. </seg>
<seg id="194"> I would like to invite all of you to please share this game with young people, anywhere in the world, particularly in developing areas, who might benefit from coming together to try to start to imagine their own social enterprises to save the world. </seg>
<seg id="195"> So, I'm going to wrap up now. </seg>
<seg id="196"> I want to ask a question. </seg>
<seg id="197"> What do you think happens next? </seg>
<seg id="198"> We've got all these amazing gamers, we've got these games that are kind of pilots of what we might do, but none of them have saved the real world yet. </seg>
<seg id="199"> Well I hope that you will agree with me that gamers are a human resource that we can use to do real-world work, that games are a powerful platform for change. </seg>
<seg id="200"> We have all these amazing superpowers: blissful productivity, the ability to weave a tight social fabric, this feeling of urgent optimism and the desire for epic meaning. </seg>
<seg id="201"> I really hope that we can come together to play games that matter, to survive on this planet for another century. </seg>
<seg id="202"> And that's my hope, that you will join me in making and playing games like this. </seg>
<seg id="203"> When I look forward to the next decade, I know two things for sure: that we can make any future we can imagine, and we can play any games we want. </seg>
<seg id="204"> So, I say: Let the world-changing games begin. </seg>
<seg id="205"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="769" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/aimee_mullins_the_opportunity_of_adversity.html</url>
<description>The thesaurus might equate "disabled" with synonyms like "useless" and "mutilated," but ground-breaking runner Aimee Mullins is out to redefine the word. Defying these associations, she shows how adversity -- in her case, being born without shinbones -- actually opens the door for human potential.</description>
<keywords>activism,happiness,health,heroism,prosthetics,social change,society</keywords>
<talkid>769</talkid>
<title>Aimee Mullins: The opportunity of adversity</title>
<seg id="1"> I'd like to share with you a discovery that I made a few months ago while writing an article for Italian Wired. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I always keep my thesaurus handy whenever I'm writing anything, but I'd already finished editing the piece, and I realized that I had never once in my life looked up the word "disabled" to see what I'd find. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Let me read you the entry. </seg>
<seg id="4"> "Disabled, adjective: crippled, helpless, useless, wrecked, stalled, maimed, wounded, mangled, lame, mutilated, run-down, worn-out, weakened, impotent, castrated, paralyzed, handicapped, senile, decrepit, laid-up, done-up, done-for, done-in cracked-up, counted-out; see also hurt, useless and weak. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Antonyms, healthy, strong, capable." </seg>
<seg id="6"> I was reading this list out loud to a friend and at first was laughing, it was so ludicrous, but I'd just gotten past "mangled," and my voice broke, and I had to stop and collect myself from the emotional shock and impact that the assault from these words unleashed. </seg>
<seg id="7"> You know, of course, this is my raggedy old thesaurus so I'm thinking this must be an ancient print date, right? </seg>
<seg id="8"> But, in fact, the print date was the early 1980s, when I would have been starting primary school and forming an understanding of myself outside the family unit and as related to the other kids and the world around me. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And, needless to say, thank God I wasn't using a thesaurus back then. </seg>
<seg id="10"> I mean, from this entry, it would seem that I was born into a world that perceived someone like me to have nothing positive whatsoever going for them, when in fact, today I'm celebrated for the opportunities and adventures my life has procured. </seg>
<seg id="11"> So, I immediately went to look up the 2009 online edition, expecting to find a revision worth noting. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Here's the updated version of this entry. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Unfortunately, it's not much better. </seg>
<seg id="14"> I find the last two words under "Near Antonyms," particularly unsettling: "whole" and "wholesome." </seg>
<seg id="15"> So, it's not just about the words. </seg>
<seg id="16"> It's what we believe about people when we name them with these words. </seg>
<seg id="17"> It's about the values behind the words, and how we construct those values. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Our language affects our thinking and how we view the world and how we view other people. </seg>
<seg id="19"> In fact, many ancient societies, including the Greeks and the Romans, believed that to utter a curse verbally was so powerful, because to say the thing out loud brought it into existence. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So, what reality do we want to call into existence: a person who is limited, or a person who's empowered? </seg>
<seg id="21"> By casually doing something as simple as naming a person, a child, we might be putting lids and casting shadows on their power. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Wouldn't we want to open doors for them instead? </seg>
<seg id="23"> One such person who opened doors for me was my childhood doctor at the A.I. duPont Institute in Wilmington, Delaware. </seg>
<seg id="24"> His name was Dr. Pizzutillo, an Italian American, whose name, apparently, was too difficult for most Americans to pronounce, so he went by Dr. P. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And Dr. P always wore really colorful bow ties and had the very perfect disposition to work with children. </seg>
<seg id="26"> I loved almost everything about my time spent at this hospital, with the exception of my physical therapy sessions. </seg>
<seg id="27"> I had to do what seemed like innumerable repetitions of exercises with these thick, elastic bands -- different colors, you know -- to help build up my leg muscles, and I hated these bands more than anything -- I hated them, had names for them. I hated them. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And, you know, I was already bargaining, as a five year-old child, with Dr. P to try to get out of doing these exercises, unsuccessfully, of course. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And, one day, he came in to my session -- exhaustive and unforgiving, these sessions -- and he said to me, "Wow. Aimee, you are such a strong and powerful little girl, I think you're going to break one of those bands. </seg>
<seg id="30"> When you do break it, I'm going to give you a hundred bucks." </seg>
<seg id="31"> Now, of course, this was a simple ploy on Dr. P's part to get me to do the exercises I didn't want to do before the prospect of being the richest five-year-old in the second floor ward, but what he effectively did for me was reshape an awful daily occurrence into a new and promising experience for me. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And I have to wonder today to what extent his vision and his declaration of me as a strong and powerful little girl shaped my own view of myself as an inherently strong, powerful and athletic person well into the future. </seg>
<seg id="33"> This is an example of how adults in positions of power can ignite the power of a child. </seg>
<seg id="34"> But, in the previous instances of those thesaurus entries, our language isn't allowing us to evolve into the reality that we would all want, the possibility of an individual to see themselves as capable. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Our language hasn't caught up with the changes in our society, many of which have been brought about by technology. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Certainly, from a medical standpoint, my legs, laser surgery for vision impairment, titanium knees and hip replacements for aging bodies that are allowing people to more fully engage with their abilities, and move beyond the limits that nature has imposed on them -- not to mention social networking platforms allow people to self-identify, to claim their own descriptions of themselves, so they can go align with global groups of their own choosing. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So, perhaps technology is revealing more clearly to us now what has always been a truth: that everyone has something rare and powerful to offer our society, and that the human ability to adapt is our greatest asset. </seg>
<seg id="38"> The human ability to adapt, it's an interesting thing, because people have continually wanted to talk to me about overcoming adversity, and I'm going to make an admission: This phrase never sat right with me, and I always felt uneasy trying to answer people's questions about it, and I think I'm starting to figure out why. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Implicit in this phrase of "overcoming adversity" is the idea that success, or happiness, is about emerging on the other side of a challenging experience unscathed or unmarked by the experience, as if my successes in life have come about from an ability to sidestep or circumnavigate the presumed pitfalls of a life with prosthetics, or what other people perceive as my disability. </seg>
<seg id="40"> But, in fact, we are changed. We are marked, of course, by a challenge, whether physically, emotionally or both. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And I'm going to suggest that this is a good thing. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Adversity isn't an obstacle that we need to get around in order to resume living our life. </seg>
<seg id="43"> It's part of our life. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And I tend to think of it like my shadow. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Sometimes I see a lot of it, sometimes there's very little, but it's always with me. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And, certainly, I'm not trying to diminish the impact, the weight, of a person's struggle. </seg>
<seg id="47"> There is adversity and challenge in life, and it's all very real and relative to every single person, but the question isn't whether or not you're going to meet adversity, but how you're going to meet it. </seg>
<seg id="48"> So, our responsibility is not simply shielding those we care for from adversity, but preparing them to meet it well. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And we do a disservice to our kids when we make them feel that they're not equipped to adapt. </seg>
<seg id="50"> There's an important difference and distinction between the objective medical fact of my being an amputee and the subjective societal opinion of whether or not I'm disabled. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And, truthfully, the only real and consistent disability I've had to confront is the world ever thinking that I could be described by those definitions. </seg>
<seg id="52"> In our desire to protect those we care about by giving them the cold, hard truth about their medical prognosis, or, indeed, a prognosis on the expected quality of their life, we have to make sure that we don't put the first brick in a wall that will actually disable someone. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Perhaps the existing model of only looking at what is broken in you and how do we fix it, serves to be more disabling to the individual than the pathology itself. </seg>
<seg id="54"> By not treating the wholeness of a person, by not acknowledging their potency, we are creating another ill on top of whatever natural struggle they might have. </seg>
<seg id="55"> We are effectively grading someone's worth to our community. </seg>
<seg id="56"> So we need to see through the pathology and into the range of human capability. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And, most importantly, there's a partnership between those perceived deficiencies and our greatest creative ability. </seg>
<seg id="58"> So it's not about devaluing, or negating, these more trying times as something we want to avoid or sweep under the rug, but instead to find those opportunities wrapped in the adversity. </seg>
<seg id="59"> So maybe the idea I want to put out there is not so much overcoming adversity as it is opening ourselves up to it, embracing it, grappling with it, to use a wrestling term, maybe even dancing with it. </seg>
<seg id="60"> And, perhaps, if we see adversity as natural, consistent and useful, we're less burdened by the presence of it. </seg>
<seg id="61"> This year we celebrate the 200th birthday of Charles Darwin, and it was 150 years ago, when writing about evolution, that Darwin illustrated, I think, a truth about the human character. </seg>
<seg id="62"> To paraphrase: It's not the strongest of the species that survives, nor is it the most intelligent that survives; it is the one that is most adaptable to change. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Conflict is the genesis of creation. </seg>
<seg id="64"> From Darwin's work, amongst others, we can recognize that the human ability to survive and flourish is driven by the struggle of the human spirit through conflict into transformation. </seg>
<seg id="65"> So, again, transformation, adaptation, is our greatest human skill. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And, perhaps, until we're tested, we don't know what we're made of. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Maybe that's what adversity gives us: a sense of self, a sense of our own power. </seg>
<seg id="68"> So, we can give ourselves a gift. </seg>
<seg id="69"> We can re-imagine adversity as something more than just tough times. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Maybe we can see it as change. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Adversity is just change that we haven't adapted ourselves to yet. </seg>
<seg id="72"> I think the greatest adversity that we've created for ourselves is this idea of normalcy. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Now, who's normal? </seg>
<seg id="74"> There's no normal. </seg>
<seg id="75"> There's common, there's typical. There's no normal, and would you want to meet that poor, beige person if they existed? </seg>
<seg id="76"> I don't think so. </seg>
<seg id="77"> If we can change this paradigm from one of achieving normalcy to one of possibility -- or potency, to be even a little bit more dangerous -- we can release the power of so many more children, and invite them to engage their rare and valuable abilities with the community. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Anthropologists tell us that the one thing we as humans have always required of our community members is to be of use, to be able to contribute. </seg>
<seg id="79"> There's evidence that Neanderthals, 60,000 years ago, carried their elderly and those with serious physical injury, and perhaps it's because the life experience of survival of these people proved of value to the community. </seg>
<seg id="80"> They didn't view these people as broken and useless; they were seen as rare and valuable. </seg>
<seg id="81"> A few years ago, I was in a food market in the town where I grew up in that red zone in northeastern Pennsylvania, and I was standing over a bushel of tomatoes. </seg>
<seg id="82"> It was summertime: I had shorts on. </seg>
<seg id="83"> I hear this guy, his voice behind me say, "Well, if it isn't Aimee Mullins." </seg>
<seg id="84"> And I turn around, and it's this older man. I have no idea who he is. </seg>
<seg id="85"> And I said, "I'm sorry, sir, have we met? I don't remember meeting you." </seg>
<seg id="86"> He said, "Well, you wouldn't remember meeting me. </seg>
<seg id="87"> I mean, when we met I was delivering you from your mother's womb." </seg>
<seg id="88"> Oh, that guy. </seg>
<seg id="89"> And, but of course, actually, it did click. </seg>
<seg id="90"> This man was Dr. Kean, a man that I had only known about through my mother's stories of that day, because, of course, typical fashion, I arrived late for my birthday by two weeks. </seg>
<seg id="91"> And so my mother's prenatal physician had gone on vacation, so the man who delivered me was a complete stranger to my parents. </seg>
<seg id="92"> And, because I was born without the fibula bones, and had feet turned in, and a few toes in this foot and a few toes in that, he had to be the bearer -- this stranger had to be the bearer of bad news. </seg>
<seg id="93"> He said to me, "I had to give this prognosis to your parents that you would never walk, and you would never have the kind of mobility that other kids have or any kind of life of independence, and you've been making liar out of me ever since." </seg>
<seg id="94"> The extraordinary thing is that he said he had saved newspaper clippings throughout my whole childhood, whether winning a second grade spelling bee, marching with the Girl Scouts, you know, the Halloween parade, winning my college scholarship, or any of my sports victories, and he was using it, and integrating it into teaching resident students, med students from Hahnemann Medical School and Hershey Medical School. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And he called this part of the course the X Factor, the potential of the human will. </seg>
<seg id="96"> No prognosis can account for how powerful this could be as a determinant in the quality of someone's life. </seg>
<seg id="97"> And Dr. Kean went on to tell me, he said, "In my experience, unless repeatedly told otherwise, and even if given a modicum of support, if left to their own devices, a child will achieve." </seg>
<seg id="98"> See, Dr. Kean made that shift in thinking. </seg>
<seg id="99"> He understood that there's a difference between the medical condition and what someone might do with it. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And there's been a shift in my thinking over time, in that, if you had asked me at 15 years old, if I would have traded prosthetics for flesh-and-bone legs, I wouldn't have hesitated for a second. </seg>
<seg id="101"> I aspired to that kind of normalcy back then. </seg>
<seg id="102"> But if you ask me today, I'm not so sure. </seg>
<seg id="103"> And it's because of the experiences I've had with them, not in spite of the experiences I've had with them. </seg>
<seg id="104"> And perhaps this shift in me has happened because I've been exposed to more people who have opened doors for me than those who have put lids and cast shadows on me. </seg>
<seg id="105"> See, all you really need is one person to show you the epiphany of your own power, and you're off. </seg>
<seg id="106"> If you can hand somebody the key to their own power -- the human spirit is so receptive -- if you can do that and open a door for someone at a crucial moment, you are educating them in the best sense. </seg>
<seg id="107"> You're teaching them to open doors for themselves. </seg>
<seg id="108"> In fact, the exact meaning of the word "educate" comes from the root word "educe." </seg>
<seg id="109"> It means "to bring forth what is within, to bring out potential." </seg>
<seg id="110"> So again, which potential do we want to bring out? </seg>
<seg id="111"> There was a case study done in 1960s Britain, when they were moving from grammar schools to comprehensive schools. </seg>
<seg id="112"> It's called the streaming trials. We call it "tracking" here in the States. </seg>
<seg id="113"> It's separating students from A, B, C, D and so on. </seg>
<seg id="114"> And the "A students" get the tougher curriculum, the best teachers, etc. </seg>
<seg id="115"> Well, they took, over a three-month period, D-level students, gave them A's, told them they were "A's," told them they were bright, and at the end of this three-month period, they were performing at A-level. </seg>
<seg id="116"> And, of course, the heartbreaking, flip side of this study, is that they took the "A students" and told them they were "D's." </seg>
<seg id="117"> And that's what happened at the end of that three-month period. </seg>
<seg id="118"> Those who were still around in school, besides the people who had dropped out. </seg>
<seg id="119"> A crucial part of this case study was that the teachers were duped too. </seg>
<seg id="120"> The teachers didn't know a switch had been made. </seg>
<seg id="121"> They were simply told, "These are the 'A-students,' these are the 'D-students.'" And that's how they went about teaching them and treating them. </seg>
<seg id="122"> So, I think that the only true disability is a crushed spirit, a spirit that's been crushed doesn't have hope, it doesn't see beauty, it no longer has our natural, childlike curiosity and our innate ability to imagine. </seg>
<seg id="123"> If instead, we can bolster a human spirit to keep hope, to see beauty in themselves and others, to be curious and imaginative, then we are truly using our power well. </seg>
<seg id="124"> When a spirit has those qualities, we are able to create new realities and new ways of being. </seg>
<seg id="125"> I'd like to leave you with a poem by a fourteenth-century Persian poet named Hafiz that my friend, Jacques Dembois told me about, and the poem is called "The God Who Only Knows Four Words": "Every child has known God, not the God of names, not the God of don'ts, but the God who only knows four words and keeps repeating them, saying, 'Come dance with me. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Come, dance with me. Come, dance with me.'" Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
</refset>
</mteval>
