<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<refset setid="iwslt2014-tst2011" srclang="german" trglang="english" refid="ref">
<doc docid="1131" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/harvey_fineberg_are_we_ready_for_neo_evolution.html</url>
<description>Medical ethicist Harvey Fineberg shows us three paths forward for the ever-evolving human species: to stop evolving completely, to evolve naturally -- or to control the next steps of human evolution, using genetic modification, to make ourselves smarter, faster, better. Neo-evolution is within our grasp. What will we do with it?</description>
<keywords>evolution,medicine,philosophy,science,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1131</talkid>
<title>Harvey Fineberg: Are we ready for neo-evolution?</title>
<seg id="1"> How would you like to be better than you are? </seg>
<seg id="2"> Suppose I said that, with just a few changes in your genes, you could get a better memory -- more precise, more accurate and quicker. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Or maybe you'd like to be more fit, stronger, with more stamina. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Would you like to be more attractive and self-confident? </seg>
<seg id="5"> How about living longer with good health? </seg>
<seg id="6"> Or perhaps you're one of those who's always yearned for more creativity. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Which one would you like the most? </seg>
<seg id="8"> Which would you like, if you could have just one? </seg>
<seg id="9"> Creativity. </seg>
<seg id="10"> How many people would choose creativity? </seg>
<seg id="11"> Raise your hands. Let me see. </seg>
<seg id="12"> A few. Probably about as many as there are creative people here. </seg>
<seg id="13"> That's very good. </seg>
<seg id="14"> How many would opt for memory? </seg>
<seg id="15"> Quite a few more. </seg>
<seg id="16"> How about fitness? </seg>
<seg id="17"> A few less. </seg>
<seg id="18"> What about longevity? </seg>
<seg id="19"> Ah, the majority. That makes me feel very good as a doctor. </seg>
<seg id="20"> If you could have any one of these, it would be a very different world. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Is it just imaginary? </seg>
<seg id="22"> Or, is it, perhaps, possible? </seg>
<seg id="23"> Evolution has been a perennial topic here at the TED Conference, but I want to give you today one doctor's take on the subject. </seg>
<seg id="24"> The great 20th-century geneticist, T.G. Dobzhansky, who was also a communicant in the Russian Orthodox Church, once wrote an essay that he titled "Nothing in Biology Makes Sense Except in the Light of Evolution." </seg>
<seg id="25"> Now if you are one of those who does not accept the evidence for biological evolution, this would be a very good time to turn off your hearing aid, take out your personal communications device -- I give you permission -- and perhaps take another look at Kathryn Schultz's book on being wrong, because nothing in the rest of this talk is going to make any sense whatsoever to you. </seg>
<seg id="26"> But if you do accept biological evolution, consider this: is it just about the past, or is it about the future? </seg>
<seg id="27"> Does it apply to others, or does it apply to us? </seg>
<seg id="28"> This is another look at the tree of life. </seg>
<seg id="29"> In this picture, I've put a bush with a center branching out in all directions, because if you look at the edges of the tree of life, every existing species at the tips of those branches has succeeded in evolutionary terms: it has survived; it has demonstrated a fitness to its environment. </seg>
<seg id="30"> The human part of this branch, way out on one end, is, of course, the one that we are most interested in. </seg>
<seg id="31"> We branch off of a common ancestor to modern chimpanzees about six or eight million years ago. </seg>
<seg id="32"> In the interval, there have been perhaps 20 or 25 different species of hominids. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Some have come and gone. </seg>
<seg id="34"> We have been here for about 130,000 years. </seg>
<seg id="35"> It may seem like we're quite remote from other parts of this tree of life, but actually, for the most part, the basic machinery of our cells is pretty much the same. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Do you realize that we can take advantage and commandeer the machinery of a common bacterium to produce the protein of human insulin used to treat diabetics? </seg>
<seg id="37"> This is not like human insulin; this is the same protein that is chemically indistinguishable from what comes out of your pancreas. </seg>
<seg id="38"> And speaking of bacteria, do you realize that each of us carries in our gut more bacteria than there are cells in the rest of our body? </seg>
<seg id="39"> Maybe 10 times more. </seg>
<seg id="40"> I mean think of it, when Antonio Damasio asks about your self-image, do you think about the bacteria? </seg>
<seg id="41"> Our gut is a wonderfully hospitable environment for those bacteria. </seg>
<seg id="42"> It's warm, it's dark, it's moist, it's very cozy. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And you're going to provide all the nutrition that they could possibly want with no effort on their part. </seg>
<seg id="44"> It's really like an Easy Street for bacteria, with the occasional interruption of the unintended forced rush to the exit. </seg>
<seg id="45"> But otherwise, you are a wonderful environment for those bacteria, just as they are essential to your life. </seg>
<seg id="46"> They help in the digestion of essential nutrients, and they protect you against certain diseases. </seg>
<seg id="47"> But what will come in the future? </seg>
<seg id="48"> Are we at some kind of evolutionary equipoise as a species? </seg>
<seg id="49"> Or, are we destined to become something different -- something, perhaps, even better adapted to the environment? </seg>
<seg id="50"> Now let's take a step back in time to the Big Bang, 14 billion years ago -- the Earth, the solar system, about four and a half billion years -- the first signs of proto-life, maybe three to four billion years ago on Earth -- the first multi-celled organisms, perhaps as much as 800 or a billion years ago -- and then the human species, finally emerging in the last 130,000 years. </seg>
<seg id="51"> In this vast unfinished symphony of the universe, life on Earth is like a brief measure; the animal kingdom, like a single measure; and human life, a small grace note. </seg>
<seg id="52"> That was us. </seg>
<seg id="53"> That also constitutes the entertainment portion of this talk, so I hope you enjoyed it. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Now when I was a freshman in college, I took my first biology class. </seg>
<seg id="55"> I was fascinated by the elegance and beauty of biology. </seg>
<seg id="56"> I became enamored of the power of evolution, and I realized something very fundamental: in most of the existence of life in single-celled organisms, each cell simply divides, and all of the genetic energy of that cell is carried on in both daughter cells. </seg>
<seg id="57"> But at the time multi-celled organisms come online, things start to change. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Sexual reproduction enters the picture. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And very importantly, with the introduction of sexual reproduction that passes on the genome, the rest of the body becomes expendable. </seg>
<seg id="60"> In fact, you could say that the inevitability of the death of our bodies enters in evolutionary time at the same moment as sexual reproduction. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Now I have to confess, when I was a college undergraduate, I thought, okay, sex/death, sex/death, death for sex -- it seemed pretty reasonable at the time, but with each passing year, I've come to have increasing doubts. </seg>
<seg id="62"> I've come to understand the sentiments of George Burns, who was performing still in Las Vegas well into his 90s. </seg>
<seg id="63"> And one night, there's a knock at his hotel room door. </seg>
<seg id="64"> He answers the door. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Standing before him is a gorgeous, scantily clad showgirl. </seg>
<seg id="66"> She looks at him and says, "I'm here for super sex." </seg>
<seg id="67"> "That's fine," says George, "I'll take the soup." </seg>
<seg id="68"> I came to realize, as a physician, that I was working toward a goal which was different from the goal of evolution -- not necessarily contradictory, just different. </seg>
<seg id="69"> I was trying to preserve the body. </seg>
<seg id="70"> I wanted to keep us healthy. </seg>
<seg id="71"> I wanted to restore health from disease. </seg>
<seg id="72"> I wanted us to live long and healthy lives. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Evolution is all about passing on the genome to the next generation, adapting and surviving through generation after generation. </seg>
<seg id="74"> From an evolutionary point of view, you and I are like the booster rockets designed to send the genetic payload into the next level of orbit and then drop off into the sea. </seg>
<seg id="75"> I think we would all understand the sentiment that Woody Allen expressed when he said, "I don't want to achieve immortality through my work. </seg>
<seg id="76"> I want to achieve it through not dying." </seg>
<seg id="77"> Evolution does not necessarily favor the longest-lived. </seg>
<seg id="78"> It doesn't necessarily favor the biggest or the strongest or the fastest, and not even the smartest. </seg>
<seg id="79"> Evolution favors those creatures best adapted to their environment. </seg>
<seg id="80"> That is the sole test of survival and success. </seg>
<seg id="81"> At the bottom of the ocean, bacteria that are thermophilic and can survive at the steam vent heat that would otherwise produce, if fish were there, sous-vide cooked fish, nevertheless, have managed to make that a hospitable environment for them. </seg>
<seg id="82"> So what does this mean, as we look back at what has happened in evolution, and as we think about the place again of humans in evolution, and particularly as we look ahead to the next phase, I would say that there are a number of possibilities. </seg>
<seg id="83"> The first is that we will not evolve. </seg>
<seg id="84"> We have reached a kind of equipoise. </seg>
<seg id="85"> And the reasoning behind that would be, first, we have, through medicine, managed to preserve a lot of genes that would otherwise be selected out and be removed from the population. </seg>
<seg id="86"> And secondly, we as a species have so configured our environment that we have managed to make it adapt to us as well as we adapt to it. </seg>
<seg id="87"> And by the way, we immigrate and circulate and intermix so much that you can't any longer have the isolation that is necessary for evolution to take place. </seg>
<seg id="88"> A second possibility is that there will be evolution of the traditional kind, natural, imposed by the forces of nature. </seg>
<seg id="89"> And the argument here would be that the wheels of evolution grind slowly, but they are inexorable. </seg>
<seg id="90"> And as far as isolation goes, when we as a species do colonize distant planets, there will be the isolation and the environmental changes that could produce evolution in the natural way. </seg>
<seg id="91"> But there's a third possibility, an enticing, intriguing and frightening possibility. </seg>
<seg id="92"> I call it neo-evolution -- the new evolution that is not simply natural, but guided and chosen by us as individuals in the choices that we will make. </seg>
<seg id="93"> Now how could this come about? </seg>
<seg id="94"> How could it be possible that we would do this? </seg>
<seg id="95"> Consider, first, the reality that people today, in some cultures, are making choices about their offspring. </seg>
<seg id="96"> They're, in some cultures, choosing to have more males than females. </seg>
<seg id="97"> It's not necessarily good for the society, but it's what the individual and the family are choosing. </seg>
<seg id="98"> Think also, if it were possible ever for you to choose, not simply to choose the sex of your child, but for you in your body to make the genetic adjustments that would cure or prevent diseases. </seg>
<seg id="99"> What if you could make the genetic changes to eliminate diabetes or Alzheimer's or reduce the risk of cancer or eliminate stroke? </seg>
<seg id="100"> Wouldn't you want to make those changes in your genes? </seg>
<seg id="101"> If we look ahead, these kind of changes are going to be increasingly possible. </seg>
<seg id="102"> The Human Genome Project started in 1990, and it took 13 years. </seg>
<seg id="103"> It cost 2.7 billion dollars. </seg>
<seg id="104"> The year after it was finished in 2004, you could do the same job for 20 million dollars in three to four months. </seg>
<seg id="105"> Today, you can have a complete sequence of the three billion base pairs in the human genome at a cost of about 20,000 dollars and in the space of about a week. </seg>
<seg id="106"> It won't be very long before the reality will be the 1,000-dollar human genome, and it will be increasingly available for everyone. </seg>
<seg id="107"> Just a week ago, the National Academy of Engineering awarded its Draper Prize to Francis Arnold and Willem Stemmer, two scientists who independently developed techniques to encourage the natural process of evolution to work faster and to lead to desirable proteins in a more efficient way -- what Frances Arnold calls "directed evolution." </seg>
<seg id="108"> A couple of years ago, the Lasker Prize was awarded to the scientist Shinya Yamanaka for his research in which he took an adult skin cell, a fibroblast, and by manipulating just four genes, he induced that cell to revert to a pluripotential stem cell -- a cell potentially capable of becoming any cell in your body. </seg>
<seg id="109"> These changes are coming. </seg>
<seg id="110"> The same technology that has produced the human insulin in bacteria can make viruses that will not only protect you against themselves, but induce immunity against other viruses. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Believe it or not, there's an experimental trial going on with vaccine against influenza that has been grown in the cells of a tobacco plant. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Can you imagine something good coming out of tobacco? </seg>
<seg id="113"> These are all reality today, and [in] the future, will be evermore possible. </seg>
<seg id="114"> Imagine then just two other little changes. </seg>
<seg id="115"> You can change the cells in your body, but what if you could change the cells in your offspring? </seg>
<seg id="116"> What if you could change the sperm and the ova, or change the newly fertilized egg, and give your offspring a better chance at a healthier life -- eliminate the diabetes, eliminate the hemophilia, reduce the risk of cancer? </seg>
<seg id="117"> Who doesn't want healthier children? </seg>
<seg id="118"> And then, that same analytic technology, that same engine of science that can produce the changes to prevent disease, will also enable us to adopt super-attributes, hyper-capacities -- that better memory. </seg>
<seg id="119"> Why not have the quick wit of a Ken Jennings, especially if you can augment it with the next generation of the Watson machine? </seg>
<seg id="120"> Why not have the quick twitch muscle that will enable you to run faster and longer? </seg>
<seg id="121"> Why not live longer? </seg>
<seg id="122"> These will be irresistible. </seg>
<seg id="123"> And when we are at a position where we can pass it on to the next generation, and we can adopt the attributes we want, we will have converted old-style evolution into neo-evolution. </seg>
<seg id="124"> We'll take a process that normally might require 100,000 years, and we can compress it down to a thousand years -- and maybe even in the next 100 years. </seg>
<seg id="125"> These are choices that your grandchildren, or their grandchildren, are going to have before them. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Will we use these choices to make a society that is better, that is more successful, that is kinder? </seg>
<seg id="127"> Or, will we selectively choose different attributes that we want for some of us and not for others of us? </seg>
<seg id="128"> Will we make a society that is more boring and more uniform, or more robust and more versatile? </seg>
<seg id="129"> These are the kinds of questions that we will have to face. </seg>
<seg id="130"> And most profoundly of all, will we ever be able to develop the wisdom, and to inherit the wisdom, that we'll need to make these choices wisely? </seg>
<seg id="131"> For better or worse, and sooner than you may think, these choices will be up to us. </seg>
<seg id="132"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1104" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/eythor_bender_demos_human_exoskeletons.html</url>
<description>Eythor Bender of Berkeley Bionics brings onstage two amazing exoskeletons, HULC and eLEGS -- robotic add-ons that could one day allow a human to carry 200 pounds without tiring, or allow a wheelchair user to stand and walk. It's a powerful onstage demo, with implications for human potential of all kinds.</description>
<keywords>design,science,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1104</talkid>
<title> Human exoskeletons -- for war and healing</title>
<seg id="1"> I want you now to imagine a wearable robot that gives you superhuman abilities, or another one that takes wheelchair users up standing and walking again. </seg>
<seg id="2"> We at Berkeley Bionics call these robots exoskeletons. </seg>
<seg id="3"> These are nothing else than something that you put on in the morning, and it will give you extra strength, and it will further enhance your speed, and it will help you, for instance, to manage your balance. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It is actually the true integration of the man and the machine. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But not only that -- it will integrate and network you to the universe and other devices out there. </seg>
<seg id="6"> This is just not some blue sky thinking. </seg>
<seg id="7"> To show you now what we are working on by starting out talking about the American soldier, that on average does carry about 100 lbs. on their backs, and they are being asked to carry more equipment. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Obviously, this is resulting in some major complications -- back injuries, 30 percent of them -- chronic back injuries. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So we thought we would look at this challenge and create an exoskeleton that would help deal with this issue. </seg>
<seg id="10"> So let me now introduce to you HULC -- or the Human Universal Load Carrier. </seg>
<seg id="11"> With the HULC exoskeleton, I can carry 200 lbs. over varied terrain for many hours. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Its flexible design allows for deep squats, crawls and high-agility movements. </seg>
<seg id="13"> It senses what I want to do, where I want to go, and then augments my strength and endurance. </seg>
<seg id="14"> We are ready with our industry partner to introduce this device, this new exoskeleton this year. </seg>
<seg id="15"> So this is for real. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Now let's turn our heads towards the wheelchair users, something that I'm particularly passionate about. </seg>
<seg id="17"> There are 68 million people estimated to be in wheelchairs worldwide. </seg>
<seg id="18"> This is about one percent of the total population. </seg>
<seg id="19"> And that's actually a conservative estimate. </seg>
<seg id="20"> We are talking here about, oftentimes, very young individuals with spinal cord injuries, that in the prime of their life -- 20s, 30s, 40s -- hit a wall and the wheelchair's the only option. </seg>
<seg id="21"> But it is also the aging population that is multiplying in numbers. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And the only option, pretty much -- when it's stroke or other complications -- is the wheelchair. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And that is actually for the last 500 years, since its very successful introduction, I must say. </seg>
<seg id="24"> So we thought we would start writing a brand new chapter of mobility. </seg>
<seg id="25"> Let me now introduce you to eLEGS that is worn by Amanda Boxtel that 19 years ago was spinal cord injured, and as a result of that she has not been able to walk for 19 years until now. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Amanda is wearing our eLEGS set. </seg>
<seg id="28"> It has sensors. </seg>
<seg id="29"> It's completely non-invasive, sensors in the crutches that send signals back to our onboard computer that is sitting here at her back. </seg>
<seg id="30"> There are battery packs here as well that power motors that are sitting at her hips, as well as her knee joints, that move her forward in this kind of smooth and very natural gait. </seg>
<seg id="31"> I was 24 years old and at the top of my game when a freak summersault while downhill skiing paralyzed me. </seg>
<seg id="32"> In a split second, I lost all sensation and movement below my pelvis. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Not long afterwards, a doctor strode into my hospital room, and he said, "Amanda, you'll never walk again." </seg>
<seg id="34"> And that was 19 yeas ago. </seg>
<seg id="35"> He robbed every ounce of hope from my being. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Adaptive technology has since enabled me to learn how to downhill ski again, to rock climb and even handcycle. </seg>
<seg id="37"> But nothing has been invented that enables me to walk, until now. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="39"> As you can see, we have the technology, we have the platforms to sit down and have discussions with you. </seg>
<seg id="40"> It's in our hands, and we have all the potential here to change the lives of future generations -- not only for the soldiers, or for Amanda here and all the wheelchair users, but for everyone. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Thanks. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1096" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/mark_bezos_a_life_lesson_from_a_volunteer_firefighter.html</url>
<description>Volunteer firefighter Mark Bezos tells a story of an act of heroism that didn't go quite as expected -- but that taught him a big lesson: Don't wait to be a hero.</description>
<keywords>community,compassion,culture</keywords>
<talkid>1096</talkid>
<title> A life lesson from a volunteer firefighter</title>
<seg id="1"> Back in New York, I am the head of development for a non-profit called Robin Hood. </seg>
<seg id="2"> When I'm not fighting poverty, I'm fighting fires as the assistant captain of a volunteer fire company. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now in our town, where the volunteers supplement a highly skilled career staff, you have to get to the fire scene pretty early to get in on any action. </seg>
<seg id="4"> I remember my first fire. </seg>
<seg id="5"> I was the second volunteer on the scene, so there was a pretty good chance I was going to get in. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But still it was a real footrace against the other volunteers to get to the captain in charge to find out what our assignments would be. </seg>
<seg id="7"> When I found the captain, he was having a very engaging conversation with the homeowner, who was surely having one of the worst days of her life. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Here it was, the middle of the night, she was standing outside in the pouring rain, under an umbrella, in her pajamas, barefoot, while her house was in flames. </seg>
<seg id="9"> The other volunteer who had arrived just before me -- let's call him Lex Luther -- got to the captain first and was asked to go inside and save the homeowner's dog. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The dog! I was stunned with jealousy. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Here was some lawyer or money manager who, for the rest of his life, gets to tell people that he went into a burning building to save a living creature, just because he beat me by five seconds. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Well, I was next. </seg>
<seg id="13"> The captain waved me over. </seg>
<seg id="14"> He said, "Bezos, I need you to go into the house. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I need you to go upstairs, past the fire, and I need you to get this woman a pair of shoes." </seg>
<seg id="16"> I swear. </seg>
<seg id="17"> So, not exactly what I was hoping for, but off I went -- up the stairs, down the hall, past the 'real' firefighters, who were pretty much done putting out the fire at this point, into the master bedroom to get a pair of shoes. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Now I know what you're thinking, but I'm no hero. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I carried my payload back downstairs where I met my nemesis and the precious dog by the front door. </seg>
<seg id="20"> We took our treasures outside to the homeowner, where, not surprisingly, his received much more attention than did mine. </seg>
<seg id="21"> A few weeks later, the department received a letter from the homeowner thanking us for the valiant effort displayed in saving her home. </seg>
<seg id="22"> The act of kindness she noted above all others: someone had even gotten her a pair of shoes. </seg>
<seg id="23"> In both my vocation at Robin Hood and my avocation as a volunteer firefighter, I am witness to acts of generosity and kindness on a monumental scale, but I'm also witness to acts of grace and courage on an individual basis. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And you know what I've learned? </seg>
<seg id="25"> They all matter. </seg>
<seg id="26"> So as I look around this room at people who either have achieved, or are on their way to achieving, remarkable levels of success, I would offer this reminder: don't wait. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Don't wait until you make your first million to make a difference in somebody's life. </seg>
<seg id="28"> If you have something to give, give it now. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Serve food at a soup kitchen. Clean up a neighborhood park. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Be a mentor. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Not every day is going to offer us a chance to save somebody's life, but every day offers us an opportunity to affect one. </seg>
<seg id="32"> So get in the game. Save the shoes. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Mark, Mark, come back. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1102" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/isabel_behncke_evolution_s_gift_of_play_from_bonobo_apes_to_humans.html</url>
<description>With never-before-seen video, primatologist Isabel Behncke Izquierdo shows how bonobo ape society learns from constantly playing -- solo, with friends, even as a prelude to sex. Indeed, play appears to be the bonobos' key to problem-solving and avoiding conflict. If it works for our close cousins, why not for us?</description>
<keywords>TED Fellows,animals,culture,play,science</keywords>
<talkid>1102</talkid>
<title>Isabel Behncke: Evolution's gift of play, from bonobo apes to humans</title>
<seg id="1"> I just came back from a community that holds the secret to human survival. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It's a place where women run the show, have sex to say hello, and play rules the day -- where fun is serious business. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And no, this isn't Burning Man or San Francisco. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Ladies and gentlemen, meet your cousins. </seg>
<seg id="5"> This is the world of wild bonobos in the jungles of Congo. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Bonobos are, together with chimpanzees, your living closest relative. </seg>
<seg id="7"> That means we all share a common ancestor, an evolutionary grandmother, who lived around six million years ago. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Now, chimpanzees are well-known for their aggression. </seg>
<seg id="9"> But unfortunately, we have made too much of an emphasis of this aspect in our narratives of human evolution. </seg>
<seg id="10"> But bonobos show us the other side of the coin. </seg>
<seg id="11"> While chimpanzees are dominated by big, scary guys, bonobo society is run by empowered females. </seg>
<seg id="12"> These guys have really worked something out, since this leads to a highly tolerant society where fatal violence has not been observed yet. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But unfortunately, bonobos are the least understood of the great apes. </seg>
<seg id="14"> They live in the depths of the Congolese jungle, and it has been very difficult to study them. </seg>
<seg id="15"> The Congo is a paradox -- a land of extraordinary biodiversity and beauty, but also the heart of darkness itself -- the scene of a violent conflict that has raged for decades and claimed nearly as many lives as the First World War. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Not surprisingly, this destruction also endangers bonobo survival. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Bushmeat trades and forest loss means we couldn't fill a small stadium with all the bonobos that are left in the world -- and we're not even sure of that to be honest. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Yet, in this land of violence and chaos, you can hear hidden laughter swaying the trees. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Who are these cousins? </seg>
<seg id="20"> We know them as the "make love, not war" apes since they have frequent, promiscuous and bisexual sex to manage conflict and solve social issues. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Now, I'm not saying this is the solution to all of humanity's problems -- since there's more to bonobo life than the Kama Sutra. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Bonobos, like humans, love to play throughout their entire lives. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Play is not just child's games. </seg>
<seg id="24"> For us and them, play is foundational for bonding relationships and fostering tolerance. </seg>
<seg id="25"> It's where we learn to trust and where we learn about the rules of the game. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Play increases creativity and resilience, and it's all about the generation of diversity -- diversity of interactions, diversity of behaviors, diversity of connections. </seg>
<seg id="27"> And when you watch bonobo play, you're seeing the very evolutionary roots of human laughter, dance and ritual. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Play is the glue that binds us together. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Now, I don't know how you play, but I want to show you a couple of unique clips fresh from the wild. </seg>
<seg id="30"> First, it's a ball game bonobo-style -- and I do not mean football. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So here, we have a young female and a male engaged in a chase game. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Have a look what she's doing. </seg>
<seg id="33"> It might be the evolutionary origin of the phrase, "she's got him by the balls." </seg>
<seg id="34"> Only I think that he's rather loving it here, right? </seg>
<seg id="35"> Yeah. </seg>
<seg id="36"> So sex play is common in both bonobos and humans. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And this video is really interesting because it shows -- this video's really interesting because it shows the inventiveness of bringing unusual elements into play -- such as testicles -- and also how play both requires trust and fosters trust -- while at the same time being tremendous fun. </seg>
<seg id="38"> But play's a shapeshifter. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Play's a shapeshifter, and it can take many forms, some of which are more quiet, imaginative, curious -- maybe where wonder is discovered anew. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And I want you to see, this is Fuku, a young female, and she is quietly playing with water. </seg>
<seg id="41"> I think, like her, we sometimes play alone, and we explore the boundaries of our inner and our outer worlds. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And it's that playful curiosity that drives us to explore, drives us to interact, and then the unexpected connections we form are the real hotbed for creativity. </seg>
<seg id="43"> So these are just small tasters into the insights that bonobo give us to our past and present. </seg>
<seg id="44"> But they also hold a secret for our future, a future where we need to adapt to an increasingly challenging world through greater creativity and greater cooperation. </seg>
<seg id="45"> The secret is that play is the key to these capacities. </seg>
<seg id="46"> In other words, play is our adaptive wildcard. </seg>
<seg id="47"> In order to adapt successfully to a changing world, we need to play. </seg>
<seg id="48"> But will we make the most of our playfulness? </seg>
<seg id="49"> Play is not frivolous. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Play's essential. </seg>
<seg id="51"> For bonobos and humans alike, life is not just red in tooth and claw. </seg>
<seg id="52"> In times when it seems least appropriate to play, it might be the times when it is most urgent. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And so, my fellow primates, let us embrace this gift from evolution and play together, as we rediscover creativity, fellowship and wonder. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1166" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/alice_dreger_is_anatomy_destiny.html</url>
<description>Alice Dreger works with people at the edge of anatomy, such as conjoined twins and intersexed people. In her observation, it's often a fuzzy line between male and female, among other anatomical distinctions. Which brings up a huge question: Why do we let our anatomy determine our fate? &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
<keywords>culture,gender,politics</keywords>
<talkid>1166</talkid>
<title>Alice Dreger: Is anatomy destiny?</title>
<seg id="1"> I want you to imagine two couples in the middle of 1979 on the exact same day, at the exact same moment, each conceiving a baby -- okay? </seg>
<seg id="2"> So two couples each conceiving one baby. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now I don't want you to spend too much time imagining the conception, because if you spend all that time imagining that conception, you're not going to listen to me. </seg>
<seg id="4"> So just imagine that for a moment. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And in this scenario, I want to imagine that, in one case, the sperm is carrying a Y chromosome, meeting that X chromosome of the egg. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And in the other case, the sperm is carrying an X chromosome, meeting the X chromosome of the egg. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Both are viable; both take off. </seg>
<seg id="8"> We'll come back to these people later. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So I wear two hats in most of what I do. </seg>
<seg id="10"> As the one hat, I do history of anatomy. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I'm a historian by training, and what I study in that case is the way that people have dealt with anatomy -- meaning human bodies, animal bodies -- how they dealt with bodily fluids, concepts of bodies; how have they thought about bodies. </seg>
<seg id="12"> The other hat that I've worn in my work is as an activist, as a patient advocate -- or, as I sometimes say, as an impatient advocate -- for people who are patients of doctors. </seg>
<seg id="13"> In that case, what I've worked with is people who have body types that challenge social norms. </seg>
<seg id="14"> So some of what I've worked on, for example, is people who are conjoined twins -- two people within one body. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Some of what I've worked on is people who have dwarfism -- so people who are much shorter than typical. </seg>
<seg id="16"> And a lot of what I've worked on is people who have atypical sex -- so people who don't have the standard male or the standard female body types. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And as a general term, we can use the term intersex for this. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Intersex comes in a lot of different forms. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I'll just give you a few examples of the types of ways you can have sex that isn't standard for male or female. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So in one instance, you can have somebody who has an XY chromosomal basis, and that SRY gene on the Y chromosome tells the proto-gonads, which we all have in the fetal life, to become testes. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And so in the fetal life the testes are pumping out testosterone. </seg>
<seg id="22"> But because this individual lacks receptors to hear that testosterone, the body doesn't react to the testosterone. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And this is a syndrome called androgen insensitivity syndrome. </seg>
<seg id="24"> So lots of levels of testosterone, but no reaction to it. </seg>
<seg id="25"> As a consequence, the body develops more along the female typical path. </seg>
<seg id="26"> When the child is born, she looks like a girl. </seg>
<seg id="27"> She is a girl. She is raised as a girl. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And it's often not until she hits puberty and she's growing and developing breasts, but she's not getting her period, that somebody figures out something's up here. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And they do some tests and figure out that, instead of having ovaries inside and a uterus, she actually has testes inside, and she has a Y chromosome. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Now what's important to understand is you may think of this person as really being male, but they're really not. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Females, like males, have in our bodies something called the adrenal glands. </seg>
<seg id="32"> They're in the back of our body. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And the adrenal glands make androgens, which are a masculinizing hormone. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Most females like me -- I believe myself to be a typical female -- I don't actually know my chromosomal make-up but I think I'm probably typical -- most females like me are actually androgen-sensitive. </seg>
<seg id="35"> We're making androgen, and we're responding to androgens. </seg>
<seg id="36"> The consequence is that somebody like me has actually had a brain exposed to more androgens than the woman born with testes who has androgen insensitivity syndrome. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So sex is really complicated; it's not just that intersex people are in the middle of all the sex spectrum -- in some ways, they can be all over the place. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Another example: a few years ago I got a call from a man who was 19 years old, who was born a boy, raised a boy, had a girlfriend, had sex with his girlfriend, had a life as a guy and had just found out that he had ovaries and a uterus inside. </seg>
<seg id="39"> What he had was an extreme form of a condition called congenital adrenal hyperplasia. </seg>
<seg id="40"> He had XX chromosomes, and in the womb, his adrenal glands were in such high gear that it created, essentially, a masculine hormonal environment. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And as a consequence, his genitals were masculinzed, his brain was subject to the more typical masculine component of hormones. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And he was born looking like a boy -- nobody suspected anything. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And it was only when he had reached the age of 19 that he began to have enough medical problems actually from menstruating internally, that doctors figured out that, in fact, he was female internally. </seg>
<seg id="44"> Okay, so just one more quick example of a way you can have intersex. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Some people who have XX chromosomes develop what are called ovotestis, which is when you have ovarian tissue with testicular tissue wrapped around it. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And we're not exactly sure why that happens. </seg>
<seg id="47"> So sex can come in lots of different varieties. </seg>
<seg id="48"> The reason that children with these kinds of bodies -- whether it's dwarfism, or it's conjoined twinning, or it's an intersex type -- are often normalized by surgeons is not because it actually leaves them better off in terms of physical health. </seg>
<seg id="49"> In many cases, people are actually perfectly healthy. </seg>
<seg id="50"> The reason they're often subject to various kinds of surgeries is because they threaten our social categories. </seg>
<seg id="51"> Or system has been based typically on the idea that a particular kind of anatomy comes with a particular identity. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So we have the concept that what it means to be a woman is to have a female identity; what it means to be a black person is, allegedly, is to have an African anatomy in terms of your history. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And so we have this terribly simplistic idea. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And when we're faced with a body that actually presents us something quite different, it startles us in terms of those categorizations. </seg>
<seg id="55"> So we have a lot of very romantic ideas in our culture about individualism. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And our nation's really founded on a very romantic concept of individualism. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Well you can imagine how startling then it is when you have children that are born who are two people inside of one body. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Where I ran into the most heat from this most recently was last year the South African runner, Caster Semenya, had her sex called into question at the International Games in Berlin. </seg>
<seg id="59"> I had a lot of journalists calling me, asking me, "Which is the test they're going to run that will tell us whether or not Caster Semenya is male or female?" </seg>
<seg id="60"> And I had to explain to the journalists there isn't such a test. </seg>
<seg id="61"> In fact, we now know that sex is complicated enough that we have to admit nature doesn't draw the line for us between male and female, or between male and intersex and female and intersex; we actually draw that line on nature. </seg>
<seg id="62"> So what we have is a sort of situation where the farther our science goes, the more we have to admit to ourselves that these categories that we thought of as stable anatomical categories that mapped very simply to stable identity categories are a lot more fuzzy than we thought. </seg>
<seg id="63"> And it's not just in terms of sex. </seg>
<seg id="64"> It's also in terms of race, which turns out to be vastly more complicated than our terminology has allowed. </seg>
<seg id="65"> As we look, we get into all sorts of uncomfortable areas. </seg>
<seg id="66"> We look, for example, about the fact that we share at least 95 percent of our DNA with chimpanzees. </seg>
<seg id="67"> What are we to make of the fact that we differ from them only really by a few nucleotides? </seg>
<seg id="68"> And as we get farther and farther with our science, we get more and more into a discomforted zone where we have to acknowledge that the simplistic categories we've had are probably overly simplistic. </seg>
<seg id="69"> So we're seeing this in all sorts of places in human life. </seg>
<seg id="70"> One of the places we're seeing it, for example, in our culture today, in the United States today, is battles over the beginning of life and the end of life. </seg>
<seg id="71"> We have difficult conversations about at what point we decide a body becomes a human, such that it has a different right than a fetal life. </seg>
<seg id="72"> We have very difficult conversations nowadays -- probably not out in the open as much as within medicine -- about the question of when somebody's dead. </seg>
<seg id="73"> In the past, our ancestors never had to struggle so much with this question of when somebody was dead. </seg>
<seg id="74"> At most, they'd stick a feather on somebody's nose, and if it twitched, they didn't bury them yet. </seg>
<seg id="75"> If it stopped twitching, you bury them. </seg>
<seg id="76"> But today, we have a situation where we want to take vital organs out of beings and give them to other beings. </seg>
<seg id="77"> And as a consequence, we're stuck with having to struggle with this really difficult question about who's dead, and this leads us to a really difficult situation where we don't have such simple categories as we've had before. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Now you might think that all this breaking-down of categories would make somebody like me really happy. </seg>
<seg id="79"> I'm a political progressive, I defend people with unusual bodies, but I have to admit to you that it makes me nervous. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Understanding that these categories are really much more unstable than we thought makes me tense. </seg>
<seg id="81"> And it makes me tense from the point of view of thinking about democracy. </seg>
<seg id="82"> So in order to tell you about that tension, I have to first admit to you that I'm a huge fan of the Founding Fathers. </seg>
<seg id="83"> I know they were racists, I know they were sexist, but they were great. </seg>
<seg id="84"> I mean, they were so brave and so bold and so radical in what they did that I find myself watching that cheesy musical "1776" every few years, and it's not because of the music, which is totally forgettable. </seg>
<seg id="85"> It's because of what happened in 1776 with the Founding Fathers. </seg>
<seg id="86"> The Founding Fathers were, for my point of view, the original anatomical activists, and this is why. </seg>
<seg id="87"> What they rejected was an anatomical concept and replaced it with another one that was radical and beautiful and held us for 200 years. </seg>
<seg id="88"> So as you all recall, what our Founding Fathers were rejecting was a concept of monarchy, and the monarchy was basically based on a very simplistic concept of anatomy. </seg>
<seg id="89"> The monarchs of the old world didn't have a concept of DNA, but they did have a concept of birthright. </seg>
<seg id="90"> They had a concept of blue blood. </seg>
<seg id="91"> They had the idea that the people who would be in political power should be in political power because of the blood being passed down from grandfather to father to son and so forth. </seg>
<seg id="92"> The Founding Fathers rejected that idea, and they replaced it with a new anatomical concept, and that concept was all men are created equal. </seg>
<seg id="93"> They leveled that playing field and decided the anatomy that mattered was the commonality of anatomy, not the difference in anatomy, and that was a really radical thing to do. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Now they were doing it in part because they were part of an Enlightenment system where two things were growing up together. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And that was democracy growing up, but it was also science growing up at the same time. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And it's really clear, if you look at the history of the Founding Fathers, a lot of them were very interested in science, and they were interested in a concept of a naturalistic world. </seg>
<seg id="97"> They were moving away from supernatural explanations, and they were rejecting things like a supernatural concept of power, where it transmitted because of a very vague concept of birthright. </seg>
<seg id="98"> They were moving towards a naturalistic concept. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And if you look, for example, in the Declaration of Independence, they talk about nature and nature's God. </seg>
<seg id="100"> They don't talk about God and God's nature. </seg>
<seg id="101"> They're talking about the power of nature to tell us who we are. </seg>
<seg id="102"> So as part of that, they were coming to us with a concept that was about anatomical commonality. </seg>
<seg id="103"> And in doing so, they were really setting up in a beautiful way the Civil Rights movement of the future. </seg>
<seg id="104"> They didn't think of it that way, but they did it for us, and it was great. </seg>
<seg id="105"> So what happened years afterward? </seg>
<seg id="106"> What happened was women, for example, who wanted the right to vote, took the Founding Fathers' concept of anatomical commonality being more important than anatomical difference and said, "The fact that we have a uterus and ovaries is not significant enough in terms of a difference to mean that we shouldn't have the right to vote, the right to full citizenship, the right to own property, etc., etc." </seg>
<seg id="107"> And women successfully argued that. </seg>
<seg id="108"> Next came the successful Civil Rights movement, where we found people like Sojourner Truth talking about, "Ain't I a woman?" </seg>
<seg id="109"> We find men on the marching lines of the Civil Rights movement saying, "I am a man." </seg>
<seg id="110"> Again, people of color appealing to a commonality of anatomy over a difference of anatomy, again, successfully. </seg>
<seg id="111"> We see the same thing with the disability rights movement. </seg>
<seg id="112"> The problem is, of course, that, as we begin to look at all that commonality, we have to begin to question why we maintain certain divisions. </seg>
<seg id="113"> Now mind you, I want to maintain some divisions, anatomically, in our culture. </seg>
<seg id="114"> For example, I don't want to give a fish the same rights as a human. </seg>
<seg id="115"> I don't want to say we give up entirely on anatomy. </seg>
<seg id="116"> I don't want to say five-year-olds should be allowed to consent to sex or consent to marry. </seg>
<seg id="117"> So there are some anatomical divisions that make sense to me and that I think we should retain. </seg>
<seg id="118"> But the challenge is trying to figure out which ones they are and why do we retain them and do they have meaning. </seg>
<seg id="119"> So let's go back to those two beings conceived at the beginning of this talk. </seg>
<seg id="120"> We have two beings, both conceived in the middle of 1979 on the exact same day. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Let's imagine one of them, Mary, is born three months prematurely, so she's born on June 1, 1980. </seg>
<seg id="122"> Henry, by contrast, is born at term, so he's born on March 1, 1980. </seg>
<seg id="123"> Simply by virtue of the fact that Mary was born prematurely three months, she comes into all sorts of rights three months earlier than Henry does -- the right to consent to sex, the right to vote, the right to drink. </seg>
<seg id="124"> Henry has to wait for all of that, not because he's actually any different in age, biologically, except in terms of when he was born. </seg>
<seg id="125"> We find other kinds of weirdness in terms of what their rights are. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Henry, by virtue of being assumed to be male -- although I haven't told you that he's the XY one -- by virtue of being assumed to be male is now liable to be drafted, which Mary does not need to worry about. </seg>
<seg id="127"> Mary, meanwhile, cannot in all the states have the same right that Henry has in all the states, namely, the right to marry. </seg>
<seg id="128"> Henry can marry in every state a woman, but Mary can only marry today in a few states a woman. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So we have these anatomical categories that persist that are in many ways problematic and questionable. </seg>
<seg id="130"> And the question to me becomes: What do we do, as our science gets to be so good in looking at anatomy, that we reach the point where we have to admit that a democracy that's been based on anatomy might start falling apart? </seg>
<seg id="131"> I don't want to give up the science, but at the same time it kind of feels sometimes like the science is coming out from under us. </seg>
<seg id="132"> So where do we go? </seg>
<seg id="133"> It seems like what happens in our culture is a sort of pragmatic attitude: "Well, we have to draw the line somewhere, so we will draw the line somewhere." </seg>
<seg id="134"> But a lot of people get stuck in a very strange position. </seg>
<seg id="135"> So for example, Texas has at one point decided that what it means to marry a man is to mean that you don't have a Y chromosome, and what it means to marry a woman means you do have a Y chromosome. </seg>
<seg id="136"> Now in practice they don't actually test people for their chromosomes. </seg>
<seg id="137"> But this is also very bizarre, because of the story I told you at the beginning about androgen insensitivity syndrome. </seg>
<seg id="138"> If we look at one of the founding fathers of modern democracy, Dr. Martin Luther King, he offers us something of a solution in his "I have a dream" speech. </seg>
<seg id="139"> He says we should judge people "based not on the color of their skin, but on the content of their character," moving beyond anatomy. </seg>
<seg id="140"> And I want to say, "Yeah, that sounds like a really good idea." </seg>
<seg id="141"> But in practice, how do you do it? </seg>
<seg id="142"> How do you judge people based on the content of character? </seg>
<seg id="143"> I also want to point out that I'm not sure that is how we should distribute rights in terms of humans, because, I have to admit, that there are some golden retrievers I know that are probably more deserving of social services than some humans I know. </seg>
<seg id="144"> I also want to say there are probably also some yellow Labradors that I know that are more capable of informed, intelligent, mature decisions about sexual relations than some 40-year-olds that I know. </seg>
<seg id="145"> So how do we operationalize the question of content of character? </seg>
<seg id="146"> It turns out to be really difficult. </seg>
<seg id="147"> And part of me also wonders, what if content of character turns out to be something that's scannable in the future -- able to be seen with an fMRI? </seg>
<seg id="148"> Do we really want to go there? </seg>
<seg id="149"> I'm not sure where we go. </seg>
<seg id="150"> What I do know is that it seems to be really important to think about the idea of the United States being in the lead of thinking about this issue of democracy. </seg>
<seg id="151"> We've done a really good job struggling with democracy, and I think we would do a good job in the future. </seg>
<seg id="152"> We don't have a situation that Iran has, for example, where a man who's sexually attracted to other men is liable to be murdered, unless he's willing to submit to a sex change, in which case he's allowed to live. </seg>
<seg id="153"> We don't have that kind of situation. </seg>
<seg id="154"> I'm glad to say we don't have the kind of situation with -- a surgeon I talked to a few years ago who had brought over a set of conjoined twins in order to separate them, partly to make a name for himself. </seg>
<seg id="155"> But when I was on the phone with him, asking why he was going to do this surgery -- this was a very high-risk surgery -- his answer was that, in this other nation, these children were going to be treated very badly, and so he had to do this. </seg>
<seg id="156"> My response to him was, "Well, have you considered political asylum instead of a separation surgery?" </seg>
<seg id="157"> The United States has offered tremendous possibility for allowing people to be the way they are, without having them have to be changed for the sake of the state. </seg>
<seg id="158"> So I think we have to be in the lead. </seg>
<seg id="159"> Well, just to close, I want to suggest to you that I've been talking a lot about the fathers. </seg>
<seg id="160"> And I want to think about the possibilities of what democracy might look like, or might have looked like, if we had more involved the mothers. </seg>
<seg id="161"> And I want to say something a little bit radical for a feminist, and that is that I think that there may be different kinds of insights that can come from different kinds of anatomies, particularly when we have people thinking in groups. </seg>
<seg id="162"> Now for years, because I've been interested in intersex, I've also been interested in sex difference research. </seg>
<seg id="163"> And one of the things that I've been really interested in is looking at the differences between males and females in terms of the way they think and operate in the world. </seg>
<seg id="164"> And what we know from cross-cultural studies is that females, on average -- not everyone, but on average -- are more inclined to be very attentive to complex social relations and to taking care of people who are basically vulnerable within the group. </seg>
<seg id="165"> And so if we think about that, we have an interesting situation on our hands. </seg>
<seg id="166"> Years ago, when I was in graduate school, one of my graduate advisers who knew I was interested in feminism -- I considered myself a feminist, as I still do -- asked a really strange question. </seg>
<seg id="167"> He said, "Tell me what's feminine about feminism." </seg>
<seg id="168"> And I thought, "Well that's the dumbest question I've ever heard. </seg>
<seg id="169"> Feminism is all about undoing stereotypes about gender, so there's nothing feminine about feminism." </seg>
<seg id="170"> But the more I thought about his question, the more I thought there might be something feminine about feminism. </seg>
<seg id="171"> That is to say, there might be something, on average, different about female brains from male brains that makes us more attentive to deeply complex social relationships and more attentive to taking care of the vulnerable. </seg>
<seg id="172"> So whereas the fathers were extremely attentive to figuring out how to protect individuals from the state, it's possible that if we injected more mothers into this concept, what we would have is more of a concept of, not just how to protect, but how to care for each other. </seg>
<seg id="173"> And maybe that's where we need to go in the future, when we take democracy beyond anatomy, is to think less about the individual body, in terms of the identity, and think more about those relationships. </seg>
<seg id="174"> So that as we the people try to create a more perfect union, we're thinking about what we do for each other. </seg>
<seg id="175"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1161" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jessi_arrington_wearing_nothing_new.html</url>
<description>Designer Jessi Arrington packed nothing for but 7 pairs of undies, buying the rest of her clothes in thrift stores around LA. It's a meditation on conscious consumption -- wrapped in a rainbow of color and creativity.</description>
<keywords>consumerism,creativity,culture,design</keywords>
<talkid>1161</talkid>
<title>Jessi Arrington: Wearing nothing new</title>
<seg id="1"> I'm Jessi, and this is my suitcase. </seg>
<seg id="2"> But before I show you what I've got inside, I'm going to make a very public confession, and that is, I'm outfit-obsessed. </seg>
<seg id="3"> I love finding, wearing, and more recently, photographing and blogging a different, colorful, crazy outfit for every single occasion. </seg>
<seg id="4"> But I don't buy anything new. </seg>
<seg id="5"> I get all my clothes secondhand from flea markets and thrift stores. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Aww, thank you. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Secondhand shopping allows me to reduce the impact my wardrobe has on the environment and on my wallet. </seg>
<seg id="8"> I get to meet all kinds of great people; my dollars usually go to a good cause; I look pretty unique; and it makes shopping like my own personal treasure hunt. </seg>
<seg id="9"> I mean, what am I going to find today? </seg>
<seg id="10"> Is it going to be my size? </seg>
<seg id="11"> Will I like the color? </seg>
<seg id="12"> Will it be under $20? </seg>
<seg id="13"> If all the answers are yes, I feel as though I've won. </seg>
<seg id="14"> I want to get back to my suitcase and tell you what I packed for this exciting week here at TED. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I mean, what does somebody with all these outfits bring with her? </seg>
<seg id="16"> So I'm going to show you exactly what I brought. </seg>
<seg id="17"> I brought seven pairs of underpants and that's it. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Exactly one week's worth of undies is all I put in my suitcase. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I was betting that I'd be able to find everything else I could possible want to wear once I got here to Palm Springs. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And since you don't know me as the woman walking around TED in her underwear -- that means I found a few things. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And I'd really love to show you my week's worth of outfits right now. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Does that sound good? </seg>
<seg id="23"> So as I do this, I'm also going to tell you a few of the life lessons that, believe it or not, I have picked up in these adventures wearing nothing new. </seg>
<seg id="24"> So let's start with Sunday. </seg>
<seg id="25"> I call this "Shiny Tiger." </seg>
<seg id="26"> You do not have to spend a lot of money to look great. </seg>
<seg id="27"> You can almost always look phenomenal for under $50. </seg>
<seg id="28"> This whole outfit, including the jacket, cost me $55, and it was the most expensive thing that I wore the entire week. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Monday: Color is powerful. </seg>
<seg id="30"> It is almost physiologically impossible to be in a bad mood when you're wearing bright red pants. </seg>
<seg id="31"> If you are happy, you are going to attract other happy people to you. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Tuesday: Fitting in is way overrated. </seg>
<seg id="33"> I've spent a whole lot of my life trying to be myself and at the same time fit in. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Just be who you are. </seg>
<seg id="35"> If you are surrounding yourself with the right people, they will not only get it, they will appreciate it. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Wednesday: Embrace your inner child. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Sometimes people tell me that I look like I'm playing dress-up, or that I remind them of their seven-year-old. </seg>
<seg id="38"> I like to smile and say, "Thank you." </seg>
<seg id="39"> Thursday: Confidence is key. </seg>
<seg id="40"> If you think you look good in something, you almost certainly do. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And if you don't think you look good in something, you're also probably right. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I grew up with a mom who taught me this day-in and day-out. </seg>
<seg id="43"> But it wasn't until I turned 30 that I really got what this meant. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And I'm going to break it down for you for just a second. </seg>
<seg id="45"> If you believe you're a beautiful person inside and out, there is no look that you can't pull off. </seg>
<seg id="46"> So there is no excuse for any of us here in this audience. </seg>
<seg id="47"> We should be able to rock anything we want to rock. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Friday: A universal truth -- five words for you: Gold sequins go with everything. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And finally, Saturday: Developing your own unique personal style is a really great way to tell the world something about you without having to say a word. </seg>
<seg id="51"> It's been proven to me time and time again as people have walked up to me this week simply because of what I'm wearing, and we've had great conversations. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So obviously this is not all going to fit back in my tiny suitcase. </seg>
<seg id="53"> So before I go home to Brooklyn, I'm going to donate everything back. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Because the lesson I'm trying to learn myself this week is that it's okay to let go. </seg>
<seg id="55"> I don't need to get emotionally attached to these things because around the corner, there is always going to be another crazy, colorful, shiny outfit just waiting for me, if I put a little love in my heart and look. </seg>
<seg id="56"> Thank you very much. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1137" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/carlo_ratti_architecture_that_senses_and_responds.html</url>
<description>With his team at SENSEable City Lab, MIT's Carlo Ratti makes cool things by sensing the data we create. He pulls from passive data sets -- like the calls we make, the garbage we throw away -- to create surprising visualizations of city life. And he and his team create dazzling interactive environments from moving water and flying light, powered by simple gestures caught through sensors.</description>
<keywords>cities,design,entertainment,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1137</talkid>
<title>Carlo Ratti: Architecture that senses and responds</title>
<seg id="1"> Good afternoon, everybody. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I've got something to show you. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Think about this as a pixel, a flying pixel. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This is what we call, in our lab, sensible design. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Let me tell you a bit about it. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Now if you take this picture -- I'm Italian originally, and every boy in Italy grows up with this picture on the wall of his bedroom -- but the reason I'm showing you this is that something very interesting happened in Formula 1 racing over the past couple of decades. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Now some time ago, if you wanted to win a Formula 1 race, you take a budget, and you bet your budget on a good driver and a good car. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And if the car and the driver were good enough, then you'd win the race. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Now today, if you want to win the race, actually you need also something like this -- something that monitors the car in real time, has a few thousand sensors collecting information from the car, transmitting this information into the system, and then processing it and using it in order to go back to the car with decisions and changing things in real time as information is collected. </seg>
<seg id="10"> This is what, in engineering terms, you would call a real time control system. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And basically, it's a system made of two components -- a sensing and an actuating component. </seg>
<seg id="12"> What is interesting today is that real time control systems are starting to enter into our lives. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Our cities, over the past few years, just have been blanketed with networks, electronics. </seg>
<seg id="14"> They're becoming like computers in open air. </seg>
<seg id="15"> And, as computers in open air, they're starting to respond in a different way to be able to be sensed and to be actuated. </seg>
<seg id="16"> If we fix cities, actually it's a big deal. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Just as an aside, I wanted to mention, cities are only two percent of the Earth's crust, but they are 50 percent of the world's population. </seg>
<seg id="18"> They are 75 percent of the energy consumption -- up to 80 percent of CO2 emissions. </seg>
<seg id="19"> So if we're able to do something with cities, that's a big deal. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Beyond cities, all of this sensing and actuating is entering our everyday objects. </seg>
<seg id="21"> That's from an exhibition that Paola Antonelli is organizing at MoMA later this year, during the summer. </seg>
<seg id="22"> It's called "Talk to Me." </seg>
<seg id="23"> Well our objects, our environment is starting to talk back to us. </seg>
<seg id="24"> In a certain sense, it's almost as if every atom out there were becoming both a sensor and an actuator. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And that is radically changing the interaction we have as humans with the environment out there. </seg>
<seg id="26"> In a certain sense, it's almost as if the old dream of Michelangelo ... </seg>
<seg id="27"> you know, when Michelangelo sculpted the Moses, at the end it said that he took the hammer, threw it at the Moses -- actually you can still see a small chip underneath -- and said, shouted, "Perch non parli? Why don't you talk?" </seg>
<seg id="28"> Well today, for the first time, our environment is starting to talk back to us. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And I'll show just a few examples -- again, with this idea of sensing our environment and actuating it. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Let's starting with sensing. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Well, the first project I wanted to share with you is actually one of the first projects by our lab. </seg>
<seg id="32"> It was four and a half years ago in Italy. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And what we did there was actually use a new type of network at the time that had been deployed all across the world -- that's a cellphone network -- and use anonymous and aggregated information from that network, that's collected anyway by the operator, in order to understand how the city works. </seg>
<seg id="34"> The summer was a lucky summer -- 2006. </seg>
<seg id="35"> It's when Italy won the soccer World Cup. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Some of you might remember, it was Italy and France playing, and then Zidane at the end, the headbutt. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And anyway, Italy won at the end. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Now look at what happened that day just by monitoring activity happening on the network. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Here you see the city. </seg>
<seg id="40"> You see the Colosseum in the middle, the river Tiber. </seg>
<seg id="41"> It's morning, before the match. </seg>
<seg id="42"> You see the timeline on the top. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Early afternoon, people here and there, making calls and moving. </seg>
<seg id="44"> The match begins -- silence. </seg>
<seg id="45"> France scores. Italy scores. </seg>
<seg id="46"> Halftime, people make a quick call and go to the bathroom. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Second half. End of normal time. </seg>
<seg id="48"> First overtime, second. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Zidane, the headbutt in a moment. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Italy wins. Yeah. </seg>
<seg id="51"> Well, that night, everybody went to celebrate in the center. </seg>
<seg id="52"> You saw the big peak. </seg>
<seg id="53"> The following day, again everybody went to the center to meet the winning team and the prime minister at the time. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And then everybody moved down. </seg>
<seg id="55"> You see the image of the place called Circo Massimo, where, since Roman times, people go to celebrate, to have a big party, and you see the peak at the end of the day. </seg>
<seg id="56"> Well, that's just one example of how we can sense the city today in a way that we couldn't have done just a few years ago. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Another quick example about sensing: it's not about people, but about things we use and consume. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Well today, we know everything about where our objects come from. </seg>
<seg id="59"> This is a map that shows you all the chips that form a Mac computer, how they came together. </seg>
<seg id="60"> But we know very little about where things go. </seg>
<seg id="61"> So in this project, we actually developed some small tags to track trash as it moves through the system. </seg>
<seg id="62"> So we actually started with a number of volunteers who helped us in Seattle, just over a year ago, to tag what they were throwing away -- different types of things, as you can see here -- things they would throw away anyway. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Then we put a little chip, little tag, onto the trash and then started following it. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Here are the results we just obtained. </seg>
<seg id="65"> From Seattle ... </seg>
<seg id="66"> after one week. </seg>
<seg id="67"> With this information we realized there's a lot of inefficiencies in the system. </seg>
<seg id="68"> We can actually do the same thing with much less energy. </seg>
<seg id="69"> This data was not available before. </seg>
<seg id="70"> But there's a lot of wasted transportation and convoluted things happening. </seg>
<seg id="71"> But the other thing is that we believe that if we see every day that the cup we're throwing away, it doesn't disappear, it's still somewhere on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And the plastic bottle we're throwing away every day still stays there. </seg>
<seg id="73"> And if we show that to people, then we can also promote some behavioral change. </seg>
<seg id="74"> So that was the reason for the project. </seg>
<seg id="75"> My colleague at MIT, Assaf Biderman, he could tell you much more about sensing and many other wonderful things we can do with sensing, but I wanted to go to the second part we discussed at the beginning, and that's actuating our environment. </seg>
<seg id="76"> And the first project is something we did a couple of years ago in Zaragoza, Spain. </seg>
<seg id="77"> It started with a question by the mayor of the city, who came to us saying that Spain and Southern Europe have a beautiful tradition of using water in public space, in architecture. </seg>
<seg id="78"> And the question was: How could technology, new technology, be added to that? </seg>
<seg id="79"> And one of the ideas that was developed at MIT in a workshop was, imagine this pipe, and you've got valves, solenoid valves, taps, opening and closing. </seg>
<seg id="80"> You create like a water curtain with pixels made of water. </seg>
<seg id="81"> If those pixels fall, you can write on it, you can show patterns, images, text. </seg>
<seg id="82"> And even you can approach it, and it will open up to let you jump through, as you see in this image. </seg>
<seg id="83"> Well, we presented this to Mayor Belloch. </seg>
<seg id="84"> He liked it very much. </seg>
<seg id="85"> And we got a commission to design a building at the entrance of the expo. </seg>
<seg id="86"> We called it Digital Water Pavilion. </seg>
<seg id="87"> The whole building is made of water. </seg>
<seg id="88"> There's no doors or windows, but when you approach it, it will open up to let you in. </seg>
<seg id="89"> The roof also is covered with water. </seg>
<seg id="90"> And if there's a bit of wind, if you want to minimize splashing, you can actually lower the roof. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Or you could close the building, and the whole architecture will disappear, You know, these days, you always get images during the winter, when they take the roof down, of people who have been there and said, "They demolished the building." </seg>
<seg id="92"> No, they didn't demolish it, just when it goes down, the architecture almost disappears. </seg>
<seg id="93"> Here's the building working. </seg>
<seg id="94"> You see the person puzzled about what was going on inside. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And here was myself trying not to get wet, testing the sensors that open the water. </seg>
<seg id="96"> Well, I should tell you now what happened one night when all of the sensors stopped working. </seg>
<seg id="97"> But actually that night, it was even more fun. </seg>
<seg id="98"> All the kids from Zaragoza came to the building, because the way of engaging with the building became something different. </seg>
<seg id="99"> Not anymore a building that would open up to let you in, but a building that would still make cuts and holes through the water, and you had to jump without getting wet. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And that was, for us, was very interesting, because, as architects, as engineers, as designers, we always think about how people will use the things we design. </seg>
<seg id="101"> But then reality's always unpredictable. </seg>
<seg id="102"> And that's the beauty of doing things that are used and interact with people. </seg>
<seg id="103"> Here is an image then of the building with the physical pixels, the pixels made of water, and then projections on them. </seg>
<seg id="104"> And this is what led us to think about the following project I'll show you now. </seg>
<seg id="105"> That's, imagine those pixels could actually start flying. </seg>
<seg id="106"> Imagine you could have small helicopters that move in the air, and then each of them with a small pixel in changing lights -- almost as a cloud that can move in space. </seg>
<seg id="107"> Here is the video. </seg>
<seg id="108"> So imagine one helicopter, like the one we saw before, moving with others, in synchrony. </seg>
<seg id="109"> So you can have this cloud. </seg>
<seg id="110"> You can have a kind of flexible screen or display, like this -- a regular configuration in two dimensions. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Or in regular, but in three dimensions, where the thing that changes is the light, not the pixels' position. </seg>
<seg id="112"> You can play with a different type. </seg>
<seg id="113"> Imagine your screen could just appear in different scales or sizes, different types of resolution. </seg>
<seg id="114"> But then the whole thing can be just a 3D cloud of pixels that you can approach and move through it and see from many, many directions. </seg>
<seg id="115"> Here is the real Flyfire control and going down to form the regular grid as before. </seg>
<seg id="116"> When you turn on the light, actually you see this. So the same as we saw before. </seg>
<seg id="117"> And imagine each of them then controlled by people. </seg>
<seg id="118"> You can have each pixel having an input that comes from people, from people's movement, or so and so. </seg>
<seg id="119"> I want to show you something here for the first time. </seg>
<seg id="120"> We've been working with Roberto Bolle, one of today's top ballet dancers -- the toile at Metropolitan in New York and La Scala in Milan -- and actually captured his movement in 3D in order to use it as an input for Flyfire. </seg>
<seg id="121"> And here you can see Roberto dancing. </seg>
<seg id="122"> You see on the left the pixels, the different resolutions being captured. </seg>
<seg id="123"> It's both 3D scanning in real time and motion capture. </seg>
<seg id="124"> So you can reconstruct a whole movement. </seg>
<seg id="125"> You can go all the way through. </seg>
<seg id="126"> But then, once we have the pixels, then you can play with them and play with color and movement and gravity and rotation. </seg>
<seg id="127"> So we want to use this as one of the possible inputs for Flyfire. </seg>
<seg id="128"> I wanted to show you the last project we are working on. </seg>
<seg id="129"> It's something we're working on for the London Olympics. </seg>
<seg id="130"> It's called The Cloud. </seg>
<seg id="131"> And the idea here is, imagine, again, we can involve people in doing something and changing our environment -- almost to impart what we call cloud raising -- like barn raising, but with a cloud. </seg>
<seg id="132"> Imagine you can have everybody make a small donation for one pixel. </seg>
<seg id="133"> And I think what is remarkable that has happened over the past couple of years is that, over the past couple of decades, we went from the physical world to the digital one. </seg>
<seg id="134"> This has been digitizing everything, knowledge, and making that accessible through the Internet. </seg>
<seg id="135"> Now today, for the first time -- and the Obama campaign showed us this -- we can go from the digital world, from the self-organizing power of networks, to the physical one. </seg>
<seg id="136"> This can be, in our case, we want to use it for designing and doing a symbol. </seg>
<seg id="137"> That means something built in a city. </seg>
<seg id="138"> But tomorrow it can be, in order to tackle today's pressing challenges -- think about climate change or CO2 emissions -- how we can go from the digital world to the physical one. </seg>
<seg id="139"> So the idea that we can actually involve people in doing this thing together, collectively. </seg>
<seg id="140"> The cloud is a cloud, again, made of pixels, in the same way as the real cloud is a cloud made of particles. </seg>
<seg id="141"> And those particles are water, where our cloud is a cloud of pixels. </seg>
<seg id="142"> It's a physical structure in London, but covered with pixels. </seg>
<seg id="143"> You can move inside, have different types of experiences. </seg>
<seg id="144"> You can actually see from underneath, sharing the main moments for the Olympics in 2012 and beyond, and really using it as a way to connect with the community. </seg>
<seg id="145"> So both the physical cloud in the sky and something you can go to the top [of], like London's new mountaintop. </seg>
<seg id="146"> You can enter inside it. </seg>
<seg id="147"> And a kind of new digital beacon for the night -- but most importantly, a new type of experience for anybody who will go to the top. </seg>
<seg id="148"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1171" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/camille_seaman_haunting_photos_of_ice.html</url>
<description>Photographer Camille Seaman shoots icebergs, showing the world the complex beauty of these massive, ancient chunks of ice. Dive in to her photo slideshow, "The Last Iceberg."</description>
<keywords>art,arts,glacier,global issues,photography</keywords>
<talkid>1171</talkid>
<title>Camille Seaman: Haunting photos of polar ice</title>
<seg id="1"> As an artist, connection is very important to me. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Through my work I'm trying to articulate that humans are not separate from nature and that everything is interconnected. </seg>
<seg id="3"> I first went to Antarctica almost 10 years ago, where I saw my first icebergs. </seg>
<seg id="4"> I was in awe. </seg>
<seg id="5"> My heart beat fast, my head was dizzy, trying to comprehend what it was that stood in front of me. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The icebergs around me were almost 200 feet out of the water, and I could only help but wonder that this was one snowflake on top of another snowflake, year after year. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Icebergs are born when they calve off of glaciers or break off of ice shelves. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Each iceberg has its own individual personality. </seg>
<seg id="9"> They have a distinct way of interacting with their environment and their experiences. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Some refuse to give up and hold on to the bitter end, while others can't take it anymore and crumble in a fit of dramatic passion. </seg>
<seg id="11"> It's easy to think, when you look at an iceberg, that they're isolated, that they're separate and alone, much like we as humans sometimes view ourselves. </seg>
<seg id="12"> But the reality is far from it. </seg>
<seg id="13"> As an iceberg melts, I am breathing in its ancient atmosphere. </seg>
<seg id="14"> As the iceberg melts, it is releasing mineral-rich fresh water that nourishes many forms of life. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I approach photographing these icebergs as if I'm making portraits of my ancestors, knowing that in these individual moments they exist in that way and will never exist that way again. </seg>
<seg id="16"> It is not a death when they melt; it is not an end, but a continuation of their path through the cycle of life. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Some of the ice in the icebergs that I photograph is very young -- a couple thousand years old. </seg>
<seg id="18"> And some of the ice is over 100,000 years old. </seg>
<seg id="19"> The last pictures I'd like to show you are of an iceberg that I photographed in Qeqetarsuaq, Greenland. </seg>
<seg id="20"> It's a very rare occasion that you get to actually witness an iceberg rolling. </seg>
<seg id="21"> So here it is. </seg>
<seg id="22"> You can see on the left side a small boat. </seg>
<seg id="23"> That's about a 15-foot boat. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And I'd like you to pay attention to the shape of the iceberg and where it is at the waterline. </seg>
<seg id="25"> You can see here, it begins to roll, and the boat has moved to the other side, and the man is standing there. </seg>
<seg id="26"> This is an average-size Greenlandic iceberg. </seg>
<seg id="27"> It's about 120 feet above the water, or 40 meters. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And this video is real time. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And just like that, the iceberg shows you a different side of its personality. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1115" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/mick_ebeling_the_invention_that_unlocked_a_locked_in_artist.html</url>
<description>The nerve disease ALS left graffiti artist TEMPT paralyzed from head to toe, forced to communicate blink by blink. In a remarkable talk at TEDActive, entrepreneur Mick Ebeling shares how he and a team of collaborators built an open-source invention that gave the artist -- and gives others in his circumstance -- the means to make art again.</description>
<keywords>creativity,design,disease,invention,open-source,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1115</talkid>
<title>Mick Ebeling: The invention that unlocked a locked-in artist</title>
<seg id="1"> I have had the distinct blessing in my life to have worked on a bunch of amazing projects. </seg>
<seg id="2"> But the coolest I ever worked on was around this guy. </seg>
<seg id="3"> This guy's name is TEMPT. </seg>
<seg id="4"> TEMPT was one of the foremost graffiti artists in the 80s. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And he came up home from a run one day and said, "Dad, my legs are tingling." </seg>
<seg id="6"> And that was the onset of ALS. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So TEMPT is now completely paralyzed. </seg>
<seg id="8"> He only has use of his eyes. </seg>
<seg id="9"> I was exposed to him. </seg>
<seg id="10"> I have a company that does design and animation, so obviously graffiti is definitely an intricate part of what we admire and respect in the art world. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And so we decided that we were going to sponsor Tony, TEMPT, and his cause. </seg>
<seg id="12"> So I went and met with his brother and father and said, "We're going to give you this money. </seg>
<seg id="13"> What are you going to do with it?" </seg>
<seg id="14"> And his brother said, "I just want to be able to talk to Tony again. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I just want to be able to communicate with him And I said, "Wait a second, isn't that -- I've seen Stephen Hawking -- don't all paralyzed people have the ability to communicate via these devices?" </seg>
<seg id="16"> And he said, "No, unless you're in the upper echelon and you've got really amazing insurance, you can't actually do that. </seg>
<seg id="17"> These devices aren't accessible to people." </seg>
<seg id="18"> And I said, "Well, how do you actually communicate?" </seg>
<seg id="19"> Has everyone seen the movie "The Diving Bell and the Butterfly?" </seg>
<seg id="20"> That's how they communicate -- so run their finger along. </seg>
<seg id="21"> I said, "That's archaic. How can that be?" </seg>
<seg id="22"> So I showed up with the desire to just write a check, and instead, I wrote a check that I had no freaking idea how I was going to cash. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I committed to his brother and his father right then and there -- I'm like, "All right, here's the deal: Tony's going to speak, we're going to get him a machine, and we're going to figure out a way for him to do his art again. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Because it's a travesty that someone who still has all of that in him isn't able to communicate it." </seg>
<seg id="25"> So I spoke at a conference a couple months after that. </seg>
<seg id="26"> I met these guys called GRL, Graffiti Research Lab, and they have a technology that allows them to project a light onto any surface and then, with a laser pointer, draw on it, and it just registers the negative space. </seg>
<seg id="27"> So they go around and do art installations like this. </seg>
<seg id="28"> All the things that go up there, they said there's a life cycle. </seg>
<seg id="29"> First it starts with the sexual organs, then it starts with cuss words, then it was Bush slanders and then people actually got to art. </seg>
<seg id="30"> But there was always a life cycle to their presentations. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So I went home and was having dinner with my wife and was telling her about this, and we were like, "Well wait a second. If we know that this technology exists where you can use your eyes to control things, why don't we figure out a way for TEMPT to control a laser and he could do graf again? Well that would be awesome." </seg>
<seg id="32"> So that started the journey. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And about two years later, about a year later, after a bunch of organization and a bunch of moving things around, we'd accomplished a couple things. </seg>
<seg id="34"> One, we battered down the doors of the insurance companies, and we actually got TEMPT a machine that let him communicate -- a Stephen Hawking machine. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Which was awesome. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And he's seriously one of the funniest -- I call him Yoda, because you talk to the guy, you get an email from him, and you're like, "I'm not worthy. This guy's so amazing." </seg>
<seg id="37"> The other thing we did is we flew seven programmers from all over the world -- literally every corner of the world -- into our house. </seg>
<seg id="38"> My wife and kids and I moved to our back garage, and these hackers and programmers and conspiracy theorists and anarchists took over our house. </seg>
<seg id="39"> A lot of our friends thought we were absolutely stupid to do that and that we were going to come back and all the pictures on the wall would be removed and graf on the walls. </seg>
<seg id="40"> But for over two weeks, we programmed, we went to the Venice boardwalk, my kids got involved, my dog got involved, and we created this. </seg>
<seg id="41"> This is called the EyeWriter, and you can see the description. </seg>
<seg id="42"> This is a cheap pair of sunglasses that we bought at the Venice Beach boardwalk, some copper wire and some stuff from Home Depot and Radio Shack. </seg>
<seg id="43"> We took a PS3 camera, hacked it open, mounted it to an LED light, and now there's a device that is free -- you build this yourself, we publish the code for free, you download the software for free. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And now we've created a device that has absolutely no limitations. </seg>
<seg id="45"> There's no insurance company that can say "No." </seg>
<seg id="46"> There's no hospital that can say "No." </seg>
<seg id="47"> Anybody who's paralyzed now has access to actually draw or communicate using only their eyes. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Thank you guys very much. That was awesome. </seg>
<seg id="50"> So at the end of the two weeks, we went back to TEMPT's room. </seg>
<seg id="51"> I love this picture, because this is someone else's room and that's his room. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So there's all this hustle and bustle going on for the big unveiling. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And after over a year of planning, two weeks of programming, carb-fest and all-night sessions, Tony drew again for the first time in seven years. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And this is an amazing picture, because this is his life support system, and he's looking over his life support system. </seg>
<seg id="55"> We kicked his bed so that he could see out. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And we set up a projector on a wall out in the parking lot outside of his hospital. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And he drew again for the first time, in front of his family and friends -- and you can only imagine what the feeling in the parking lot was. </seg>
<seg id="58"> The funny thing was, we had to break into the parking lot too, so we totally felt like we were legit in the whole graf scene too. </seg>
<seg id="59"> So at the end of this, he sent us an email, and this is what the email said: "That was the first time I've drawn anything for seven years. </seg>
<seg id="60"> I feel like I had been held underwater, and someone finally reached down and pulled my head up so I could breathe." </seg>
<seg id="61"> Isn't that awesome? </seg>
<seg id="62"> So that's kind of our battle cry. </seg>
<seg id="63"> That's what keeps us going and keeps us developing. </seg>
<seg id="64"> And we've got such a long way to go with this. </seg>
<seg id="65"> This is an amazing device, but it's the equivalent of an Etch A Sketch. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And someone who has that kind of artistic potential deserves so much more. </seg>
<seg id="67"> So we're in the process of trying to figure out how to make it better, faster, stronger. </seg>
<seg id="68"> Since that time, we've had all kinds of acknowledgment. </seg>
<seg id="69"> We've won a bunch of awards. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Remember, it's free; none of us are making any money on this thing. </seg>
<seg id="71"> It's all coming out of our own pockets. </seg>
<seg id="72"> So the awards were like, "Oh, this is fantastic." </seg>
<seg id="73"> Armstrong Twittered about us, and then in December, Time magazine honored us as one of the top 50 inventions of 2010, which was really cool. </seg>
<seg id="74"> The coolest thing about this -- and this is what's completing the whole circle -- is that in April of this year, at the Geffen MOCA in downtown Los Angeles, there's going to be an exhibition called "Art of the Streets." </seg>
<seg id="75"> And "Art of the Streets" is going to have pretty much the bad-asses of the street art scene -- Banksy, Shepard Fairey, KAWS -- all of these guys will be there. </seg>
<seg id="76"> TEMPT's going to be in the show, which is pretty awesome. </seg>
<seg id="77"> So basically this is my point: If you see something that's not possible, make it possible. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Everything in this room wasn't possible -- this stage, this computer, this mic, the EyeWriter -- wasn't possible at one point. </seg>
<seg id="79"> Make it possible, everyone in this room. </seg>
<seg id="80"> I'm not a programmer, never done anything with ocular recognition technology, but I just recognized something and associated myself with amazing people so that we could make something happen. </seg>
<seg id="81"> And this is the question I want everyone to ask yourself every single day when you come up with something you feel that needs to be done: if not now, then when? And if not me, then who? </seg>
<seg id="82"> Thank you guys. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1176" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jok_church_a_circle_of_caring.html</url>
<description>In this 3-minute talk, cartoonist and educator Jok Church tells a moving story of the teacher who cared for him when no one else did -- and how he returned the favor.</description>
<keywords>culture,education,love,storytelling</keywords>
<talkid>1176</talkid>
<title>Jok Church: A circle of caring</title>
<seg id="1"> You know, what I do is write for children, and I'm probably America's most widely read children's author, in fact. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And I always tell people that I don't want to show up looking like a scientist. </seg>
<seg id="3"> You can have me as a farmer, or in leathers, and no one has ever chose farmer. </seg>
<seg id="4"> I'm here today to talk to you about circles and epiphanies. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And you know, an epiphany is usually something you find that you dropped someplace. </seg>
<seg id="6"> You've just got to go around the block to see it as an epiphany. </seg>
<seg id="7"> That's a painting of a circle. </seg>
<seg id="8"> A friend of mine did that -- Richard Bollingbroke. </seg>
<seg id="9"> It's the kind of complicated circle that I'm going to tell you about. </seg>
<seg id="10"> My circle began back in the '60s in high school in Stow, Ohio where I was the class queer. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I was the guy beaten up bloody every week in the boys' room, until one teacher saved my life. </seg>
<seg id="12"> She saved my life by letting me go to the bathroom in the teachers' lounge. </seg>
<seg id="13"> She did it in secret. </seg>
<seg id="14"> She did it for three years. </seg>
<seg id="15"> And I had to get out of town. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I had a thumb, I had 85 dollars, and I ended up in San Francisco, California -- met a lover -- and back in the '80s, found it necessary to begin work on AIDS organizations. </seg>
<seg id="17"> About three or four years ago, I got a phone call in the middle of the night from that teacher, Mrs. Posten, who said, "I need to see you. </seg>
<seg id="18"> I'm disappointed that we never got to know each other as adults. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Could you please come to Ohio, and please bring that man that I know you have found by now. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And I should mention that I have pancreatic cancer, and I'd like you to please be quick about this." </seg>
<seg id="21"> Well, the next day we were in Cleveland. </seg>
<seg id="22"> We took a look at her, we laughed, we cried, and we knew that she needed to be in a hospice. </seg>
<seg id="23"> We found her one, we got her there, and we took care of her and watched over her family, because it was necessary. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It's something we knew how to do. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And just as the woman who wanted to know me as an adult got to know me, she turned into a box of ashes and was placed in my hands. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And what had happened was the circle had closed, it had become a circle -- and that epiphany I talked about presented itself. </seg>
<seg id="27"> The epiphany is that death is a part of life. </seg>
<seg id="28"> She saved my life; I and my partner saved hers. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And you know, that part of life needs everything that the rest of life does. </seg>
<seg id="30"> It needs truth and beauty, and I'm so happy it's been mentioned so much here today. </seg>
<seg id="31"> It also needs -- it needs dignity, love and pleasure, and it's our job to hand those things out. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1130" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/ric_elias.html</url>
<description>Ric Elias had a front-row seat on Flight 1549, the plane that crash-landed in the Hudson River in New York in January 2009. What went through his mind as the doomed plane went down? At he tells his story publicly for the first time.</description>
<keywords>business,storytelling,transportation</keywords>
<talkid>1130</talkid>
<title>Ric Elias: 3 things I learned while my plane crashed</title>
<seg id="1"> Imagine a big explosion as you climb through 3,000 ft. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Imagine a plane full of smoke. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Imagine an engine going clack, clack, clack, clack, clack, clack, clack. </seg>
<seg id="4"> It sounds scary. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Well I had a unique seat that day. I was sitting in 1D. </seg>
<seg id="6"> I was the only one who could talk to the flight attendants. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So I looked at them right away, and they said, "No problem. We probably hit some birds." </seg>
<seg id="8"> The pilot had already turned the plane around, and we weren't that far. </seg>
<seg id="9"> You could see Manhattan. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Two minutes later, three things happened at the same time. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The pilot lines up the plane with the Hudson River. </seg>
<seg id="12"> That's usually not the route. </seg>
<seg id="13"> He turns off the engines. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Now imagine being in a plane with no sound. </seg>
<seg id="15"> And then he says three words -- the most unemotional three words I've ever heard. </seg>
<seg id="16"> He says, "Brace for impact." </seg>
<seg id="17"> I didn't have to talk to the flight attendant anymore. </seg>
<seg id="18"> I could see in her eyes, it was terror. Life was over. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Now I want to share with you three things I learned about myself that day. </seg>
<seg id="20"> I learned that it all changes in an instant. </seg>
<seg id="21"> We have this bucket list, we have these things we want to do in life, and I thought about all the people I wanted to reach out to that I didn't, all the fences I wanted to mend, all the experiences I wanted to have and I never did. </seg>
<seg id="22"> As I thought about that later on, I came up with a saying, which is, "I collect bad wines." </seg>
<seg id="23"> Because if the wine is ready and the person is there, I'm opening it. </seg>
<seg id="24"> I no longer want to postpone anything in life. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And that urgency, that purpose, has really changed my life. </seg>
<seg id="26"> The second thing I learned that day -- and this is as we clear the George Washington Bridge, which was by not a lot -- I thought about, wow, I really feel one real regret. </seg>
<seg id="27"> I've lived a good life. </seg>
<seg id="28"> In my own humanity and mistakes, I've tried to get better at everything I tried. </seg>
<seg id="29"> But in my humanity, I also allow my ego to get in. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And I regretted the time I wasted on things that did not matter with people that matter. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And I thought about my relationship with my wife, with my friends, with people. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And after, as I reflected on that, I decided to eliminate negative energy from my life. </seg>
<seg id="33"> It's not perfect, but it's a lot better. </seg>
<seg id="34"> I've not had a fight with my wife in two years. </seg>
<seg id="35"> It feels great. </seg>
<seg id="36"> I no longer try to be right; I choose to be happy. </seg>
<seg id="37"> The third thing I learned -- and this is as your mental clock starts going, "15, 14, 13." </seg>
<seg id="38"> You can see the water coming. </seg>
<seg id="39"> I'm saying, "Please blow up." </seg>
<seg id="40"> I don't want this thing to break in 20 pieces like you've seen in those documentaries. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And as we're coming down, I had a sense of, wow, dying is not scary. </seg>
<seg id="42"> It's almost like we've been preparing for it our whole lives. </seg>
<seg id="43"> But it was very sad. </seg>
<seg id="44"> I didn't want to go; I love my life. </seg>
<seg id="45"> And that sadness really framed in one thought, which is, I only wish for one thing. </seg>
<seg id="46"> I only wish I could see my kids grow up. </seg>
<seg id="47"> About a month later, I was at a performance by my daughter -- first-grader, not much artistic talent ... </seg>
<seg id="48"> ... yet. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And I'm bawling, I'm crying, like a little kid. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And it made all the sense in the world to me. </seg>
<seg id="51"> I realized at that point, by connecting those two dots, that the only thing that matters in my life is being a great dad. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Above all, above all, the only goal I have in life is to be a good dad. </seg>
<seg id="53"> I was given the gift of a miracle, of not dying that day. </seg>
<seg id="54"> I was given another gift, which was to be able to see into the future and come back and live differently. </seg>
<seg id="55"> I challenge you guys that are flying today, imagine the same thing happens on your plane -- and please don't -- but imagine, and how would you change? </seg>
<seg id="56"> What would you get done that you're waiting to get done because you think you'll be here forever? </seg>
<seg id="57"> How would you change your relationships and the negative energy in them? </seg>
<seg id="58"> And more than anything, are you being the best parent you can? </seg>
<seg id="59"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1107" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/ralph_langner_cracking_stuxnet_a_21st_century_cyberweapon.html</url>
<description>When first discovered in 2010, the Stuxnet computer worm posed a baffling puzzle. Beyond its sophistication loomed a more troubling mystery: its purpose. Ralph Langner and team helped crack the code that revealed this digital warhead's final target. In a fascinating look inside cyber-forensics, he explains how -- and makes a bold guess at its shocking origins.</description>
<keywords>Iran,computers,government,nuclear energy,politics,science,technology,war</keywords>
<talkid>1107</talkid>
<title> Cracking Stuxnet, a 21st-century cyber weapon</title>
<seg id="1"> The idea behind the Stuxnet computer worm is actually quite simple. </seg>
<seg id="2"> We don't want Iran to get the bomb. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Their major asset for developing nuclear weapons is the Natanz uranium enrichment facility. </seg>
<seg id="4"> The gray boxes that you see, these are real-time control systems. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Now if we manage to compromise these systems that control drive speeds and valves, we can actually cause a lot of problems with the centrifuge. </seg>
<seg id="6"> The gray boxes don't run Windows software; they are a completely different technology. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But if we manage to place a good Windows virus on a notebook that is used by a maintenance engineer to configure this gray box, then we are in business. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And this is the plot behind Stuxnet. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So we start with a Windows dropper. </seg>
<seg id="10"> The payload goes onto the gray box, damages the centrifuge, and the Iranian nuclear program is delayed -- mission accomplished. </seg>
<seg id="11"> That's easy, huh? </seg>
<seg id="12"> I want to tell you how we found that out. </seg>
<seg id="13"> When we started our research on Stuxnet six months ago, it was completely unknown what the purpose of this thing was. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The only thing that was known is it's very, very complex on the Windows part, the dropper part, used multiple zero-day vulnerabilities. </seg>
<seg id="15"> And it seemed to want to do something with these gray boxes, these real-time control systems. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So that got our attention, and we started a lab project where we infected our environment with Stuxnet and checked this thing out. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And then some very funny things happened. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Stuxnet behaved like a lab rat that didn't like our cheese -- sniffed, but didn't want to eat. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Didn't make sense to me. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And after we experimented with different flavors of cheese, I realized, well, this is a directed attack. </seg>
<seg id="21"> It's completely directed. </seg>
<seg id="22"> The dropper is prowling actively on the gray box if a specific configuration is found, and even if the actual program code that it's trying to infect is actually running on that target. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And if not, Stuxnet does nothing. </seg>
<seg id="24"> So that really got my attention, and we started to work on this nearly around the clock, because I thought, "Well, we don't know what the target is. </seg>
<seg id="25"> It could be, let's say for example, a U.S. power plant, or a chemical plant in Germany. </seg>
<seg id="26"> So we better find out what the target is soon." </seg>
<seg id="27"> So we extracted and decompiled the attack code, and we discovered that it's structured in two digital bombs -- a smaller one and a bigger one. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And we also saw that they are very professionally engineered by people who obviously had all insider information. </seg>
<seg id="29"> They knew all the bits and bites that they had to attack. </seg>
<seg id="30"> They probably even know the shoe size of the operator. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So they know everything. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And if you have heard that the dropper of Stuxnet is complex and high-tech, let me tell you this: the payload is rocket science. </seg>
<seg id="33"> It's way above everything that we have ever seen before. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Here you see a sample of this actual attack code. </seg>
<seg id="35"> We are talking about -- around about 15,000 lines of code. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Looks pretty much like old-style assembly language. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And I want to tell you how we were able to make sense out of this code. </seg>
<seg id="38"> So what we were looking for is, first of all, system function calls, because we know what they do. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And then we were looking for timers and data structures and trying to relate them to the real world -- to potential real world targets. </seg>
<seg id="40"> So we do need target theories that we can prove or disprove. </seg>
<seg id="41"> In order to get target theories, we remember that it's definitely hardcore sabotage, it must be a high-value target and it is most likely located in Iran, because that's where most of the infections had been reported. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Now you don't find several thousand targets in that area. </seg>
<seg id="43"> It basically boils down to the Bushehr nuclear power plant and to the Natanz fuel enrichment plant. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So I told my assistant, "Get me a list of all centrifuge and power plant experts from our client base." </seg>
<seg id="45"> And I phoned them up and picked their brain in an effort to match their expertise with what we found in code and data. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And that worked pretty well. </seg>
<seg id="47"> So we were able to associate the small digital warhead with the rotor control. </seg>
<seg id="48"> The rotor is that moving part within the centrifuge, that black object that you see. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And if you manipulate the speed of this rotor, you are actually able to crack the rotor and eventually even have the centrifuge explode. </seg>
<seg id="50"> What we also saw is that the goal of the attack was really to do it slowly and creepy -- obviously in an effort to drive maintenance engineers crazy, that they would not be able to figure this out quickly. </seg>
<seg id="51"> The big digital warhead -- we had a shot at this by looking very closely at data and data structures. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So for example, the number 164 really stands out in that code; you can't overlook it. </seg>
<seg id="53"> I started to research scientific literature on how these centrifuges are actually built in Natanz and found they are structured in what is called a cascade, and each cascade holds 164 centrifuges. </seg>
<seg id="54"> So that made sense, that was a match. </seg>
<seg id="55"> And it even got better. </seg>
<seg id="56"> These centrifuges in Iran are subdivided into 15, what is called, stages. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And guess what we found in the attack code? </seg>
<seg id="58"> An almost identical structure. </seg>
<seg id="59"> So again, that was a real good match. </seg>
<seg id="60"> And this gave us very high confidence for what we were looking at. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Now don't get me wrong here, it didn't go like this. </seg>
<seg id="62"> These results have been obtained over several weeks of really hard labor. </seg>
<seg id="63"> And we often went into just a dead end and had to recover. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Anyway, so we figured out that both digital warheads were actually aiming at one and the same target, but from different angles. </seg>
<seg id="65"> The small warhead is taking one cascade, and spinning up the rotors and slowing them down, and the big warhead is talking to six cascades and manipulating valves. </seg>
<seg id="66"> So in all, we are very confident that we have actually determined what the target is. </seg>
<seg id="67"> It is Natanz, and it is only Natanz. </seg>
<seg id="68"> So we don't have to worry that other targets might be hit by Stuxnet. </seg>
<seg id="69"> Here's some very cool stuff that we saw -- really knocked my socks off. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Down there is the gray box, and on the top you see the centrifuges. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Now what this thing does is it intercepts the input values from sensors -- so for example, from pressure sensors and vibration sensors -- and it provides legitimate program code, which is still running during the attack, with fake input data. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And as a matter of fact, this fake input data is actually prerecorded by Stuxnet. </seg>
<seg id="73"> So it's just like from the Hollywood movies where during the heist, the observation camera is fed with prerecorded video. </seg>
<seg id="74"> That's cool, huh? </seg>
<seg id="75"> The idea here is obviously not only to fool the operators in the control room. </seg>
<seg id="76"> It actually is much more dangerous and aggressive. </seg>
<seg id="77"> The idea is to circumvent a digital safety system. </seg>
<seg id="78"> We need digital safety systems where a human operator could not act quick enough. </seg>
<seg id="79"> So for example, in a power plant, when your big steam turbine gets too over speed, you must open relief valves within a millisecond. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Obviously, this cannot be done by a human operator. </seg>
<seg id="81"> So this is where we need digital safety systems. </seg>
<seg id="82"> And when they are compromised, then real bad things can happen. </seg>
<seg id="83"> Your plant can blow up. </seg>
<seg id="84"> And neither your operators nor your safety system will notice it. </seg>
<seg id="85"> That's scary. </seg>
<seg id="86"> But it gets worse. </seg>
<seg id="87"> And this is very important, what I'm going to say. </seg>
<seg id="88"> Think about this: this attack is generic. </seg>
<seg id="89"> It doesn't have anything to do, in specifics, with centrifuges, with uranium enrichment. </seg>
<seg id="90"> So it would work as well, for example, in a power plant or in an automobile factory. </seg>
<seg id="91"> It is generic. </seg>
<seg id="92"> And you don't have -- as an attacker -- you don't have to deliver this payload by a USB stick, as we saw it in the case of Stuxnet. </seg>
<seg id="93"> You could also use conventional worm technology for spreading. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Just spread it as wide as possible. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And if you do that, what you end up with is a cyber weapon of mass destruction. </seg>
<seg id="96"> That's the consequence that we have to face. </seg>
<seg id="97"> So unfortunately, the biggest number of targets for such attacks are not in the Middle East. </seg>
<seg id="98"> They're in the United States and Europe and in Japan. </seg>
<seg id="99"> So all of the green areas, these are your target-rich environments. </seg>
<seg id="100"> We have to face the consequences, and we better start to prepare right now. </seg>
<seg id="101"> Thanks. </seg>
<seg id="102"> I've got a question. </seg>
<seg id="103"> Ralph, it's been quite widely reported that people assume that Mossad is the main entity behind this. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Is that your opinion? </seg>
<seg id="105"> Okay, you really want to hear that? </seg>
<seg id="106"> Yeah. Okay. </seg>
<seg id="107"> My opinion is that the Mossad is involved, but that the leading force is not Israel. </seg>
<seg id="108"> So the leading force behind that is the cyber superpower. </seg>
<seg id="109"> There is only one, and that's the United States -- fortunately, fortunately. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Because otherwise, our problems would even be bigger. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Thank you for scaring the living daylights out of us. Thank you, Ralph. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1114" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/morgan_spurlock_the_greatest_ted_talk_ever_sold.html</url>
<description>With humor and persistence, filmmaker Morgan Spurlock dives into the hidden but influential world of brand marketing, on his quest to make a completely sponsored film about sponsorship. </description>
<keywords>Talks</keywords>
<talkid>1114</talkid>
<title> The greatest TED Talk ever sold</title>
<seg id="1"> I have spent the past few years putting myself into situations that are usually very difficult and at the same time somewhat dangerous. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I went to prison -- difficult. </seg>
<seg id="3"> I worked in a coal mine -- dangerous. </seg>
<seg id="4"> I filmed in war zones -- difficult and dangerous. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And I spent 30 days eating nothing but this -- fun in the beginning, little difficult in the middle, very dangerous in the end. </seg>
<seg id="6"> In fact, most of my career, I've been immersing myself into seemingly horrible situations for the whole goal of trying to examine societal issues in a way that make them engaging, that make them interesting, that hopefully break them down in a way that make them entertaining and accessible to an audience. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So when I knew I was coming here to do a TED Talk that was going to look at the world of branding and sponsorship, I knew I would want to do something a little different. </seg>
<seg id="8"> So as some of you may or may not have heard, a couple weeks ago, I took out an ad on eBay. </seg>
<seg id="9"> I sent out some Facebook messages, some Twitter messages, and I gave people the opportunity to buy the naming rights to my 2011 TED Talk. </seg>
<seg id="10"> That's right, some lucky individual, corporation, for-profit or non-profit, was going to get the once-in-a-lifetime opportunity -- because I'm sure Chris Anderson will never let it happen again -- to buy the naming rights to the talk you're watching right now, that at the time didn't have a title, didn't really have a lot of content and didn't really give much hint as to what the subject matter would actually be. </seg>
<seg id="11"> So what you were getting was this: Your name here presents: My TED Talk that you have no idea what the subject is and, depending on the content, could ultimately blow up in your face, especially if I make you or your company look stupid for doing it. </seg>
<seg id="12"> But that being said, it's a very good media opportunity. </seg>
<seg id="13"> You know how many people watch these TED Talks? </seg>
<seg id="14"> It's a lot. </seg>
<seg id="15"> That's just a working title, by the way. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So even with that caveat, I knew that someone would buy the naming rights. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Now if you'd have asked me that a year ago, I wouldn't have been able to tell you that with any certainty. </seg>
<seg id="18"> But in the new project that I'm working on, my new film, we examine the world of marketing, advertising. </seg>
<seg id="19"> And as I said earlier, I put myself in some pretty horrible situations over the years, but nothing could prepare me, nothing could ready me, for anything as difficult or as dangerous as going into the rooms with these guys. </seg>
<seg id="20"> You see, I had this idea for a movie. </seg>
<seg id="21"> What I want to do is make a film all about product placement, marketing and advertising, where the entire film is funded by product placement, marketing and advertising. </seg>
<seg id="22"> So the movie will be called "The Greatest Movie Ever Sold." </seg>
<seg id="23"> So what happens in "The Greatest Movie Ever Sold," is that everything from top to bottom, from start to finish, is branded from beginning to end -- from the above-the-title sponsor that you'll see in the movie, which is brand X. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Now this brand, the Qualcomm Stadium, the Staples Center ... </seg>
<seg id="25"> these people will be married to the film in perpetuity -- forever. </seg>
<seg id="26"> And so the film explores this whole idea -- It's what? In perpetuity, forever? </seg>
<seg id="27"> I'm a redundant person. </seg>
<seg id="28"> That was more for emphasis. </seg>
<seg id="29"> It was, "In perpetuity. Forever." </seg>
<seg id="30"> But not only are we going to have the brand X title sponsor, but we're going to make sure we sell out every category we can in the film. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So maybe we sell a shoe and it becomes the greatest shoe you ever wore ... </seg>
<seg id="32"> the greatest car you ever drove from "The Greatest Movie Ever Sold," the greatest drink you've ever had, courtesy of "The Greatest Movie Ever Sold." </seg>
<seg id="33"> So the idea is, beyond just showing that brands are a part of your life, but actually get them to finance the film? </seg>
<seg id="34"> And actually we show the whole process of how does it work. </seg>
<seg id="35"> The goal of this whole film is transparency. </seg>
<seg id="36"> You're going to see the whole thing take place in this movie. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So that's the whole concept, the whole film, start to finish. </seg>
<seg id="38"> And I would love for CEG to help make it happen. </seg>
<seg id="39"> You know it's funny, because when I first hear it, it is the ultimate respect for an audience. </seg>
<seg id="40"> I don't know how receptive people are going to be to it, though. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Do you have a perspective -- I don't want to use "angle" because that has a negative connotation -- but do you know how this is going to play out? </seg>
<seg id="42"> How much money does it take to do this? </seg>
<seg id="43"> 1.5 million. </seg>
<seg id="44"> I think that you're going to have a hard time meeting with them, but I think it's certainly worth pursuing a couple big, really obvious brands. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Who knows, maybe by the time your film comes out, we look like a bunch of blithering idiots. </seg>
<seg id="46"> What do you think the response is going to be? </seg>
<seg id="47"> The responses mostly will be "no." </seg>
<seg id="48"> But is it a tough sell because of the film or a tough sell because of me? </seg>
<seg id="49"> JK: Both. </seg>
<seg id="50"> ... Meaning not so optimistic. </seg>
<seg id="51"> So, sir, can you help me? I need help. </seg>
<seg id="52"> I can help you. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Okay. </seg>
<seg id="54"> Awesome. </seg>
<seg id="55"> We've gotta figure out which brands. </seg>
<seg id="56"> Yeah. </seg>
<seg id="57"> When you look at the people you deal with .. </seg>
<seg id="58"> We've got some places we can go. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Turn the camera off. </seg>
<seg id="60"> I thought "Turn the camera off" meant, "Let's have an off-the-record conversation." </seg>
<seg id="61"> Turns out it really means, "We want nothing to do with your movie." </seg>
<seg id="62"> And just like that, one by one, all of these companies suddenly disappeared. </seg>
<seg id="63"> None of them wanted anything to do with this movie. </seg>
<seg id="64"> I was amazed. </seg>
<seg id="65"> They wanted absolutely nothing to do with this project. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And I was blown away, because I thought the whole concept, the idea of advertising, was to get your product out in front of as many people as possible, to get as many people to see it as possible. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Especially in today's world, this intersection of new media and old media and the fractured media landscape, isn't the idea to get that new buzz-worthy delivery vehicle that's going to get that message to the masses? </seg>
<seg id="68"> No, that's what I thought. </seg>
<seg id="69"> But the problem was, you see, my idea had one fatal flaw, and that flaw was this. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Actually no, that was not the flaw whatsoever. </seg>
<seg id="71"> That wouldn't have been a problem at all. </seg>
<seg id="72"> This would have been fine. </seg>
<seg id="73"> But what this image represents was the problem. </seg>
<seg id="74"> See, when you do a Google image search for transparency, this is --- This is one of the first images that comes up. </seg>
<seg id="75"> So I like the way you roll, Sergey Brin. No. </seg>
<seg id="76"> This is was the problem: transparency -- free from pretense or deceit; easily detected or seen through; readily understood; characterized by visibility or accessibility of information, especially concerning business practices -- that last line being probably the biggest problem. </seg>
<seg id="77"> You see, we hear a lot about transparency these days. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Our politicians say it, our president says it, even our CEO's say it. </seg>
<seg id="79"> But suddenly when it comes down to becoming a reality, something suddenly changes. </seg>
<seg id="80"> But why? Well, transparency is scary -- like that odd, still-screaming bear. </seg>
<seg id="81"> It's unpredictable -- like this odd country road. </seg>
<seg id="82"> And it's also very risky. </seg>
<seg id="83"> What else is risky? </seg>
<seg id="84"> Eating an entire bowl of Cool Whip. </seg>
<seg id="85"> That's very risky. </seg>
<seg id="86"> Now when I started talking to companies and telling them that we wanted to tell this story, and they said, "No, we want you to tell a story. </seg>
<seg id="87"> We want you to tell a story, but we just want to tell our story." </seg>
<seg id="88"> See, when I was a kid and my father would catch me in some sort of a lie -- and there he is giving me the look he often gave me -- he would say, "Son, there's three sides to every story. </seg>
<seg id="89"> There's your story, there's my story and there's the real story." </seg>
<seg id="90"> Now you see, with this film, we wanted to tell the real story. </seg>
<seg id="91"> But with only one company, one agency willing to help me -- and that's only because I knew John Bond and Richard Kirshenbaum for years -- I realized that I would have to go on my own, I'd have to cut out the middleman and go to the companies myself with all of my team. </seg>
<seg id="92"> So what you suddenly started to realize -- or what I started to realize -- is that when you started having conversations with these companies, the idea of understanding your brand is a universal problem. </seg>
<seg id="93"> I have friends who make great big, giant Hollywood films, and I have friends who make little independent films like I make. </seg>
<seg id="94"> And the friends of mine who make big, giant Hollywood movies say the reason their films are so successful is because of the brand partners that they have. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And then my friends who make small independent films say, "Well, how are we supposed to compete with these big, giant Hollywood movies?" </seg>
<seg id="96"> And the movie is called "The Greatest Movie Ever Sold." </seg>
<seg id="97"> So how specifically will we see Ban in the film? </seg>
<seg id="98"> Any time I'm ready to go, any time I open up my medicine cabinet, you will see Ban deodorant. </seg>
<seg id="99"> While anytime I do an interview with someone, I can say, "Are you fresh enough for this interview? </seg>
<seg id="100"> Are you ready? You look a little nervous. </seg>
<seg id="101"> I want to help you calm down. </seg>
<seg id="102"> So maybe you should put some one before the interview." </seg>
<seg id="103"> So we'll offer one of these fabulous scents. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Whether it's a "Floral Fusion" or a "Paradise Winds," they'll have their chance. </seg>
<seg id="105"> We will have them geared for both male or female -- solid, roll-on or stick, whatever it may be. </seg>
<seg id="106"> That's the two-cent tour. </seg>
<seg id="107"> So now I can answer any of your questions and give you the five-cent tour. </seg>
<seg id="108"> We are a smaller brand. </seg>
<seg id="109"> Much like you talked about being a smaller movie, we're very much a challenger brand. </seg>
<seg id="110"> So we don't have the budgets that other brands have. </seg>
<seg id="111"> So doing things like this -- you know, remind people about Ban -- is kind of why were interested in it. </seg>
<seg id="112"> What are the words that you would use to describe Ban? </seg>
<seg id="113"> Ban is blank. </seg>
<seg id="114"> That's a great question. </seg>
<seg id="115"> Superior technology. </seg>
<seg id="116"> Technology's not the way you want to describe something somebody's putting in their armpit. </seg>
<seg id="117"> We talk about bold, fresh. </seg>
<seg id="118"> I think "fresh" is a great word that really spins this category into the positive, versus "fights odor and wetness." </seg>
<seg id="119"> It keeps you fresh. </seg>
<seg id="120"> How do we keep you fresher longer -- better freshness, more freshness, three times fresher. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Things like that that are more of that positive benefit. </seg>
<seg id="122"> And that's a multi-million dollar corporation. </seg>
<seg id="123"> What about me? What about a regular guy? </seg>
<seg id="124"> I need to go talk to the man on the street, the people who are like me, the regular Joes. </seg>
<seg id="125"> They need to tell me about my brand. </seg>
<seg id="126"> How would you guys describe your brand? </seg>
<seg id="127"> Um, my brand? </seg>
<seg id="128"> I don't know. </seg>
<seg id="129"> I like really nice clothes. </seg>
<seg id="130"> 80's revival meets skater-punk, unless it's laundry day. </seg>
<seg id="131"> All right, what is brand Gerry? </seg>
<seg id="132"> Unique. </seg>
<seg id="133"> I guess what kind of genre, style I am would be like dark glamor. </seg>
<seg id="134"> I like a lot of black colors, a lot of grays and stuff like that. </seg>
<seg id="135"> But usually I have an accessory, like sunglasses, or I like crystal and things like that too. </seg>
<seg id="136"> If Dan were a brand, he might be a classic convertible Mercedes Benz. </seg>
<seg id="137"> The brand that I am is, I would call it casual fly. </seg>
<seg id="138"> Part hippie, part yogi, part Brooklyn girl -- I don't know. </seg>
<seg id="139"> I'm the pet guy. </seg>
<seg id="140"> I sell pet toys all over the country, all over the world. </seg>
<seg id="141"> So I guess that's my brand. </seg>
<seg id="142"> In my warped little industry, that's my brand. </seg>
<seg id="143"> My brand is FedEx because I deliver the goods. </seg>
<seg id="144"> Failed writer-alcoholic brand. </seg>
<seg id="145"> Is that something? </seg>
<seg id="146"> I'm a lawyer brand. </seg>
<seg id="147"> I'm Tom. </seg>
<seg id="148"> Well we can't all be brand Tom, but I do often find myself at the intersection of dark glamor and casual fly. </seg>
<seg id="149"> And what I realized is I needed an expert. </seg>
<seg id="150"> I needed somebody who could get inside my head, somebody who could really help me understand what they call your "brand personality." </seg>
<seg id="151"> And so I found a company called Olson Zaltman in Pittsburg. </seg>
<seg id="152"> They've helped companies like Nestle, Febreze, Hallmark discover that brand personality. </seg>
<seg id="153"> If they could do it for them, surely they could do it for me. </seg>
<seg id="154"> You brought your pictures, right? </seg>
<seg id="155"> I did. The very first picture is a picture of my family. </seg>
<seg id="156"> So tell me a little bit how it relates to your thoughts and feelings about who you are. </seg>
<seg id="157"> These are the people who shape the way I look at the world. </seg>
<seg id="158"> Tell me about this world. </seg>
<seg id="159"> This world? I think your world is the world that you live in -- like people who are around you, your friends, your family, the way you live your life, the job you do. </seg>
<seg id="160"> All those things stemmed and started from one place, and for me they stemmed and started with my family in West Virginia. </seg>
<seg id="161"> What's the next one you want to talk about? </seg>
<seg id="162"> The next one: This was the best day ever. </seg>
<seg id="163"> How does this relate to your thoughts and feelings about who you are? </seg>
<seg id="164"> It's like, who do I want to be? </seg>
<seg id="165"> I like things that are different. </seg>
<seg id="166"> I like things that are weird. I like weird things. </seg>
<seg id="167"> Tell me about the "why" phase -- what does that do for us? </seg>
<seg id="168"> What is the machete? What pupa stage are you in now? </seg>
<seg id="169"> Why is it important to reboot? What does the red represent? </seg>
<seg id="170"> Tell me a little bit about that part. </seg>
<seg id="171"> ... A little more about you that is not who you are. </seg>
<seg id="172"> What are some other metamorphoses that you've had? </seg>
<seg id="173"> ... Doesn't have to be fear. What kind of roller coaster are you on? </seg>
<seg id="174"> EEEEEE! No, thank you. </seg>
<seg id="175"> Thanks for you patience. </seg>
<seg id="176"> Yeah. All right. </seg>
<seg id="177"> Yeah, I don't know what's going to come of this. </seg>
<seg id="178"> There was a whole lot of crazy going on in there. </seg>
<seg id="179"> The first thing we saw was this idea that you had two distinct, but complementary sides to your brand personality -- the Morgan Spurlock brand is a mindful/play brand. </seg>
<seg id="180"> Those are juxtaposed very nicely together. </seg>
<seg id="181"> And I think there's almost a paradox with those. </seg>
<seg id="182"> And I think some companies will just focus on one of their strengths or the other instead of focusing on both. </seg>
<seg id="183"> Most companies tend to -- and it's human nature -- to avoid things that they're not sure of, avoid fear, those elements, and you really embrace those, and you actually turn them into positives for you, and it's a neat thing to see. </seg>
<seg id="184"> What other brands are like that? </seg>
<seg id="185"> The first on here is the classic, Apple. </seg>
<seg id="186"> And you can see here too, Target, Wii, Mini from the Mini Coopers, and JetBlue. </seg>
<seg id="187"> Now there's playful brands and mindful brands, those things that have come and gone, but a playful, mindful brand is a pretty powerful thing. </seg>
<seg id="188"> A playful, mindful brand. What is your brand? </seg>
<seg id="189"> If somebody asked you to describe your brand identity, your brand personality, what would you be? </seg>
<seg id="190"> Are you an up attribute? Are you something that gets the blood flowing? </seg>
<seg id="191"> Or are you more of a down attribute? </seg>
<seg id="192"> Are you something that's a little more calm, reserved, conservative? </seg>
<seg id="193"> Up attributes are things like being playful, being fresh like the Fresh Prince, contemporary, adventurous, edgy or daring like Errol Flynn, nimble or agile, profane, domineering, magical or mystical like Gandalf. </seg>
<seg id="194"> Or are you more of a down attribute? </seg>
<seg id="195"> Are you mindful, sophisticated like 007? </seg>
<seg id="196"> Are you established, traditional, nurturing, protective, empathetic like the Oprah? </seg>
<seg id="197"> Are you reliable, stable, familiar, safe, secure, sacred, contemplative or wise like the Dalai Lama or Yoda? </seg>
<seg id="198"> Over the course of this film, we had 500-plus companies who were up and down companies saying, "no," they didn't want any part of this project. </seg>
<seg id="199"> They wanted nothing to do with this film, mainly because they would have no control, they would have no control over the final product. </seg>
<seg id="200"> But we did get 17 brand partners who were willing to relinquish that control, who wanted to be in business with someone as mindful and as playful as myself and who ultimately empowered us to tell stories that normally we wouldn't be able to tell -- stories that an advertiser would normally never get behind. </seg>
<seg id="201"> They enabled us to tell the story about neuromarketing, as we got into telling the story in this film about how now they're using MRI's to target the desire centers of your brain for both commercials as well as movie marketing. </seg>
<seg id="202"> We went to San Paulo where they have banned outdoor advertising. </seg>
<seg id="203"> In the entire city for the past five years, there's no billboards, there's no posters, there's no fliers, nothing. </seg>
<seg id="204"> And we went to school districts where now companies are making their way into cash-strapped schools all across America. </seg>
<seg id="205"> What's incredible for me is the projects that I've gotten the most feedback out of, or I've had the most success in, are ones where I've interacted with things directly. </seg>
<seg id="206"> And that's what these brands did. </seg>
<seg id="207"> They cut out the middleman, they cut out their agencies and said, "Maybe these agencies don't have my best interest in mind. </seg>
<seg id="208"> I'm going to deal directly with the artist. </seg>
<seg id="209"> I'm going to work with him to create something different, something that's going to get people thinking, that's going to challenge the way we look at the world." </seg>
<seg id="210"> And how has that been for them? Has it been successful? </seg>
<seg id="211"> Well, since the film premiered at the Sundance Film Festival, let's take a look. </seg>
<seg id="212"> According to Burrelles, the movie premiered in January, and since then -- and this isn't even the whole thing -- we've had 900 million media impressions for this film. </seg>
<seg id="213"> That's literally covering just like a two and a half-week period. </seg>
<seg id="214"> That's only online -- no print, no TV. </seg>
<seg id="215"> The film hasn't even been distributed yet. </seg>
<seg id="216"> It's not even online. It's not even streaming. </seg>
<seg id="217"> It's not even been out into other foreign countries yet. </seg>
<seg id="218"> So ultimately, this film has already started to gain a lot of momentum. </seg>
<seg id="219"> And not bad for a project that almost every ad agency we talked to advised their clients not to take part. </seg>
<seg id="220"> What I always believe is that if you take chances, if you take risks, that in those risks will come opportunity. </seg>
<seg id="221"> I believe that when you push people away from that, you're pushing them more towards failure. </seg>
<seg id="222"> I believe that when you train your employees to be risk averse, then you're preparing your whole company to be reward challenged. </seg>
<seg id="223"> I feel like that what has to happen moving forward is we need to encourage people to take risks. </seg>
<seg id="224"> We need to encourage people to not be afraid of opportunities that may scare them. </seg>
<seg id="225"> Ultimately, moving forward, I think we have to embrace fear. </seg>
<seg id="226"> We've got to put that bear in a cage. </seg>
<seg id="227"> Embrace fear. Embrace risk. </seg>
<seg id="228"> One big spoonful at a time, we have to embrace risk. </seg>
<seg id="229"> And ultimately, we have to embrace transparency. </seg>
<seg id="230"> Today, more than ever, a little honesty is going to go a long way. </seg>
<seg id="231"> And that being said, through honesty and transparency, my entire talk, "Embrace Transparency," has been brought to you by my good friends at EMC, who for $7,100 bought the naming rights on eBay. </seg>
<seg id="232"> Turning big data into big opportunity for organizations all over the world. </seg>
<seg id="233"> EMC presents: "Embrace Transparency." </seg>
<seg id="234"> Thank you very much, guys. </seg>
<seg id="235"> So, Morgan, in the name of transparency, what exactly happened to that $7,100? </seg>
<seg id="236"> That is a fantastic question. </seg>
<seg id="237"> I have in my pocket a check made out to the parent organization to the TED organization, the Sapling Foundation -- a check for $7,100 to be applied toward my attendance for next year's TED. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1144" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/amit_sood_building_a_museum_of_museums_on_the_web.html</url>
<description>Imagine being able to see artwork in the greatest museums around the world without leaving your chair. Driven by his passion for art, Amit Sood tells the story of how he developed Art Project to let people do just that.</description>
<keywords>art,arts,design,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1144</talkid>
<title>Amit Sood: Building a museum of museums on the web</title>
<seg id="1"> My name is Amit. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And 18 months ago, I had another job at Google, and I pitched this idea of doing something with museums and art to my boss who's actually here, and she allowed me to do it. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And it took 18 months. </seg>
<seg id="4"> A lot of fun, negotiations and stories, I can tell you, with 17 very interesting museums from nine countries. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But I'm going to focus on the demo. </seg>
<seg id="6"> There are a lot of stories about why we did this. </seg>
<seg id="7"> I think my personal story is explained very simply on the slide, and it's access. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And I grew up in India. </seg>
<seg id="9"> I had a great education -- I'm not complaining -- but I didn't have access to a lot of these museums and these artworks. </seg>
<seg id="10"> And so when I started traveling and going to these museums, I started learning a lot. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And while working at Google, I tried to put this desire to make it more accessible with technology together. </seg>
<seg id="12"> So we formed a team, a great team of people, and we started doing this. </seg>
<seg id="13"> I'm going to probably get into the demo and then tell you a couple of the interesting things we've had since launch. </seg>
<seg id="14"> So, simple: you come to GoogleArtProject.com. </seg>
<seg id="15"> You look around at all these museums here. </seg>
<seg id="16"> You've got the Uffizi, you've got the MoMA, the Hermitage, the Rijks, the Van Gogh. </seg>
<seg id="17"> I'm going to actually get to one of my favorites, the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Two ways of going in -- very simple. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Click and, bang, you're in this museum. </seg>
<seg id="20"> It doesn't matter where you are -- Bombay, Mexico, it doesn't really matter. </seg>
<seg id="21"> You move around, you have fun. </seg>
<seg id="22"> You want to navigate around the museum? </seg>
<seg id="23"> Open the plan up, and, in one click, jump. </seg>
<seg id="24"> You're in there, you want to go to the end of the corridor. </seg>
<seg id="25"> Keep going. Have fun. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Explore. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Thanks. I haven't come to the best part. </seg>
<seg id="28"> So now I'm in front of one of my favorite paintings, "The Harvesters" by Pieter Bruegel at the Met. </seg>
<seg id="29"> I see this plus sign. </seg>
<seg id="30"> If the museum has given us the image, you click on it. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Now this is one of the images. </seg>
<seg id="32"> So this is all of the meta-data information. </seg>
<seg id="33"> For those of you who are truly interested in art, you can click this -- but I'm going to click this off right now. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And this is one of these images that we captured in what we call gigapixel technology. </seg>
<seg id="35"> So this image, for example, has close to, I think, around 10 billion pixels. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And I get a lot of people asking me: "What do you get for 10 billion pixels?" </seg>
<seg id="37"> So I'm going to try and show you what you really get for 10 billion pixels. </seg>
<seg id="38"> You can zoom around very simply. </seg>
<seg id="39"> You see some fun stuff happening here. </seg>
<seg id="40"> I love this guy; his expression is priceless. </seg>
<seg id="41"> But then you really want to go deep. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And so I started playing around, and I found something going on over here. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And I was like, "Hold on. That sounds interesting." </seg>
<seg id="44"> Went in, and I started noticing that these kids were actually beating something. </seg>
<seg id="45"> I did a little research, spoke to a couple of my contacts at the Met, and actually found out that this is a game called squall, which involves beating a goose with a stick on Shrove Tuesday. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And apparently it was quite popular. </seg>
<seg id="47"> I don't know why they did it, but I learned something about it. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Now just to get really deep in, you can really get to the cracks. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Now just to give you some perspective, I'm going to zoom out so you really see what you get. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Here is where we were, and this is the painting. </seg>
<seg id="51"> The best is yet to come -- so in a second. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So now let's just quickly jump into the MoMA, again in New York. </seg>
<seg id="53"> So another one of my favorites, "The Starry Night." </seg>
<seg id="54"> Now the example I showed you was all about finding details. </seg>
<seg id="55"> But what if you want to see brush strokes? </seg>
<seg id="56"> And what if you want to see how Van Gogh actually created this masterpiece? </seg>
<seg id="57"> You zoom in. You really go in. </seg>
<seg id="58"> I'm going to go to one of my favorite parts in this painting, and I'm really going to get to the cracks. </seg>
<seg id="59"> This is "The Starry Night," I think, never seen like this before. </seg>
<seg id="60"> I'm going to show you my other favorite feature. </seg>
<seg id="61"> There's a lot of other stuff here, but I don't have time. </seg>
<seg id="62"> This is the real cool part. It's called Collections. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Any one of you, anybody -- doesn't matter if you're rich, if you're poor, if you have a fancy house -- doesn't matter. </seg>
<seg id="64"> You can go and create your own museum online -- create your own collection across all these images. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Very simply, you go in -- and I've created this, called The Power of Zoom -- you can just zoom around. </seg>
<seg id="66"> This is "The Ambassadors," based in the National Gallery. </seg>
<seg id="67"> You can annotate the stuff, send it to your friends and really get a conversation going about what you're feeling when you go through these masterpieces. </seg>
<seg id="68"> So I think, in conclusion, for me, the main thing is that all the amazing stuff here does not really come from Google. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It doesn't, in my opinion, even come from the museums. </seg>
<seg id="70"> I probably shouldn't say that. </seg>
<seg id="71"> It really comes from these artists. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And that's been my humbling experience in this. </seg>
<seg id="73"> I mean, I hope in this digital medium that we do justice to their artwork and represent it properly online. </seg>
<seg id="74"> And the biggest question I get asked nowadays is, "Did you do this to replicate the experience of going to a museum?" </seg>
<seg id="75"> And the answer is no. </seg>
<seg id="76"> It's to supplement the experience. </seg>
<seg id="77"> And that's it. Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1160" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/aaron_o_connell_making_sense_of_a_visible_quantum_object.html</url>
<description>Physicists are used to the idea that subatomic particles behave according to the bizarre rules of quantum mechanics, completely different to human-scale objects. In a breakthrough experiment, Aaron O'Connell has blurred that distinction by creating an object that is visible to the unaided eye, but provably in two places at the same time. In this talk he suggests an intriguing way of thinking about the result.</description>
<keywords>philosophy,physics,science</keywords>
<talkid>1160</talkid>
<title>Aaron O'Connell: Making sense of a visible quantum object</title>
<seg id="1"> This is a representation of your brain, and your brain can be broken into two parts. </seg>
<seg id="2"> There's the left half, which is the logical side, and then the right half, which is the intuitive. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And so if we had a scale to measure the aptitude of each hemisphere, then we can plot our brain. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And for example, this would be somebody who's completely logical. </seg>
<seg id="5"> This would be someone who's entirely intuitive. </seg>
<seg id="6"> So where would you put your brain on this scale? </seg>
<seg id="7"> Some of us may have opted for one of these extremes, but I think for most people in the audience, your brain is something like this -- with a high aptitude in both hemispheres at the same time. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It's not like they're mutually exclusive or anything. </seg>
<seg id="9"> You can be logical and intuitive. </seg>
<seg id="10"> And so I consider myself one of these people, along with most of the other experimental quantum physicists, who need a good deal of logic to string together these complex ideas. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But at the same time, we need a good deal of intuition to actually make the experiments work. </seg>
<seg id="12"> How do we develop this intuition? Well we like to play with stuff. </seg>
<seg id="13"> So we go out and play with it, and then we see how it acts, and then we develop our intuition from there. </seg>
<seg id="14"> And really you do the same thing. </seg>
<seg id="15"> So some intuition that you may have developed over the years is that one thing is only in one place at a time. </seg>
<seg id="16"> I mean, it can sound weird to think about one thing being in two different places at the same time, but you weren't born with this notion, you developed it. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And I remember watching a kid playing on a car stop. </seg>
<seg id="18"> He was just a toddler and he wasn't very good at it, and he kept falling over. </seg>
<seg id="19"> But I bet playing with this car stop taught him a really valuable lesson, and that's that large things don't let you get right past them, and that they stay in one place. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And so this is a great conceptual model to have of the world, unless you're a particle physicist. </seg>
<seg id="21"> It'd be a terrible model for a particle physicist, because they don't play with car stops, they play with these little weird particles. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And when they play with their particles, they find they do all sorts of really weird things -- like they can fly right through walls, or they can be in two different places at the same time. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And so they wrote down all these observations, and they called it the theory of quantum mechanics. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And so that's where physics was at a few years ago; you needed quantum mechanics to describe little, tiny particles. </seg>
<seg id="25"> But you didn't need it to describe the large, everyday objects around us. </seg>
<seg id="26"> This didn't really sit well with my intuition, and maybe it's just because I don't play with particles very often. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Well, I play with them sometimes, but not very often. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And I've never seen them. </seg>
<seg id="29"> I mean, nobody's ever seen a particle. </seg>
<seg id="30"> But it didn't sit well with my logical side either. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Because if everything is made up of little particles and all the little particles follow quantum mechanics, then shouldn't everything just follow quantum mechanics? </seg>
<seg id="32"> I don't see any reason why it shouldn't. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And so I'd feel a lot better about the whole thing if we could somehow show that an everyday object also follows quantum mechanics. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So a few years ago, I set off to do just that. </seg>
<seg id="35"> So I made one. </seg>
<seg id="36"> This is the first object that you can see that has been in a mechanical quantum superposition. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So what we're looking at here is a tiny computer chip. </seg>
<seg id="38"> And you can sort of see this green dot right in the middle. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And that's this piece of metal I'm going to be talking about in a minute. </seg>
<seg id="40"> This is a photograph of the object. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And here I'll zoom in a little bit. We're looking right there in the center. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And then here's a really, really big close-up of the little piece of metal. </seg>
<seg id="43"> So what we're looking at is a little chunk of metal, and it's shaped like a diving board, and it's sticking out over a ledge. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And so I made this thing in nearly the same way as you make a computer chip. </seg>
<seg id="45"> I went into a clean room with a fresh silicon wafer, and then I just cranked away at all the big machines for about 100 hours. </seg>
<seg id="46"> For the last stuff, I had to build my own machine -- to make this swimming pool-shaped hole underneath the device. </seg>
<seg id="47"> This device has the ability to be in a quantum superposition, but it needs a little help to do it. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Here, let me give you an analogy. </seg>
<seg id="49"> You know how uncomfortable it is to be in a crowded elevator? </seg>
<seg id="50"> I mean, when I'm in an elevator all alone, I do all sorts of weird things, but then other people get on board and I stop doing those things because I don't want to bother them, or, frankly, scare them. </seg>
<seg id="51"> So quantum mechanics says that inanimate objects feel the same way. </seg>
<seg id="52"> The fellow passengers for inanimate objects are not just people, but it's also the light shining on it and the wind blowing past it and the heat of the room. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And so we knew, if we wanted to see this piece of metal behave quantum mechanically, we're going to have to kick out all the other passengers. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And so that's what we did. </seg>
<seg id="55"> We turned off the lights, and then we put it in a vacuum and sucked out all the air, and then we cooled it down Now, all alone in the elevator, the little chunk of metal is free to act however it wanted. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And so we measured its motion. </seg>
<seg id="57"> We found it was moving in really weird ways. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Instead of just sitting perfectly still, it was vibrating, and the way it was vibrating was breathing something like this -- like expanding and contracting bellows. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And by giving it a gentle nudge, we were able to make it both vibrate and not vibrate at the same time -- something that's only allowed with quantum mechanics. </seg>
<seg id="60"> So what I'm telling you here is something truly fantastic. </seg>
<seg id="61"> What does it mean for one thing to be both vibrating and not vibrating at the same time? </seg>
<seg id="62"> So let's think about the atoms. </seg>
<seg id="63"> So in one case: all the trillions of atoms that make up that chunk of metal are sitting still and at the same time those same atoms are moving up and down. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Now it's only at precise times when they align. </seg>
<seg id="65"> The rest of the time they're delocalized. </seg>
<seg id="66"> That means that every atom is in two different places at the same time, which in turn means the entire chunk of metal is in two different places. </seg>
<seg id="67"> I think this is really cool. </seg>
<seg id="68"> Really. </seg>
<seg id="69"> It was worth locking myself in a clean room to do this for all those years because, check this out, the difference in scale between a single atom and that chunk of metal is about the same as the difference between that chunk of metal and you. </seg>
<seg id="70"> So if a single atom can be in two different places at the same time, that chunk of metal can be in two different places, then why not you? </seg>
<seg id="71"> I mean, this is just my logical side talking. </seg>
<seg id="72"> So imagine if you're in multiple places at the same time, what would that be like? </seg>
<seg id="73"> How would your consciousness handle your body being delocalized in space? </seg>
<seg id="74"> There's one more part to the story. </seg>
<seg id="75"> It's when we warmed it up, and we turned on the lights and looked inside the box, we saw that the piece metal was still there in one piece. </seg>
<seg id="76"> And so I had to develop this new intuition, that it seems like all the objects in the elevator are really just quantum objects just crammed into a tiny space. </seg>
<seg id="77"> You hear a lot of talk about how quantum mechanics says that everything is all interconnected. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Well, that's not quite right. </seg>
<seg id="79"> It's more than that; it's deeper. </seg>
<seg id="80"> It's that those connections, your connections to all the things around you, literally define who you are, and that's the profound weirdness of quantum mechanics. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1165" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/paul_romer_the_world_s_first_charter_city.html</url>
<description>Back in 2009, Paul Romer unveiled the idea for a "charter city" -- a new kind of city with rules that favor democracy and trade. This year, at TED2011, he tells the story of how such a city might just happen in Honduras ... with a little help from his TEDTalk.</description>
<keywords>business,cities,culture,design,global issues,politics</keywords>
<talkid>1165</talkid>
<title>Paul Romer: The world's first charter city?</title>
<seg id="1"> In 2007, I decided that we needed to reconceptualize how we thought about economic development. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Our new goal should be that when every family thinks about where they want to live and work, they should be able to choose between at least a handful of different cities that were all competing to attract new residents. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Now we're a long way away from that goal right now. </seg>
<seg id="4"> There are billions of people in developing countries who don't have even a single city that would be willing to welcome them. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But the amazing thing about cities is they're worth so much more than it costs to build them. </seg>
<seg id="6"> So we could easily supply the world with dozens, maybe hundreds, of new cities. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Now this might sound preposterous to you if you've never thought about new cities. </seg>
<seg id="8"> But just substitute apartment building for cities. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Imagine half the people who wanted to be in apartments already had them; the other half aren't there yet. </seg>
<seg id="10"> You could try and expand the capacity by doing additions on all the existing apartments. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But you know what you'd run into is those apartments and the surrounding areas have rules to avoid discomfort and the distractions of construction. </seg>
<seg id="12"> So it's extremely hard to do all of those additions. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But you could go out someplace brand new, build a brand new apartment building, as long as the rules there were ones that facilitated construction rather than getting in the way. </seg>
<seg id="14"> So I proposed that governments create new reform zones big enough to hold cities and gave them a name: charter cities. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Later I learned that at about this same time, Javier and Octavio were thinking about the challenge of reform in Honduras. </seg>
<seg id="16"> They knew that about 75,000 Hondurans every year would leave to go to the United States, and they wanted to ask, what could they do to make sure that those people could stay and do the same things in Honduras. </seg>
<seg id="17"> At one point, Javier said to Octavio, "What if we took some of our empty land -- what if we just gave it to an embassy -- give some to the U.S. embassy; give some to the Canadian embassy -- and then if people want to go work under the rules of Canada or under the rules of the United States, they can go get jobs, do everything they do on those embassy grounds that they would otherwise have to go to Canada or the U.S. to do?" </seg>
<seg id="18"> In the summer of 2009, Honduras went through a wrenching constitutional crisis. </seg>
<seg id="19"> At the next regularly scheduled election, Pepe Lobo won in a landslide on a platform that promised reform, but reconciliation as well. </seg>
<seg id="20"> He asked Octavio to be his chief of staff. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Meanwhile, I was getting ready to give a talk at TEDGlobal. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Through a process of refinement, trial and error, a lot of user testing, I tried to boil this complicated concept of charter city down to the bare essentials. </seg>
<seg id="23"> The first point was the importance of rules, like those rules that say you can't come in and disturb all the existing apartment holders. </seg>
<seg id="24"> We pay a lot of attention to new technologies, but it takes technologies and rules to get progress, and it's usually the rules that hold us back. </seg>
<seg id="25"> In the fall of 2010, a friend from Guatemala sent Octavio a link to the TEDTalk. </seg>
<seg id="26"> He showed it to Javier. </seg>
<seg id="27"> They called me. </seg>
<seg id="28"> They said, "Let's present this to the leaders of our country." </seg>
<seg id="29"> So in December we met in Miami, in a hotel conference room. </seg>
<seg id="30"> I tried to explain this point about how valuable cities are, how much more valuable they are than they cost. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And I used this slide showing how valuable the raw land is in a place like New York City: notice, land that's worth thousands of dollars, in some cases, per square meter. </seg>
<seg id="32"> But it was a fairly abstract discussion, and at some point when there was a pause, Octavio said, "Paul, maybe we could watch the TEDTalk." </seg>
<seg id="33"> So the TEDTalk laid out in very simple terms, a charter city is a place where you start with uninhabited land, a charter that specifies the rules that will apply there and then a chance for people to opt in, to go live under those rules or not. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So I was asked by the president of Honduras who said that we need to do this project, this is important, this could be the way forward for our country. </seg>
<seg id="35"> I was asked to come to Tegucigalpa and talk again on January fourth and fifth. </seg>
<seg id="36"> So I presented another fact-filled lecture that included a slide like this, which tried to make the point that, if you want to create a lot of value in a city, it has to be very big. </seg>
<seg id="37"> This is a picture of Denver, and the outline is the new airport that was built in Denver. </seg>
<seg id="38"> This airport alone covers more than 100 square kilometers. </seg>
<seg id="39"> So I was trying to persuade the Hondurans, if you build a new city, you've got to start with a site that's at least 1,000 square kilometers. </seg>
<seg id="40"> That's more than 250 hundred-thousand acres. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Everybody applauded politely. </seg>
<seg id="42"> The faces in the audience were very serious and attentive. </seg>
<seg id="43"> The leader of the congress came up on stage and said, "Professor Romer, thank you very much for your lecture, but maybe we could watch the TEDTalk. </seg>
<seg id="44"> I've got it here on my laptop." </seg>
<seg id="45"> So I sat down, and they played the TEDTalk. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And it got to the essence, which is that a new city could offer new choices for people. </seg>
<seg id="47"> There would be a choice of a city which you could go to which could be in Honduras, instead of hundreds of miles away in the North. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And it also involved new choices for leaders. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Because the leaders in the government there in Honduras would need help from partner countries, who could benefit from partner countries who help them set up the rules in this charter and the enforcement, so everybody can trust that the charter really will be enforced. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And the insight of President Lobo was that that assurance of enforcement that I was thinking about as a way to get the foreign investors to come in and build the city could be equally important for all the different parties in Honduras who had suffered for so many years from fear and distrust. </seg>
<seg id="51"> We went and looked at a site. </seg>
<seg id="52"> This picture's from there. </seg>
<seg id="53"> It easily could hold a thousand square kilometers. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And shortly thereafter, on January 19th, they voted in the congress to amend their constitution to have a constitutional provision that allows for special development regions. </seg>
<seg id="55"> In a country which had just gone through this wrenching crisis, the vote in the congress in favor of this constitutional amendment was 124 to one. </seg>
<seg id="56"> All parties, all factions in society, backed this. </seg>
<seg id="57"> To be part of the constitution, you actually have to pass it twice in the congress. </seg>
<seg id="58"> On February 17th they passed it again with another vote of 114 to one. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Immediately after that vote, on February 21st to the 24th, a delegation of about 30 Hondurans went to the two places in the world that are most interested in getting into the city building business. </seg>
<seg id="60"> One is South Korea. </seg>
<seg id="61"> This is a picture of a big, new city center that's being built in South Korea -- bigger than downtown Boston. </seg>
<seg id="62"> Everything you see there was built in four years, after they spent four years getting the permits. </seg>
<seg id="63"> The other place that's very interested in city building is Singapore. </seg>
<seg id="64"> They've actually built two cities already in China and are preparing the third. </seg>
<seg id="65"> So if you think about this practically, here's where we are. </seg>
<seg id="66"> They've got a site; they're already thinking about this site for the second city. </seg>
<seg id="67"> They're putting in place a legal system that could allow for managers to come in, and also an external legal system. </seg>
<seg id="68"> One country has already volunteered to let its supreme court be the court of final appeal for the new judicial system there. </seg>
<seg id="69"> There's designers and builders of cities who are very interested. </seg>
<seg id="70"> They even can bring with them some financing. </seg>
<seg id="71"> But the one thing you know they've already solved is that there's lots of tenants. </seg>
<seg id="72"> There's lots of businesses that would like to locate in the Americas, especially in a place with a free trade zone, and there's lots of people who'd like to go there. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Around the world, there's 700 million people who say they'd like to move permanently someplace else right now. </seg>
<seg id="74"> There's a million a year who leave Latin America to go to the United States. </seg>
<seg id="75"> Many of these are a father who has to leave his family behind to go get a job -- sometimes a single mother who has to get enough money to even pay for food or clothing. </seg>
<seg id="76"> Sadly, sometimes there are even children who are trying to get reunited with their parents that they haven't seen, in some cases, for a decade. </seg>
<seg id="77"> So what kind of an idea is it to think about building a brand new city in Honduras? </seg>
<seg id="78"> Or to build a dozen of these, or a hundred of these, around the world? </seg>
<seg id="79"> What kind of an idea is it to think about insisting that every family have a choice of several cities that are competing to attract new residents? </seg>
<seg id="80"> This is an idea worth spreading. </seg>
<seg id="81"> And my friends from Honduras asked me to say thank you, TED. </seg>
</doc>
</refset>
</mteval>
