<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<refset setid="iwslt2014-tst2012" srclang="german" trglang="english" refid="ref">
<doc docid="1330" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/sheena_iyengar_choosing_what_to_choose.html</url>
<description>We all want customized experiences and products -- but when faced with 700 options, consumers freeze up. With fascinating new research, Sheena Iyengar demonstrates how businesses can improve the experience of choosing.</description>
<keywords>business,choice,culture,marketing</keywords>
<talkid>1330</talkid>
<title>Sheena Iyengar: How to make choosing easier</title>
<seg id="1"> Do you know how many choices you make in a typical day? </seg>
<seg id="2"> Do you know how many choices you make in typical week? </seg>
<seg id="3"> I recently did a survey with over 2,000 Americans, and the average number of choices that the typical American reports making is about 70 in a typical day. </seg>
<seg id="4"> There was also recently a study done with CEOs in which they followed CEOs around for a whole week. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And these scientists simply documented all the various tasks that these CEOs engaged in and how much time they spent engaging in making decisions related to these tasks. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And they found that the average CEO engaged in about 139 tasks in a week. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Each task was made up of many, many, many sub-choices of course. </seg>
<seg id="8"> 50 percent of their decisions were made in nine minutes or less. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Only about 12 percent of the decisions did they make an hour or more of their time. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Think about your own choices. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Do you know how many choices make it into your nine minute category versus your one hour category? </seg>
<seg id="12"> How well do you think you're doing at managing those choices? </seg>
<seg id="13"> Today I want to talk about one of the biggest modern day choosing problems that we have, which is the choice overload problem. </seg>
<seg id="14"> I want to talk about the problem and some potential solutions. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Now as I talk about this problem, I'm going to have some questions for you and I'm going to want to know your answers. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So when I ask you a question, since I'm blind, only raise your hand if you want to burn off some calories. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Otherwise, when I ask you a question, and if your answer is yes, So for my first question for you today: Are you guys ready to hear about the choice overload problem? </seg>
<seg id="18"> Thank you. </seg>
<seg id="19"> So when I was a graduate student at Stanford University, I used to go to this very, very upscale grocery store; at least at that time it was truly upscale. </seg>
<seg id="20"> It was a store called Draeger's. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Now this store, it was almost like going to an amusement park. </seg>
<seg id="22"> They had 250 different kinds of mustards and vinegars and over 500 different kinds of fruits and vegetables and more than two dozen different kinds of bottled water -- and this was during a time when we actually used to drink tap water. </seg>
<seg id="23"> I used to love going to this store, but on one occasion I asked myself, well how come you never buy anything? </seg>
<seg id="24"> Here's their olive oil aisle. </seg>
<seg id="25"> They had over 75 different kinds of olive oil, including those that were in a locked case that came from thousand-year-old olive trees. </seg>
<seg id="26"> So I one day decided to pay a visit to the manager, and I asked the manager, "Is this model of offering people all this choice really working?" </seg>
<seg id="27"> And he pointed to the busloads of tourists that would show up everyday, with cameras ready usually. </seg>
<seg id="28"> We decided to do a little experiment, and we picked jam for our experiment. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Here's their jam aisle. </seg>
<seg id="30"> They had 348 different kinds of jam. </seg>
<seg id="31"> We set up a little tasting booth right near the entrance of the store. </seg>
<seg id="32"> We there put out six different flavors of jam or 24 different flavors of jam, and we looked at two things: First, in which case were people more likely to stop, sample some jam? </seg>
<seg id="33"> More people stopped when there were 24, about 60 percent, than when there were six, about 40 percent. </seg>
<seg id="34"> The next thing we looked at is in which case were people more likely to buy a jar of jam. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Now we see the opposite effect. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Of the people who stopped when there were 24, only three percent of them actually bought a jar of jam. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Of the people who stopped when there were six, well now we saw that 30 percent of them actually bought a jar of jam. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Now if you do the math, people were at least six times more likely to buy a jar of jam if they encountered six than if they encountered 24. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Now choosing not to buy a jar of jam is probably good for us -- at least it's good for our waistlines -- but it turns out that this choice overload problem affects us even in very consequential decisions. </seg>
<seg id="40"> We choose not to choose, even when it goes against our best self-interests. </seg>
<seg id="41"> So now for the topic of today: financial savings. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Now I'm going to describe to you a study I did with Gur Huberman, Emir Kamenica, Wei Jang where we looked at the retirement savings decisions of nearly a million Americans from about 650 plans all in the U.S. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And what we looked at was whether the number of fund offerings available in a retirement savings plan, the 401 plan, does that affect people's likelihood to save more for tomorrow. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And what we found was that indeed there was a correlation. </seg>
<seg id="45"> So in these plans, we had about 657 plans that ranged from offering people anywhere from two to 59 different fund offerings. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And what we found was that, the more funds offered, indeed, there was less participation rate. </seg>
<seg id="47"> So if you look at the extremes, those plans that offered you two funds, participation rates were around in the mid-70s -- still not as high as we want it to be. </seg>
<seg id="48"> In those plans that offered nearly 60 funds, participation rates have now dropped to about the 60th percentile. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Now it turns out that even if you do choose to participate when there are more choices present, even then, it has negative consequences. </seg>
<seg id="50"> So for those people who did choose to participate, the more choices available, the more likely people were to completely avoid stocks or equity funds. </seg>
<seg id="51"> The more choices available, the more likely they were to put all their money in pure money market accounts. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Now neither of these extreme decisions are the kinds of decisions that any of us would recommend for people when you're considering their future financial well-being. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Well, over the past decade, we have observed three main negative consequences to offering people more and more choices. </seg>
<seg id="54"> They're more likely to delay choosing -- procrastinate even when it goes against their best self-interest. </seg>
<seg id="55"> They're more likely to make worse choices -- worse financial choices, medical choices. </seg>
<seg id="56"> They're more likely to choose things that make them less satisfied, even when they do objectively better. </seg>
<seg id="57"> The main reason for this is because, we might enjoy gazing at those giant walls of mayonnaises, mustards, vinegars, jams, but we can't actually do the math of comparing and contrasting and actually picking from that stunning display. </seg>
<seg id="58"> So what I want to propose to you today are four simple techniques -- techniques that we have tested in one way or another in different research venues -- that you can easily apply in your businesses. </seg>
<seg id="59"> The first: Cut. </seg>
<seg id="60"> You've heard it said before, but it's never been more true than today, that less is more. </seg>
<seg id="61"> People are always upset when I say, "Cut." </seg>
<seg id="62"> They're always worried they're going to lose shelf space. </seg>
<seg id="63"> But in fact, what we're seeing more and more is that if you are willing to cut, get rid of those extraneous redundant options, well there's an increase in sales, there's a lowering of costs, there is an improvement of the choosing experience. </seg>
<seg id="64"> When Proctor &amp; Gamble went from 26 different kinds of Head &amp; Shoulders to 15, they saw an increase in sales by 10 percent. </seg>
<seg id="65"> When the Golden Cat Corporation got rid of their 10 worst-selling cat litter products, they saw an increase in profits by 87 percent -- a function of both increase in sales and lowering of costs. </seg>
<seg id="66"> You know, the average grocery store today offers you 45,000 products. </seg>
<seg id="67"> The typical Walmart today offers you 100,000 products. </seg>
<seg id="68"> But the ninth largest retailer, the ninth biggest retailer in the world today is Aldi, and it offers you only 1,400 products -- one kind of canned tomato sauce. </seg>
<seg id="69"> Now in the financial savings world, I think one of the best examples that has recently come out on how to best manage the choice offerings has actually been something that David Laibson was heavily involved in designing, which was the program that they have at Harvard. </seg>
<seg id="70"> Every single Harvard employee is now automatically enrolled in a lifecycle fund. </seg>
<seg id="71"> For those people who actually want to choose, they're given 20 funds, not 300 or more funds. </seg>
<seg id="72"> You know, often, people say, "I don't know how to cut. </seg>
<seg id="73"> They're all important choices." </seg>
<seg id="74"> And the first thing I do is I ask the employees, "Tell me how these choices are different from one another. </seg>
<seg id="75"> And if your employees can't tell them apart, neither can your consumers." </seg>
<seg id="76"> Now before we started our session this afternoon, I had a chat with Gary. </seg>
<seg id="77"> And Gary said that he would be willing to offer people in this audience an all-expenses-paid free vacation to the most beautiful road in the world. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Here's a description of the road. </seg>
<seg id="79"> And I'd like you to read it. </seg>
<seg id="80"> And now I'll give you a few seconds to read it and then I want you to clap your hands if you're ready to take Gary up on his offer. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Okay. Anybody who's ready to take him up on his offer. </seg>
<seg id="82"> Is that all? </seg>
<seg id="83"> All right, let me show you some more about this. </seg>
<seg id="84"> You guys knew there was a trick, didn't you. </seg>
<seg id="85"> Now who's ready to go on this trip. </seg>
<seg id="86"> I think I might have actually heard more hands. </seg>
<seg id="87"> All right. </seg>
<seg id="88"> Now in fact, you had objectively more information the first time around than the second time around, but I would venture to guess that you felt that it was more real the second time around. </seg>
<seg id="89"> Because the pictures made it feel more real to you. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Which brings me to the second technique for handling the choice overload problem, which is concretization. </seg>
<seg id="91"> That in order for people to understand the differences between the choices, they have to be able to understand the consequences associated with each choice, and that the consequences need to be felt in a vivid sort of way, in a very concrete way. </seg>
<seg id="92"> Why do people spend an average of 15 to 30 percent more when they use an ATM card or a credit card as opposed to cash? </seg>
<seg id="93"> Because it doesn't feel like real money. </seg>
<seg id="94"> And it turns out that making it feel more concrete can actually be a very positive tool to use in getting people to save more. </seg>
<seg id="95"> So a study that I did with Shlomo Benartzi and Alessandro Previtero, we did a study with people at ING -- employees that are all working at ING -- and now these people were all in a session where they're doing enrollment for their 401 plan. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And during that session, we kept the session exactly the way it used to be, but we added one little thing. </seg>
<seg id="97"> The one little thing we added was we asked people to just think about all the positive things that would happen in your life if you saved more. </seg>
<seg id="98"> By doing that simple thing, there was an increase in enrollment by 20 percent and there was an increase in the amount of people willing to save or the amount that they were willing to put down into their savings account by four percent. </seg>
<seg id="99"> The third technique: Categorization. </seg>
<seg id="100"> We can handle more categories than we can handle choices. </seg>
<seg id="101"> So for example, here's a study we did in a magazine aisle. </seg>
<seg id="102"> It turns out that in Wegmans grocery stores up and down the northeast corridor, the magazine aisles range anywhere from 331 different kinds of magazines all the way up to 664. </seg>
<seg id="103"> But you know what? </seg>
<seg id="104"> If I show you 600 magazines and I divide them up into 10 categories, versus I show you 400 magazines and divide them up into 20 categories, you believe that I have given you more choice and a better choosing experience if I gave you the 400 than if I gave you the 600. </seg>
<seg id="105"> Because the categories tell me how to tell them apart. </seg>
<seg id="106"> Here are two different jewelry displays. </seg>
<seg id="107"> One is called "Jazz" and the other one is called "Swing." </seg>
<seg id="108"> If you think the display on the left is Swing and the display on the right is Jazz, clap your hands. </seg>
<seg id="109"> Okay, there's some. </seg>
<seg id="110"> If you think the one on the left is Jazz and the one on the right is Swing, clap your hands. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Okay, a bit more. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Now it turns out you're right. </seg>
<seg id="113"> The one on the left is Jazz and the one on the right is Swing, but you know what? </seg>
<seg id="114"> This is a highly useless categorization scheme. </seg>
<seg id="115"> The categories need to say something to the chooser, not the choice-maker. </seg>
<seg id="116"> And you often see that problem when it comes down to those long lists of all these funds. </seg>
<seg id="117"> Who are they actually supposed to be informing? </seg>
<seg id="118"> My fourth technique: Condition for complexity. </seg>
<seg id="119"> It turns out we can actually handle a lot more information than we think we can, we've just got to take it a little easier. </seg>
<seg id="120"> We have to gradually increase the complexity. </seg>
<seg id="121"> I'm going to show you one example of what I'm talking about. </seg>
<seg id="122"> Let's take a very, very complicated decision: buying a car. </seg>
<seg id="123"> Here's a German car manufacturer that gives you the opportunity to completely custom make your car. </seg>
<seg id="124"> You've got to make 60 different decisions, completely make up your car. </seg>
<seg id="125"> Now these decisions vary in the number of choices that they offer per decision. </seg>
<seg id="126"> Car colors, exterior car colors -- I've got 56 choices. </seg>
<seg id="127"> Engines, gearshift -- four choices. </seg>
<seg id="128"> So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to vary the order in which these decisions appear. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So half of the customers are going to go from high choice, 56 car colors, to low choice, four gearshifts. </seg>
<seg id="130"> The other half of the customers are going to go from low choice, four gearshifts, to 56 car colors, high choice. </seg>
<seg id="131"> What am I going to look at? </seg>
<seg id="132"> How engaged you are. </seg>
<seg id="133"> If you keep hitting the default button per decision, that means you're getting overwhelmed, that means I'm losing you. </seg>
<seg id="134"> What you find is the people who go from high choice to low choice, they're hitting that default button over and over and over again. </seg>
<seg id="135"> We're losing them. </seg>
<seg id="136"> They go from low choice to high choice, they're hanging in there. </seg>
<seg id="137"> It's the same information. It's the same number of choices. </seg>
<seg id="138"> The only thing that I have done is I have varied the order in which that information is presented. </seg>
<seg id="139"> If I start you off easy, I learn how to choose. </seg>
<seg id="140"> Even though choosing gearshift doesn't tell me anything about my preferences for interior decor, it still prepares me for how to choose. </seg>
<seg id="141"> It also gets me excited about this big product that I'm putting together, so I'm more willing to be motivated to be engaged. </seg>
<seg id="142"> So let me recap. </seg>
<seg id="143"> I have talked about four techniques for mitigating the problem of choice overload -- cut -- get rid of the extraneous alternatives; concretize -- make it real; categorize -- we can handle more categories, less choices; condition for complexity. </seg>
<seg id="144"> All of these techniques that I'm describing to you today are designed to help you manage your choices -- better for you, you can use them on yourself, better for the people that you are serving. </seg>
<seg id="145"> Because I believe that the key to getting the most from choice is to be choosy about choosing. </seg>
<seg id="146"> And the more we're able to be choosy about choosing the better we will be able to practice the art of choosing. </seg>
<seg id="147"> Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1371" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/kevin_allocca_why_videos_go_viral.html</url>
<description>Kevin Allocca is YouTube's trends manager, and he has deep thoughts about silly web video. In this talk from TEDYouth, he shares the 4 reasons a video goes viral. </description>
<keywords>entertainment,video</keywords>
<talkid>1371</talkid>
<title>Kevin Allocca: Why videos go viral</title>
<seg id="1"> Hi. I'm Kevin Allocca, I'm the trends manager at YouTube, and I professionally watch YouTube videos. </seg>
<seg id="2"> It's true. </seg>
<seg id="3"> So we're going to talk a little bit today about how videos go viral and then why that even matters. </seg>
<seg id="4"> We all want to be stars -- celebrities, singers, comedians -- and when I was younger, that seemed so very, very hard to do. </seg>
<seg id="5"> But now Web video has made it so that any of us or any of the creative things that we do can become completely famous in a part of our world's culture. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Any one of you could be famous on the Internet by next Saturday. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But there are over 48 hours of video uploaded to YouTube every minute. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And of that, only a tiny percentage ever goes viral and gets tons of views and becomes a cultural moment. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So how does it happen? </seg>
<seg id="10"> Three things: tastemakers, communities of participation and unexpectedness. </seg>
<seg id="11"> All right, let's go. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Oh, my God. Oh, my God. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Oh, my God! </seg>
<seg id="14"> Wooo! </seg>
<seg id="15"> Ohhhhh, wowwww! </seg>
<seg id="16"> Last year, Bear Vasquez posted this video that he had shot outside his home in Yosemite National Park. </seg>
<seg id="17"> In 2010, it was viewed 23 million times. </seg>
<seg id="18"> This is a chart of what it looked like when it first became popular last summer. </seg>
<seg id="19"> But he didn't actually set out to make a viral video, Bear. </seg>
<seg id="20"> He just wanted to share a rainbow. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Because that's what you do when your name is Yosemite Mountain Bear. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And he had posted lots of nature videos in fact. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And this video had actually been posted all the way back in January. </seg>
<seg id="24"> So what happened here? </seg>
<seg id="25"> Jimmy Kimmel actually. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Jimmy Kimmel posted this tweet that would eventually propel the video to be as popular as it would become. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Because tastemakers like Jimmy Kimmel introduce us to new and interesting things and bring them to a larger audience. </seg>
<seg id="28"> It's Friday, Friday. Gotta get down on Friday. Everybody's looking forward to the weekend, weekend. Friday, Friday. Gettin' down on Friday. So you didn't think that we could actually have this conversation without talking about this video I hope. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Rebecca Black's "Friday" is one of the most popular videos of the year. </seg>
<seg id="30"> It's been seen nearly 200 million times this year. </seg>
<seg id="31"> This is a chart of what it looked like. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And similar to "Double Rainbow," it seems to have just sprouted up out of nowhere. </seg>
<seg id="33"> So what happened on this day? </seg>
<seg id="34"> Well it was a Friday, this is true. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And if you're wondering about those other spikes, those are also Fridays. </seg>
<seg id="36"> But what about this day, this one particular Friday? </seg>
<seg id="37"> Well Tosh.0 picked it up, a lot of blogs starting writing about. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Michael J. Nelson from Mystery Science Theater was one of the first people to post a joke about the video on Twitter. </seg>
<seg id="39"> But what's important is that an individual or a group of tastemakers took a point of view and they shared that with a larger audience, accelerating the process. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And so then this community formed of people who shared this big inside joke and they started talking about it and doing things with it. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And now there are 10,000 parodies of "Friday" on YouTube. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Even in the first seven days, there was one parody for every other day of the week. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Unlike the one-way entertainment of the 20th century, this community participation is how we become a part of the phenomenon -- either by spreading it or by doing something new with it. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So "Nyan Cat" is a looped animation with looped music. </seg>
<seg id="45"> It's this, just like this. </seg>
<seg id="46"> It's been viewed nearly 50 million times this year. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And if you think that that is weird, you should know that there is a three-hour version of this that's been viewed four million times. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Even cats were watching this video. </seg>
<seg id="49"> Cats were watching other cats watch this video. </seg>
<seg id="50"> But what's important here is the creativity that it inspired amongst this techie, geeky Internet culture. </seg>
<seg id="51"> There were remixes. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Someone made an old timey version. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And then it went international. </seg>
<seg id="54"> An entire remix community sprouted up that brought it from being just a stupid joke to something that we can all actually be a part of. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Because we don't just enjoy now, we participate. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And who could have predicted any of this? </seg>
<seg id="57"> Who could have predicted "Double Rainbow" or Rebecca Black or "Nyan Cat?" </seg>
<seg id="58"> What scripts could you have written that would have contained this in it? </seg>
<seg id="59"> In a world where over two days of video get uploaded every minute, only that which is truly unique and unexpected can stand out in the way that these things have. </seg>
<seg id="60"> When a friend of mine told me that I needed to see this great video about a guy protesting bicycle fines in New York City, I admit I wasn't very interested. </seg>
<seg id="61"> So I got a ticket for not riding in the bike lane, but often there are obstructions that keep you from properly riding in the bike lane. </seg>
<seg id="62"> By being totally surprising and humorous, Casey Niestat got his funny idea and point seen five million times. </seg>
<seg id="63"> And so this approach holds for anything new that we do creatively. </seg>
<seg id="64"> And so it all brings us to one big question ... </seg>
<seg id="65"> What does this mean? </seg>
<seg id="66"> Ohhhh. </seg>
<seg id="67"> What does it mean? </seg>
<seg id="68"> Tastemakers, creative participating communities, complete unexpectedness, these are characteristics of a new kind of media and a new kind of culture where anyone has access and the audience defines the popularity. </seg>
<seg id="69"> I mean, as mentioned earlier, one of the biggest stars in the world right now, Justin Bieber, got his start on YouTube. </seg>
<seg id="70"> No one has to green-light your idea. </seg>
<seg id="71"> And we all now feel some ownership in our own pop culture. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And these are not characteristics of old media, and they're barely true of the media of today, but they will define the entertainment of the future. </seg>
<seg id="73"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1368" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/tan_le_my_immigration_story.html</url>
<description>In 2010, technologist Tan Le took the TEDGlobal stage to demo a powerful new interface. But now, at TEDxWomen, she tells a very personal story: the story of her family -- mother, grandmother and sister -- fleeing Vietnam and building a new life. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
<keywords>storytelling</keywords>
<talkid>1368</talkid>
<title>Tan Le: My immigration story</title>
<seg id="1"> How can I speak in 10 minutes about the bonds of women over three generations, about how the astonishing strength of those bonds took hold in the life of a four-year-old girl huddled with her young sister, her mother and her grandmother for five days and nights in a small boat in the China Sea more than 30 years ago, bonds that took hold in the life of that small girl and never let go -- that small girl now living in San Francisco and speaking to you today? </seg>
<seg id="2"> This is not a finished story. </seg>
<seg id="3"> It is a jigsaw puzzle still being put together. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Let me tell you about some of the pieces. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Imagine the first piece: a man burning his life's work. </seg>
<seg id="6"> He is a poet, a playwright, a man whose whole life had been balanced on the single hope of his country's unity and freedom. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Imagine him as the communists enter Saigon, confronting the fact that his life had been a complete waste. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Words, for so long his friends, now mocked him. </seg>
<seg id="9"> He retreated into silence. </seg>
<seg id="10"> He died broken by history. </seg>
<seg id="11"> He is my grandfather. </seg>
<seg id="12"> I never knew him in real life. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But our lives are much more than our memories. </seg>
<seg id="14"> My grandmother never let me forget his life. </seg>
<seg id="15"> My duty was not to allow it to have been in vain, and my lesson was to learn that, yes, history tried to crush us, but we endured. </seg>
<seg id="16"> The next piece of the jigsaw is of a boat in the early dawn slipping silently out to sea. </seg>
<seg id="17"> My mother, Mai, was 18 when her father died -- already in an arranged marriage, already with two small girls. </seg>
<seg id="18"> For her, life had distilled itself into one task: the escape of her family and a new life in Australia. </seg>
<seg id="19"> It was inconceivable to her that she would not succeed. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So after a four-year saga that defies fiction, a boat slipped out to sea disguised as a fishing vessel. </seg>
<seg id="21"> All the adults knew the risks. </seg>
<seg id="22"> The greatest fear was of pirates, rape and death. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Like most adults on the boat, my mother carried a small bottle of poison. </seg>
<seg id="24"> If we were captured, first my sister and I, then she and my grandmother would drink. </seg>
<seg id="25"> My first memories are from the boat -- the steady beat of the engine, the bow dipping into each wave, the vast and empty horizon. </seg>
<seg id="26"> I don't remember the pirates who came many times, but were bluffed by the bravado of the men on our boat, or the engine dying and failing to start for six hours. </seg>
<seg id="27"> But I do remember the lights on the oil rig off the Malaysian coast and the young man who collapsed and died, the journey's end too much for him, and the first apple I tasted, given to me by the men on the rig. </seg>
<seg id="28"> No apple has ever tasted the same. </seg>
<seg id="29"> After three months in a refugee camp, we landed in Melbourne. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And the next piece of the jigsaw is about four women across three generations shaping a new life together. </seg>
<seg id="31"> We settled in Footscray, a working-class suburb whose demographic is layers of immigrants. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Unlike the settled middle-class suburbs, whose existence I was oblivious of, there was no sense of entitlement in Footscray. </seg>
<seg id="33"> The smells from shop doors were from the rest of the world. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And the snippets of halting English were exchanged between people who had one thing in common, they were starting again. </seg>
<seg id="35"> My mother worked on farms, then on a car assembly line, working six days, double shifts. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Somehow she found time to study English and gain IT qualifications. </seg>
<seg id="37"> We were poor. </seg>
<seg id="38"> All the dollars were allocated and extra tuition in English and mathematics was budgeted for regardless of what missed out, which was usually new clothes; they were always secondhand. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Two pairs of stockings for school, each to hide the holes in the other. </seg>
<seg id="40"> A school uniform down to the ankles, because it had to last for six years. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And there were rare but searing chants of "slit-eye" and the occasional graffiti: "Asian, go home." </seg>
<seg id="42"> Go home to where? </seg>
<seg id="43"> Something stiffened inside me. </seg>
<seg id="44"> There was a gathering of resolve and a quiet voice saying, "I will bypass you." </seg>
<seg id="45"> My mother, my sister and I slept in the same bed. </seg>
<seg id="46"> My mother was exhausted each night, but we told one another about our day and listened to the movements of my grandmother around the house. </seg>
<seg id="47"> My mother suffered from nightmares all about the boat. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And my job was to stay awake until her nightmares came so I could wake her. </seg>
<seg id="49"> She opened a computer store then studied to be a beautician and opened another business. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And the women came with their stories about men who could not make the transition, angry and inflexible, and troubled children caught between two worlds. </seg>
<seg id="51"> Grants and sponsors were sought. </seg>
<seg id="52"> Centers were established. </seg>
<seg id="53"> I lived in parallel worlds. </seg>
<seg id="54"> In one, I was the classic Asian student, relentless in the demands that I made on myself. </seg>
<seg id="55"> In the other, I was enmeshed in lives that were precarious, tragically scarred by violence, drug abuse and isolation. </seg>
<seg id="56"> But so many over the years were helped. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And for that work, when I was a final year law student, I was chosen as the young Australian of the year. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And I was catapulted from one piece of the jigsaw to another, and their edges didn't fit. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Tan Le, anonymous Footscray resident, was now Tan Le, refugee and social activist, invited to speak in venues she had never heard of and into homes whose existence she could never have imagined. </seg>
<seg id="60"> I didn't know the protocols. </seg>
<seg id="61"> I didn't know how to use the cutlery. </seg>
<seg id="62"> I didn't know how to talk about wine. </seg>
<seg id="63"> I didn't know how to talk about anything. </seg>
<seg id="64"> I wanted to retreat to the routines and comfort of life in an unsung suburb -- a grandmother, a mother and two daughters ending each day as they had for almost 20 years, telling one another the story of their day and falling asleep, the three of us still in the same bed. </seg>
<seg id="65"> I told my mother I couldn't do it. </seg>
<seg id="66"> She reminded me that I was now the same age she had been when we boarded the boat. </seg>
<seg id="67"> No had never been an option. </seg>
<seg id="68"> "Just do it," she said, "and don't be what you're not." </seg>
<seg id="69"> So I spoke out on youth unemployment and education and the neglect of the marginalized and the disenfranchised. </seg>
<seg id="70"> And the more candidly I spoke, the more I was asked to speak. </seg>
<seg id="71"> I met people from all walks of life, so many of them doing the thing they loved, living on the frontiers of possibility. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And even though I finished my degree, I realized I could not settle into a career in law. </seg>
<seg id="73"> There had to be another piece of the jigsaw. </seg>
<seg id="74"> And I realized at the same time that it is okay to be an outsider, a recent arrival, new on the scene -- and not just okay, but something to be thankful for, perhaps a gift from the boat. </seg>
<seg id="75"> Because being an insider can so easily mean collapsing the horizons, can so easily mean accepting the presumptions of your province. </seg>
<seg id="76"> I have stepped outside my comfort zone enough now to know that, yes, the world does fall apart, but not in the way that you fear. </seg>
<seg id="77"> Possibilities that would not have been allowed were outrageously encouraged. </seg>
<seg id="78"> There was an energy there, an implacable optimism, a strange mixture of humility and daring. </seg>
<seg id="79"> So I followed my hunches. </seg>
<seg id="80"> I gathered around me a small team of people for whom the label "It can't be done" was an irresistible challenge. </seg>
<seg id="81"> For a year we were penniless. </seg>
<seg id="82"> At the end of each day, I made a huge pot of soup which we all shared. </seg>
<seg id="83"> We worked well into each night. </seg>
<seg id="84"> Most of our ideas were crazy, but a few were brilliant, and we broke through. </seg>
<seg id="85"> I made the decision to move to the U.S. </seg>
<seg id="86"> after only one trip. </seg>
<seg id="87"> My hunches again. </seg>
<seg id="88"> Three months later I had relocated, and the adventure has continued. </seg>
<seg id="89"> Before I close though, let me tell you about my grandmother. </seg>
<seg id="90"> She grew up at a time when Confucianism was the social norm and the local Mandarin was the person who mattered. </seg>
<seg id="91"> Life hadn't changed for centuries. </seg>
<seg id="92"> Her father died soon after she was born. </seg>
<seg id="93"> Her mother raised her alone. </seg>
<seg id="94"> At 17 she became the second wife of a Mandarin whose mother beat her. </seg>
<seg id="95"> With no support from her husband, she caused a sensation by taking him to court and prosecuting her own case, and a far greater sensation when she won. </seg>
<seg id="96"> "It can't be done" was shown to be wrong. </seg>
<seg id="97"> I was taking a shower in a hotel room in Sydney the moment she died 600 miles away in Melbourne. </seg>
<seg id="98"> I looked through the shower screen and saw her standing on the other side. </seg>
<seg id="99"> I knew she had come to say goodbye. </seg>
<seg id="100"> My mother phoned minutes later. </seg>
<seg id="101"> A few days later, we went to a Buddhist temple in Footscray and sat around her casket. </seg>
<seg id="102"> We told her stories and assured her that we were still with her. </seg>
<seg id="103"> At midnight the monk came and told us he had to close the casket. </seg>
<seg id="104"> My mother asked us to feel her hand. </seg>
<seg id="105"> She asked the monk, "Why is it that her hand is so warm and the rest of her is so cold?" </seg>
<seg id="106"> "Because you have been holding it since this morning," he said. </seg>
<seg id="107"> "You have not let it go." </seg>
<seg id="108"> If there is a sinew in our family, it runs through the women. </seg>
<seg id="109"> Given who we were and how life had shaped us, we can now see that the men who might have come into our lives would have thwarted us. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Defeat would have come too easily. </seg>
<seg id="111"> Now I would like to have my own children, and I wonder about the boat. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Who could ever wish it on their own? </seg>
<seg id="113"> Yet I am afraid of privilege, of ease, of entitlement. </seg>
<seg id="114"> Can I give them a bow in their lives, dipping bravely into each wave, the unperturbed and steady beat of the engine, the vast horizon that guarantees nothing? </seg>
<seg id="115"> I don't know. </seg>
<seg id="116"> But if I could give it and still see them safely through, I would. </seg>
<seg id="117"> And also, Tan's mother is here today in the fourth or fifth row. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1353" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/erik_johansson_impossible_photography.html</url>
<description>Erik Johansson creates realistic photos of impossible scenes -- capturing ideas, not moments. In this witty how-to, the Photoshop wizard describes the principles he uses to make these fantastical scenarios come to life, while keeping them visually plausible.</description>
<keywords>creativity,culture,photography,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1353</talkid>
<title>Erik Johansson: Impossible photography</title>
<seg id="1"> I'm here to share my photography. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Or is it photography? </seg>
<seg id="3"> Because, of course, this is a photograph that you can't take with your camera. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Yet, my interest in photography started as I got my first digital camera at the age of 15. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It mixed with my earlier passion for drawing, but it was a bit different, because using the camera, the process was in the planning instead. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And when you take a photograph with a camera, the process ends when you press the trigger. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So to me it felt like photography was more about being at the right place and the right time. </seg>
<seg id="8"> I felt like anyone could do that. </seg>
<seg id="9"> So I wanted to create something different, something where the process starts when you press the trigger. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Photos like this: construction going on along a busy road. </seg>
<seg id="11"> But it has an unexpected twist. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And despite that, it retains a level of realism. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Or photos like these -- both dark and colorful, but all with a common goal of retaining the level of realism. </seg>
<seg id="14"> When I say realism, I mean photo-realism. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Because, of course, it's not something you can capture really, but I always want it to look like it could have been captured somehow as a photograph. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Photos where you will need a brief moment to think to figure out the trick. </seg>
<seg id="17"> So it's more about capturing an idea than about capturing a moment really. </seg>
<seg id="18"> But what's the trick that makes it look realistic? </seg>
<seg id="19"> Is it something about the details or the colors? </seg>
<seg id="20"> Is it something about the light? </seg>
<seg id="21"> What creates the illusion? </seg>
<seg id="22"> Sometimes the perspective is the illusion. </seg>
<seg id="23"> But in the end, it comes down to how we interpret the world and how it can be realized on a two-dimensional surface. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It's not really what is realistic, it's what we think looks realistic really. </seg>
<seg id="25"> So I think the basics are quite simple. </seg>
<seg id="26"> I just see it as a puzzle of reality where you can take different pieces of reality and put it together to create alternate reality. </seg>
<seg id="27"> And let me show you a simple example. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Here we have three perfectly imaginable physical objects, something we all can relate to living in a three-dimensional world. </seg>
<seg id="29"> But combined in a certain way, they can create something that still looks three-dimensional, like it could exist. </seg>
<seg id="30"> But at the same time, we know it can't. </seg>
<seg id="31"> So we trick our brains, because our brain simply doesn't accept the fact that it doesn't really make sense. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And I see the same process with combining photographs. </seg>
<seg id="33"> It's just really about combining different realities. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So the things that make a photograph look realistic, I think it's the things that we don't even think about, the things all around us in our daily lives. </seg>
<seg id="35"> But when combining photographs, this is really important to consider, because otherwise it just looks wrong somehow. </seg>
<seg id="36"> So I would like to say that there are three simple rules to follow to achieve a realistic result. </seg>
<seg id="37"> As you can see, these images aren't really special. </seg>
<seg id="38"> But combined, they can create something like this. </seg>
<seg id="39"> So the first rule is that photos combined should have the same perspective. </seg>
<seg id="40"> Secondly, photos combined should have the same type of light. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And these two images both fulfill these two requirements -- shot at the same height and in the same type of light. </seg>
<seg id="42"> The third one is about making it impossible to distinguish where the different images begin and end by making it seamless. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Make it impossible to say how the image actually was composed. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So by matching color, contrast and brightness in the borders between the different images, adding photographic defects like depth of field, desaturated colors and noise, we erase the borders between the different images and make it look like one single image, despite the fact that one image can contain hundreds of layers basically. </seg>
<seg id="45"> So here's another example. </seg>
<seg id="46"> One might think that this is just an image of a landscape and the lower part is what's manipulated. </seg>
<seg id="47"> But this image is actually entirely composed of photographs from different locations. </seg>
<seg id="48"> I personally think that it's easier to actually create a place than to find a place, because then you don't need to compromise with the ideas in your head. </seg>
<seg id="49"> But it does require a lot of planning. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And getting this idea during winter, I knew that I had several months to plan it, to find the different locations for the pieces of the puzzle basically. </seg>
<seg id="51"> So for example, the fish was captured on a fishing trip. </seg>
<seg id="52"> The shores are from a different location. </seg>
<seg id="53"> The underwater part was captured in a stone pit. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And yeah, I even turned the house on top of the island red to make it look more Swedish. </seg>
<seg id="55"> So to achieve a realistic result, I think it comes down to planning. </seg>
<seg id="56"> It always starts with a sketch, an idea. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Then it's about combining the different photographs. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And here every piece is very well planned. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And if you do a good job capturing the photos, the result can be quite beautiful and also quite realistic. </seg>
<seg id="60"> So all the tools are out there, and the only thing that limits us is our imagination. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1359" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/lucien_engelen_crowdsource_your_health.html</url>
<description>You can use your smartphone to find a local ATM, but what if you need a defibrillator? Lucien Engelen shows us online innovations that are changing the way we save lives, including a crowdsourced map of local defibrillators. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
<keywords>health,health care,medicine,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1359</talkid>
<title>Lucien Engelen: Crowdsource your health</title>
<seg id="1"> I would like to talk to you about why many e-health projects fail. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And I really think that the most important thing of it is that we stopped listening to patients. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And one of the things we did at Radboud University is we appointed a chief listening officer. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Not in a very scientific way -- she puts up a little cup of coffee or cup of tea and asks patients, family, relatives, "What's up? </seg>
<seg id="5"> How could we help you?" </seg>
<seg id="6"> And we think, we like to think, that this is one of the major problems why all -- maybe not all -- but most of the e-health projects fail, since we stopped listening. </seg>
<seg id="7"> This is my WiFi scale. It's a very simple thing. </seg>
<seg id="8"> It's got one knob, on/off. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And every morning I hop on it. </seg>
<seg id="10"> And yes, I've got a challenge, as you might see. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And I put my challenge on 95 kg. </seg>
<seg id="12"> But the thing is that it's made this simple that whenever I hop on, it sends my data through Google Health as well. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And it's collected by my general practitioner as well, so he can see what's my problem in weight, not on the very moment that I need cardiologic support or something like it, but also looking backward. </seg>
<seg id="14"> But there's another thing. </seg>
<seg id="15"> As some of you might know, I've got more than 4,000 followers on Twitter. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So every morning I hop on my WiFi scale and before I'm in my car, people start talking to me, "I think you need a light lunch today, Lucien." </seg>
<seg id="17"> But that's the nicest thing that could happen, since this is peer pressure, peer pressure used to help patients -- since this could be used for obesity, it could be used to stop smoking in patients. </seg>
<seg id="18"> But on the other hand, it also could be used to get people from out of their chairs and try to work together in some kind of gaming activity to get more control of their health. </seg>
<seg id="19"> As of next week, it will soon be available. </seg>
<seg id="20"> There will be this little blood pressure meter connected to an iPhone or something or other. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And people will be able, from their homes, to take their blood pressure, send it into their doctor and eventually share it with others, for instance, for over a hundred dollars. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And this is the point where patients get into position and can collect, not only their own control again, be captain of their own ship, but also can help us in health care due to the challenges that we face, like health care cost explosion, doubled demand and things like that. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Make techniques that are easy to use and start with this to embrace patients in the team. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And you can do this with techniques like this, but also by crowd-sourcing. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And one of the things we did I would like to share with you introduced by a little video. </seg>
<seg id="26"> We've all got navigation controls in our car. </seg>
<seg id="27"> We maybe even [have] it in our cellphone. </seg>
<seg id="28"> We know perfectly where all the ATMs are about the city of Maastricht. </seg>
<seg id="29"> The other thing is we know where all the gas stations are. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And sure, we could find fast food chains. </seg>
<seg id="31"> But where would be the nearest AED to help this patient? </seg>
<seg id="32"> We asked around and nobody knew. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Nobody knew where the nearest life-saving AED was to be obtained right now. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So what we did, we crowdsourced The Netherlands. </seg>
<seg id="35"> We set up a website and asked the crowd, "If you see an AED, please submit it, tell us where it is, tell us when it's open," since sometimes in office hours sometimes it's closed, of course. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And over 10,000 AEDs already in The Netherlands already have been submitted. </seg>
<seg id="37"> The next step we took was to find the applications for it. </seg>
<seg id="38"> And we built an iPad application. </seg>
<seg id="39"> We made an application for Layar, augmented reality, to find these AEDs. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And whenever you are in a city like Maastricht and somebody collapses, you can use your iPhone, and within the next weeks also run your Microsoft cellphone, to find the nearest AED which can save lives. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And as of today, we would like to introduce this, not only as AED4EU, which is what the product is called, but also AED4US. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And we would like to start this on a worldwide level. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And [we're] asking all of our colleagues in the rest of the world, colleague universities, to help us to find and work and act like a hub to crowd-source all these AEDs all around the world. </seg>
<seg id="44"> That whenever you're on holiday and somebody collapses, might it be your own relative or someone just in front of you, you can find this. </seg>
<seg id="45"> The other thing we would like to ask is of companies also all over the world that will be able to help us validate these AEDs. </seg>
<seg id="46"> These might be courier services or cable guys for instance, just to see whether the AED that's submitted still is in place. </seg>
<seg id="47"> So please help us on this one and try to make not only health a little bit better, but take control of it. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1382" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/a_ted_speaker_s_worst_nightmare.html</url>
<description>Colin Robertson had 3 minutes on the stage to tell the world about his solar-powered crowdsourced health care solution. And then...</description>
<keywords>entertainment,performance,performance art</keywords>
<talkid>1382</talkid>
<title>Improv Everywhere: A TED speaker's worst nightmare</title>
<seg id="1"> Today I'm going to talk about unexpected discoveries. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now I work in the solar technology industry. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And my small startup is looking to force ourselves into the environment by paying attention to ... </seg>
<seg id="4"> ... paying attention to crowd-sourcing. </seg>
<seg id="5"> It's just a quick video of what we do. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Huh. Hang on a moment. </seg>
<seg id="7"> It might take a moment to load. </seg>
<seg id="8"> We'll just -- we can just skip -- I'll just skip through the video instead ... </seg>
<seg id="9"> No. </seg>
<seg id="10"> This is not ... </seg>
<seg id="11"> Okay. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Solar technology is ... </seg>
<seg id="13"> Oh, that's all my time? </seg>
<seg id="14"> Okay. Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1381" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/jennifer_pahlka_coding_a_better_government.html</url>
<description>Can government be run like the Internet, permissionless and open? Coder and activist Jennifer Pahlka believes it can -- and that apps, built quickly and cheaply, are a powerful new way to connect citizens to their governments -- and their neighbors.</description>
<keywords>activism,cities,government,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1381</talkid>
<title>Jennifer Pahlka: Coding a better government</title>
<seg id="1"> So a couple of years ago I started a program to try to get the rockstar tech and design people to take a year off and work in the one environment that represents pretty much everything they're supposed to hate; we have them work in government. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The program is called Code for America, and it's a little bit like a Peace Corps for geeks. </seg>
<seg id="3"> We select a few fellows every year and we have them work with city governments. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Instead of sending them off into the Third World, we send them into the wilds of City Hall. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And there they make great apps, they work with city staffers. </seg>
<seg id="6"> But really what they're doing is they're showing what's possible with technology today. </seg>
<seg id="7"> So meet Al. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Al is a fire hydrant in the city of Boston. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Here it kind of looks like he's looking for a date, but what he's really looking for is for someone to shovel him out when he gets snowed in, because he knows he's not very good at fighting fires when he's covered in four feet of snow. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now how did he come to be looking for help in this very unique manner? </seg>
<seg id="11"> We had a team of fellows in Boston last year through the Code for America program. </seg>
<seg id="12"> They were there in February, and it snowed a lot in February last year. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And they noticed that the city never gets to digging out these fire hydrants. </seg>
<seg id="14"> But one fellow in particular, a guy named Erik Michaels-Ober, noticed something else, and that's that citizens are shoveling out sidewalks right in front of these things. </seg>
<seg id="15"> So he did what any good developer would do, he wrote an app. </seg>
<seg id="16"> It's a cute little app where you can adopt a fire hydrant. </seg>
<seg id="17"> So you agree to dig it out when it snows. </seg>
<seg id="18"> If you do, you get to name it, and he called the first one Al. </seg>
<seg id="19"> And if you don't, someone can steal it from you. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So it's got cute little game dynamics on it. </seg>
<seg id="21"> This is a modest little app. </seg>
<seg id="22"> It's probably the smallest of the 21 apps that the fellows wrote last year. </seg>
<seg id="23"> But it's doing something that no other government technology does. </seg>
<seg id="24"> It's spreading virally. </seg>
<seg id="25"> There's a guy in the I.T. department of the City of Honolulu who saw this app and realized that he could use it, not for snow, but to get citizens to adopt tsunami sirens. </seg>
<seg id="26"> It's very important that these tsunami sirens work, but people steal the batteries out of them. </seg>
<seg id="27"> So he's getting citizens to check on them. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And then Seattle decided to use it to get citizens to clear out clogged storm drains. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And Chicago just rolled it out to get people to sign up to shovel sidewalks when it snows. </seg>
<seg id="30"> So we now know of nine cities that are planning to use this. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And this has spread just frictionlessly, organically, naturally. </seg>
<seg id="32"> If you know anything about government technology, you know that this isn't how it normally goes. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Procuring software usually takes a couple of years. </seg>
<seg id="34"> We had a team that worked on a project in Boston last year that took three people about two and a half months. </seg>
<seg id="35"> It was a way that parents could figure out which were the right public schools for their kids. </seg>
<seg id="36"> We were told afterward that if that had gone through normal channels, it would have taken at least two years and it would have cost about two million dollars. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And that's nothing. </seg>
<seg id="38"> There is one project in the California court system right now that so far cost taxpayers two billion dollars, and it doesn't work. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And there are projects like this at every level of government. </seg>
<seg id="40"> So an app that takes a couple of days to write and then spreads virally, that's sort of a shot across the bow to the institution of government. </seg>
<seg id="41"> It suggests how government could work better -- not more like a private company, as many people think it should. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And not even like a tech company, but more like the Internet itself. </seg>
<seg id="43"> And that means permissionless, it means open, it means generative. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And that's important. </seg>
<seg id="45"> But what's more important about this app is that it represents how a new generation is tackling the problem of government -- not as the problem of an ossified institution, but as a problem of collective action. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And that's great news, because, it turns out, we're very good at collective action with digital technology. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Now there's a very large community of people that are building the tools that we need to do things together effectively. </seg>
<seg id="48"> It's not just Code for America fellows, there are hundreds of people all over the country that are standing and writing civic apps every day in their own communities. </seg>
<seg id="49"> They haven't given up on government. </seg>
<seg id="50"> They are frustrated as hell with it, but they're not complaining about it, they're fixing it. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And these folks know something that we've lost sight of. </seg>
<seg id="52"> And that's that when you strip away all your feelings about politics and the line at the DMV and all those other things that we're really mad about, government is, at its core, in the words of Tim O'Reilly, "What we do together that we can't do alone." </seg>
<seg id="53"> Now a lot of people have given up on government. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And if you're one of those people, I would ask that you reconsider, because things are changing. </seg>
<seg id="55"> Politics is not changing; government is changing. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And because government ultimately derives its power from us -- remember "We the people?" -- how we think about it is going to effect how that change happens. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Now I didn't know very much about government when I started this program. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And like a lot of people, I thought government was basically about getting people elected to office. </seg>
<seg id="59"> Well after two years, I've come to the conclusion that, especially local government, is about opossums. </seg>
<seg id="60"> This is the call center for the services and information line. </seg>
<seg id="61"> It's generally where you will get if you call 311 in your city. </seg>
<seg id="62"> If you should ever have the chance to staff your city's call center, as our fellow Scott Silverman did as part of the program -- in fact, they all do that -- you will find that people call government with a very wide range of issues, including having an opossum stuck in your house. </seg>
<seg id="63"> So Scott gets this call. </seg>
<seg id="64"> He types "Opossum" into this official knowledge base. </seg>
<seg id="65"> He doesn't really come up with anything. He starts with animal control. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And finally, he says, "Look, can you just open all the doors to your house and play music really loud and see if the thing leaves?" </seg>
<seg id="67"> So that worked. So booya for Scott. </seg>
<seg id="68"> But that wasn't the end of the opossums. </seg>
<seg id="69"> Boston doesn't just have a call center. </seg>
<seg id="70"> It has an app, a Web and mobile app, called Citizens Connect. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Now we didn't write this app. </seg>
<seg id="72"> This is the work of the very smart people at the Office of New Urban Mechanics in Boston. </seg>
<seg id="73"> So one day -- this is an actual report -- this came in: "Opossum in my trashcan. Can't tell if it's dead. </seg>
<seg id="74"> How do I get this removed?" </seg>
<seg id="75"> But what happens with Citizens Connect is different. </seg>
<seg id="76"> So Scott was speaking person-to-person. </seg>
<seg id="77"> But on Citizens Connect everything is public, so everybody can see this. </seg>
<seg id="78"> And in this case, a neighbor saw it. </seg>
<seg id="79"> And the next report we got said, "I walked over to this location, found the trashcan behind the house. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Opossum? Check. Living? Yep. </seg>
<seg id="81"> Turned trashcan on its side. Walked home. </seg>
<seg id="82"> Goodnight sweet opossum." </seg>
<seg id="83"> Pretty simple. </seg>
<seg id="84"> So this is great. This is the digital meeting the physical. </seg>
<seg id="85"> And it's also a great example of government getting in on the crowd-sourcing game. </seg>
<seg id="86"> But it's also a great example of government as a platform. </seg>
<seg id="87"> And I don't mean necessarily a technological definition of platform here. </seg>
<seg id="88"> I'm just talking about a platform for people to help themselves and to help others. </seg>
<seg id="89"> So one citizen helped another citizen, but government played a key role here. </seg>
<seg id="90"> It connected those two people. </seg>
<seg id="91"> And it could have connected them with government services if they'd been needed, but a neighbor is a far better and cheaper alternative to government services. </seg>
<seg id="92"> When one neighbor helps another, we strengthen our communities. </seg>
<seg id="93"> We call animal control, it just costs a lot of money. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Now one of the important things we need to think about government is that it's not the same thing as politics. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And most people get that, but they think that one is the input to the other. </seg>
<seg id="96"> That our input to the system of government is voting. </seg>
<seg id="97"> Now how many times have we elected a political leader -- and sometimes we spend a lot of energy getting a new political leader elected -- and then we sit back and we expect government to reflect our values and meet our needs, and then not that much changes? </seg>
<seg id="98"> That's because government is like a vast ocean and politics is the six-inch layer on top. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And what's under that is what we call bureaucracy. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And we say that word with such contempt. </seg>
<seg id="101"> But it's that contempt that keeps this thing that we own and we pay for as something that's working against us, this other thing, and then we're disempowering ourselves. </seg>
<seg id="102"> People seem to think politics is sexy. </seg>
<seg id="103"> If we want this institution to work for us, we're going to have to make bureaucracy sexy. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Because that's where the real work of government happens. </seg>
<seg id="105"> We have to engage with the machinery of government. </seg>
<seg id="106"> So that's OccupytheSEC movement has done. </seg>
<seg id="107"> Have you seen these guys? </seg>
<seg id="108"> It's a group of concerned citizens that have written a very detailed 325-page report that's a response to the SEC's request for comment on the Financial Reform Bill. </seg>
<seg id="109"> That's not being politically active, that's being bureaucratically active. </seg>
<seg id="110"> Now for those of us who've given up on government, it's time that we asked ourselves about the world that we want to leave for our children. </seg>
<seg id="111"> You have to see the enormous challenges that they're going to face. </seg>
<seg id="112"> Do we really think we're going to get where we need to go without fixing the one institution that can act on behalf of all of us? </seg>
<seg id="113"> We can't do without government, but we do need it to be more effective. </seg>
<seg id="114"> The good news is that technology is making it possible to fundamentally reframe the function of government in a way that can actually scale by strengthening civil society. </seg>
<seg id="115"> And there's a generation out there that's grown up on the Internet, and they know that it's not that hard to do things together, you just have to architect the systems the right way. </seg>
<seg id="116"> Now the average age of our fellows is 28, so I am, begrudgingly, almost a generation older than most of them. </seg>
<seg id="117"> This is a generation that's grown up taking their voices pretty much for granted. </seg>
<seg id="118"> They're not fighting that battle that we're all fighting about who gets to speak; they all get to speak. </seg>
<seg id="119"> They can express their opinion on any channel at any time, and they do. </seg>
<seg id="120"> So when they're faced with the problem of government, they don't care as much about using their voices. </seg>
<seg id="121"> They're using their hands. </seg>
<seg id="122"> They're using their hands to write applications that make government work better. </seg>
<seg id="123"> And those applications let us use our hands to make our communities better. </seg>
<seg id="124"> That could be shoveling out a hydrant, pulling a weed, turning over a garbage can with an opossum in it. </seg>
<seg id="125"> And certainly, we could have been shoveling out those fire hydrants all along, and many people do. </seg>
<seg id="126"> But these apps are like little digital reminders that we're not just consumers, and we're not just consumers of government, putting in our taxes and getting back services. </seg>
<seg id="127"> We're more than that, we're citizens. </seg>
<seg id="128"> And we're not going to fix government until we fix citizenship. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So the question I have for all of you here: When it comes to the big, important things that we need to do together, all of us together, are we just going to be a crowd of voices, or are we also going to be a crowd of hands? </seg>
<seg id="130"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1346" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/danny_hillis_back_to_the_future_of_1994.html</url>
<description>From deep in the archive, Danny Hillis outlines an intriguing theory of how and why technological change seems to be accelerating, by linking it to the very evolution of life itself. The presentation techniques he uses may look dated, but the ideas are as relevant as ever.</description>
<keywords>future,science,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1346</talkid>
<title>Danny Hillis: Back to the future </title>
<seg id="1"> Because I usually take the role of trying to explain to people how wonderful the new technologies that are coming along are going to be, and I thought that, since I was among friends here, I would tell you what I really think and try to look back and try to understand what is really going on here with these amazing jumps in technology that seem so fast that we can barely keep on top of it. </seg>
<seg id="2"> So I'm going to start out by showing just one very boring technology slide. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And then, so if you can just turn on the slide that's on. </seg>
<seg id="4"> This is just a random slide that I picked out of my file. </seg>
<seg id="5"> What I want to show you is not so much the details of the slide, but the general form of it. </seg>
<seg id="6"> This happens to be a slide of some analysis that we were doing about the power of RISC microprocessors versus the power of local area networks. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And the interesting thing about it is that this slide, like so many technology slides that we're used to, is a sort of a straight line on a semi-log curve. </seg>
<seg id="8"> In other words, every step here represents an order of magnitude in performance scale. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And this is a new thing that we talk about technology on semi-log curves. </seg>
<seg id="10"> Something really weird is going on here. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And that's basically what I'm going to be talking about. </seg>
<seg id="12"> So, if you could bring up the lights. </seg>
<seg id="13"> If you could bring up the lights higher, because I'm just going to use a piece of paper here. </seg>
<seg id="14"> Now why do we draw technology curves in semi-log curves? </seg>
<seg id="15"> Well the answer is, if I drew it on a normal curve where, let's say, this is years, this is time of some sort, and this is whatever measure of the technology that I'm trying to graph, the graphs look sort of silly. </seg>
<seg id="16"> They sort of go like this. </seg>
<seg id="17"> And they don't tell us much. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Now if I graph, for instance, some other technology, say transportation technology, on a semi-log curve, it would look very stupid, it would look like a flat line. </seg>
<seg id="19"> But when something like this happens, things are qualitatively changing. </seg>
<seg id="20"> So if transportation technology was moving along as fast as microprocessor technology, then the day after tomorrow, I would be able to get in a taxi cab and be in Tokyo in 30 seconds. </seg>
<seg id="21"> It's not moving like that. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And there's nothing precedented in the history of technology development of this kind of self-feeding growth where you go by orders of magnitude every few years. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Now the question that I'd like to ask is, if you look at these exponential curves, they don't go on forever. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Things just can't possibly keep changing as fast as they are. </seg>
<seg id="25"> One of two things is going to happen. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Either it's going to turn into a sort of classical S-curve like this, until something totally different comes along, or maybe it's going to do this. </seg>
<seg id="27"> That's about all it can do. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Now I'm an optimist, so I sort of think it's probably going to do something like that. </seg>
<seg id="29"> If so, that means that what we're in the middle of right now is a transition. </seg>
<seg id="30"> We're sort of on this line in a transition from the way the world used to be to some new way that the world is. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And so what I'm trying to ask, what I've been asking myself, is what's this new way that the world is? </seg>
<seg id="32"> What's that new state that the world is heading toward? </seg>
<seg id="33"> Because the transition seems very, very confusing when we're right in the middle of it. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Now when I was a kid growing up, the future was kind of the year 2000, and people used to talk about what would happen in the year 2000. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Now here's a conference in which people talk about the future, and you notice that the future is still at about the year 2000. </seg>
<seg id="36"> It's about as far as we go out. </seg>
<seg id="37"> So in other words, the future has kind of been shrinking one year per year for my whole lifetime. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Now I think that the reason is because we all feel that something's happening there. </seg>
<seg id="39"> That transition is happening. We can all sense it. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And we know that it just doesn't make too much sense to think out 30, 50 years because everything's going to be so different that a simple extrapolation of what we're doing just doesn't make any sense at all. </seg>
<seg id="41"> So what I would like to talk about is what that could be, what that transition could be that we're going through. </seg>
<seg id="42"> Now in order to do that I'm going to have to talk about a bunch of stuff that really has nothing to do with technology and computers. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Because I think the only way to understand this is to really step back and take a long time scale look at things. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So the time scale that I would like to look at this on is the time scale of life on Earth. </seg>
<seg id="45"> So I think this picture makes sense if you look at it a few billion years at a time. </seg>
<seg id="46"> So if you go back about two and a half billion years, the Earth was this big, sterile hunk of rock with a lot of chemicals floating around on it. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And if you look at the way that the chemicals got organized, we begin to get a pretty good idea of how they do it. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And I think that there's theories that are beginning to understand about how it started with RNA, but I'm going to tell a sort of simple story of it, which is that, at that time, there were little drops of oil floating around with all kinds of different recipes of chemicals in them. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And some of those drops of oil had a particular combination of chemicals in them which caused them to incorporate chemicals from the outside and grow the drops of oil. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And those that were like that started to split and divide. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And those were the most primitive forms of cells in a sense, those little drops of oil. </seg>
<seg id="52"> But now those drops of oil weren't really alive, as we say it now, because every one of them was a little random recipe of chemicals. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And every time it divided, they got sort of unequal division of the chemicals within them. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And so every drop was a little bit different. </seg>
<seg id="55"> In fact, the drops that were different in a way that caused them to be better at incorporating chemicals around them, grew more and incorporated more chemicals and divided more. </seg>
<seg id="56"> So those tended to live longer, get expressed more. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Now that's sort of just a very simple chemical form of life, but when things got interesting was when these drops learned a trick about abstraction. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Somehow by ways that we don't quite understand, these little drops learned to write down information. </seg>
<seg id="59"> They learned to record the information that was the recipe of the cell onto a particular kind of chemical called DNA. </seg>
<seg id="60"> So in other words, they worked out, in this mindless sort of evolutionary way, a form of writing that let them write down what they were, so that that way of writing it down could get copied. </seg>
<seg id="61"> The amazing thing is that that way of writing seems to have stayed steady since it evolved two and a half billion years ago. </seg>
<seg id="62"> In fact the recipe for us, our genes, is exactly that same code and that same way of writing. </seg>
<seg id="63"> In fact, every living creature is written in exactly the same set of letters and the same code. </seg>
<seg id="64"> In fact, one of the things that I did just for amusement purposes is we can now write things in this code. </seg>
<seg id="65"> And I've got here a little 100 micrograms of white powder, which I try not to let the security people see at airports. </seg>
<seg id="66"> But this has in it -- what I did is I took this code -- the code has standard letters that we use for symbolizing it -- and I wrote my business card onto a piece of DNA and amplified it 10 to the 22 times. </seg>
<seg id="67"> So if anyone would like a hundred million copies of my business card, I have plenty for everyone in the room, and, in fact, everyone in the world, and it's right here. </seg>
<seg id="68"> If I had really been a egotist, I would have put it into a virus and released it in the room. </seg>
<seg id="69"> So what was the next step? </seg>
<seg id="70"> Writing down the DNA was an interesting step. </seg>
<seg id="71"> And that caused these cells -- that kept them happy for another billion years. </seg>
<seg id="72"> But then there was another really interesting step where things became completely different, which is these cells started exchanging and communicating information, so that they began to get communities of cells. </seg>
<seg id="73"> I don't know if you know this, but bacteria can actually exchange DNA. </seg>
<seg id="74"> Now that's why, for instance, antibiotic resistance has evolved. </seg>
<seg id="75"> Some bacteria figured out how to stay away from penicillin, and it went around sort of creating its little DNA information with other bacteria, and now we have a lot of bacteria that are resistant to penicillin, because bacteria communicate. </seg>
<seg id="76"> Now what this communication allowed was communities to form that, in some sense, were in the same boat together; they were synergistic. </seg>
<seg id="77"> So they survived or they failed together, which means that if a community was very successful, all the individuals in that community were repeated more and they were favored by evolution. </seg>
<seg id="78"> Now the transition point happened when these communities got so close that, in fact, they got together and decided to write down the whole recipe for the community together on one string of DNA. </seg>
<seg id="79"> And so the next stage that's interesting in life took about another billion years. </seg>
<seg id="80"> And at that stage, we have multi-cellular communities, communities of lots of different types of cells, working together as a single organism. </seg>
<seg id="81"> And in fact, we're such a multi-cellular community. </seg>
<seg id="82"> We have lots of cells that are not out for themselves anymore. </seg>
<seg id="83"> Your skin cell is really useless without a heart cell, muscle cell, a brain cell and so on. </seg>
<seg id="84"> So these communities began to evolve so that the interesting level on which evolution was taking place was no longer a cell, but a community which we call an organism. </seg>
<seg id="85"> Now the next step that happened is within these communities. </seg>
<seg id="86"> These communities of cells, again, began to abstract information. </seg>
<seg id="87"> And they began building very special structures that did nothing but process information within the community. </seg>
<seg id="88"> And those are the neural structures. </seg>
<seg id="89"> So neurons are the information processing apparatus that those communities of cells built up. </seg>
<seg id="90"> And in fact, they began to get specialists in the community and special structures that were responsible for recording, understanding, learning information. </seg>
<seg id="91"> And that was the brains and the nervous system of those communities. </seg>
<seg id="92"> And that gave them an evolutionary advantage. </seg>
<seg id="93"> Because at that point, an individual -- learning could happen within the time span of a single organism, instead of over this evolutionary time span. </seg>
<seg id="94"> So an organism could, for instance, learn not to eat a certain kind of fruit because it tasted bad and it got sick last time it ate it. </seg>
<seg id="95"> That could happen within the lifetime of a single organism, whereas before they'd built these special information processing structures, that would have had to be learned evolutionarily over hundreds of thousands of years by the individuals dying off that ate that kind of fruit. </seg>
<seg id="96"> So that nervous system, the fact that they built these special information structures, Because evolution could now happen within an individual. </seg>
<seg id="97"> It could happen in learning time scales. </seg>
<seg id="98"> But then what happened was the individuals worked out, of course, tricks of communicating. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And for example, the most sophisticated version that we're aware of is human language. </seg>
<seg id="100"> It's really a pretty amazing invention if you think about it. </seg>
<seg id="101"> Here I have a very complicated, messy, confused idea in my head. </seg>
<seg id="102"> I'm sitting here making grunting sounds basically, and hopefully constructing a similar messy, confused idea in your head that bears some analogy to it. </seg>
<seg id="103"> But we're taking something very complicated, turning it into sound, sequences of sounds, and producing something very complicated in your brain. </seg>
<seg id="104"> So this allows us now to begin to start functioning as a single organism. </seg>
<seg id="105"> And so, in fact, what we've done is we, humanity, have started abstracting out. </seg>
<seg id="106"> We're going through the same levels that multi-cellular organisms have gone through -- abstracting out our methods of recording, presenting, processing information. </seg>
<seg id="107"> So for example, the invention of language was a tiny step in that direction. </seg>
<seg id="108"> Telephony, computers, videotapes, CD-ROMs and so on are all our specialized mechanisms that we've now built within our society for handling that information. </seg>
<seg id="109"> And it all connects us together into something that is much bigger and much faster and able to evolve than what we were before. </seg>
<seg id="110"> So now, evolution can take place on a scale of microseconds. </seg>
<seg id="111"> And you saw Ty's little evolutionary example where he sort of did a little bit of evolution on the Convolution program right before your eyes. </seg>
<seg id="112"> So now we've speeded up the time scales once again. </seg>
<seg id="113"> So the first steps of the story that I told you about took a billion years a piece. </seg>
<seg id="114"> And the next steps, like nervous systems and brains, took a few hundred million years. </seg>
<seg id="115"> Then the next steps, like language and so on, took less than a million years. </seg>
<seg id="116"> And these next steps, like electronics, seem to be taking only a few decades. </seg>
<seg id="117"> The process is feeding on itself and becoming, I guess, autocatalytic is the word for it -- when something reinforces its rate of change. </seg>
<seg id="118"> The more it changes, the faster it changes. </seg>
<seg id="119"> And I think that that's what we're seeing here in this explosion of curve. </seg>
<seg id="120"> We're seeing this process feeding back on itself. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Now I design computers for a living, and I know that the mechanisms that I use to design computers would be impossible without recent advances in computers. </seg>
<seg id="122"> So right now, what I do is I design objects at such complexity that it's really impossible for me to design them in the traditional sense. </seg>
<seg id="123"> I don't know what every transistor in the connection machine does. </seg>
<seg id="124"> There are billions of them. </seg>
<seg id="125"> Instead, what I do and what the designers at Thinking Machines do is we think at some level of abstraction and then we hand it to the machine and the machine takes it beyond what we could ever do, much farther and faster than we could ever do. </seg>
<seg id="126"> And in fact, sometimes it takes it by methods that we don't quite even understand. </seg>
<seg id="127"> One method that's particularly interesting that I've been using a lot lately is evolution itself. </seg>
<seg id="128"> So what we do is we put inside the machine a process of evolution that takes place on the microsecond time scale. </seg>
<seg id="129"> So for example, in the most extreme cases, we can actually evolve a program by starting out with random sequences of instructions. </seg>
<seg id="130"> Say, "Computer, would you please make a hundred million random sequences of instructions. </seg>
<seg id="131"> Now would you please run all of those random sequences of instructions, run all of those programs, and pick out the ones that came closest to doing what I wanted." </seg>
<seg id="132"> So in other words, I define what I wanted. </seg>
<seg id="133"> Let's say I want to sort numbers, as a simple example I've done it with. </seg>
<seg id="134"> So find the programs that come closest to sorting numbers. </seg>
<seg id="135"> So of course, random sequences of instructions are very unlikely to sort numbers, so none of them will really do it. </seg>
<seg id="136"> But one of them, by luck, may put two numbers in the right order. </seg>
<seg id="137"> And I say, "Computer, would you please now take the 10 percent of those random sequences that did the best job. </seg>
<seg id="138"> Save those. Kill off the rest. </seg>
<seg id="139"> And now let's reproduce the ones that sorted numbers the best. </seg>
<seg id="140"> And let's reproduce them by a process of recombination analogous to sex." </seg>
<seg id="141"> Take two programs and they produce children by exchanging their subroutines, and the children inherit the traits of the subroutines of the two programs. </seg>
<seg id="142"> So I've got now a new generation of programs that are produced by combinations of the programs that did a little bit better job. </seg>
<seg id="143"> Say, "Please repeat that process." </seg>
<seg id="144"> Score them again. </seg>
<seg id="145"> Introduce some mutations perhaps. </seg>
<seg id="146"> And try that again and do that for another generation. </seg>
<seg id="147"> Well every one of those generations just takes a few milliseconds. </seg>
<seg id="148"> So I can do the equivalent of millions of years of evolution on that within the computer in a few minutes, or in the complicated cases, in a few hours. </seg>
<seg id="149"> At the end of that, I end up with programs that are absolutely perfect at sorting numbers. </seg>
<seg id="150"> In fact, they are programs that are much more efficient than programs I could have ever written by hand. </seg>
<seg id="151"> Now if I look at those programs, I can't tell you how they work. </seg>
<seg id="152"> I've tried looking at them and telling you how they work. </seg>
<seg id="153"> They're obscure, weird programs. </seg>
<seg id="154"> But they do the job. </seg>
<seg id="155"> And in fact, I know, I'm very confident that they do the job because they come from a line of hundreds of thousands of programs that did the job. </seg>
<seg id="156"> In fact, their life depended on doing the job. </seg>
<seg id="157"> I was riding in a 747 with Marvin Minsky once, and he pulls out this card and says, "Oh look. Look at this. </seg>
<seg id="158"> It says, 'This plane has hundreds of thousands of tiny parts working together to make you a safe flight.' Doesn't that make you feel confident?" </seg>
<seg id="159"> In fact, we know that the engineering process doesn't work very well when it gets complicated. </seg>
<seg id="160"> So we're beginning to depend on computers to do a process that's very different than engineering. </seg>
<seg id="161"> And it lets us produce things of much more complexity than normal engineering lets us produce. </seg>
<seg id="162"> And yet, we don't quite understand the options of it. </seg>
<seg id="163"> So in a sense, it's getting ahead of us. </seg>
<seg id="164"> We're now using those programs to make much faster computers so that we'll be able to run this process much faster. </seg>
<seg id="165"> So it's feeding back on itself. </seg>
<seg id="166"> The thing is becoming faster and that's why I think it seems so confusing. </seg>
<seg id="167"> Because all of these technologies are feeding back on themselves. </seg>
<seg id="168"> We're taking off. </seg>
<seg id="169"> And what we are is we're at a point in time which is analogous to when single-celled organisms were turning into multi-celled organisms. </seg>
<seg id="170"> So we're the amoebas and we can't quite figure out what the hell this thing is we're creating. </seg>
<seg id="171"> We're right at that point of transition. </seg>
<seg id="172"> But I think that there really is something coming along after us. </seg>
<seg id="173"> I think it's very haughty of us to think that we're the end product of evolution. </seg>
<seg id="174"> And I think all of us here are a part of producing whatever that next thing is. </seg>
<seg id="175"> So lunch is coming along, and I think I will stop at that point, before I get selected out. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1366" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/shilo_shiv_suleman_using_tech_to_enable_dreaming.html</url>
<description>Has our technology -- our cell phones and iPods and cameras -- stopped us from dreaming? Young artist Shilo Shiv Suleman says no, as she demos "Khoya," her new storybook for iPad, which floats us through a magical world in 7 minutes of pure creativity.</description>
<keywords>art,creativity</keywords>
<talkid>1366</talkid>
<title>Shilo Shiv Suleman: Using tech to enable dreaming</title>
<seg id="1"> My story begins right here actually in Rajasthan about two years ago. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I was in the desert, under the starry skies with the Sufi singer Mukhtiar Ali. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And we were in conversation about how nothing had changed since the time of the ancient Indian epic "The Mahabharata." </seg>
<seg id="4"> So back in the day, when us Indians wanted to travel we'd jump into a chariot and we'd zoom across the sky. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Now we do the same with airplanes. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Back then, when Arjuna, the great Indian warrior prince, when he was thirsty, he'd take out a bow, he'd shoot it into the ground and water would come out. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Now we do the same with drills and machines. </seg>
<seg id="8"> The conclusion that we came to was that magic had been replaced by machinery. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And this made me really sad. </seg>
<seg id="10"> I found myself becoming a little bit of a technophobe. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I was terrified by this idea that I would lose the ability to enjoy and appreciate the sunset without having my camera on me, without tweeting it to my friends. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And it felt like technology should enable magic, not kill it. </seg>
<seg id="13"> When I was a little girl, my grandfather gave me his little silver pocket watch. </seg>
<seg id="14"> And this piece of 50-year-old technology became the most magical thing to me. </seg>
<seg id="15"> It became a gilded gateway into a world full of pirates and shipwrecks and images in my imagination. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So I felt like our cellphones and our fancy watches and our cameras had stopped us from dreaming. </seg>
<seg id="17"> They stopped us from being inspired. </seg>
<seg id="18"> And so I jumped in, I jumped into this world of technology, to see how I could use it to enable magic as opposed to kill it. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I've been illustrating books since I was 16. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And so when I saw the iPad, I saw it as a storytelling device that could connect readers all over the world. </seg>
<seg id="21"> It can know how we're holding it. </seg>
<seg id="22"> It can know where we are. </seg>
<seg id="23"> It brings together image and text and animation and sound and touch. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Storytelling is becoming more and more multi-sensorial. </seg>
<seg id="25"> But what are we doing with it? </seg>
<seg id="26"> So I'm actually just going to go in and launch Khoya, an interactive app for the iPad. </seg>
<seg id="27"> So it says, "Place your fingers upon each light." </seg>
<seg id="28"> And so -- It says, "This box belongs to ... " And so I type in my name. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And actually I become a character in the book. </seg>
<seg id="30"> At various points, a little letter drops down to me -- and the iPad knows where you live because of GPS -- which is actually addressed to me. </seg>
<seg id="31"> The child in me is really excited by these kinds of possibilities. </seg>
<seg id="32"> Now I've been talking a lot about magic. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And I don't mean wizards and dragons, I mean the kind of childhood magic, those ideas that we all harbored as children. </seg>
<seg id="34"> This idea of fireflies in a jar, for some reason, was always really exciting to me. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And so over here you need to tilt your iPad, take the fireflies out. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And they actually illuminate your way through the rest of the book. </seg>
<seg id="37"> Another idea that really fascinated me as a child was that an entire galaxy could be contained within a single marble. </seg>
<seg id="38"> And so over here, each book and each world becomes a little marble that I drag in to this magical device within the device. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And it opens up a map. </seg>
<seg id="40"> All along, all fantasy books have always had maps, but these maps have been static. </seg>
<seg id="41"> This is a map that grows and glows and becomes your navigation for the rest of the book. </seg>
<seg id="42"> It reveals itself to you at certain points in the book as well. </seg>
<seg id="43"> So I'm just going to enter in. </seg>
<seg id="44"> Another thing that's actually really important to me is creating content that is Indian and yet very contemporary. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Over here, these are the Apsaras. </seg>
<seg id="46"> So we've all heard about fairies and we've all heard about nymphs, but how many people outside of India know about their Indian counterparts, the Apsaras? </seg>
<seg id="47"> These poor Apsaras have been trapped inside Indra's chambers for thousands of years in an old and musty book. </seg>
<seg id="48"> And so we're bringing them back in a contemporary story for children. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And a story that actually deals with new issues like the environmental crisis. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Speaking of the environmental crisis, I think a big problem has been in the last 10 years is that children have been locked inside their rooms, glued to their PCs, they haven't been able to get out. </seg>
<seg id="51"> But now with mobile technology, we can actually take our children outside into the natural world with their technology. </seg>
<seg id="52"> One of the interactions in the book is that you're sent off on this quest where you need to go outside, take out your camera on the iPad and collect pictures of different natural objects. </seg>
<seg id="53"> When I was a child, I had multiple collections of sticks and stones and pebbles and shells. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And somehow kids don't do that anymore. </seg>
<seg id="55"> So in bringing back this childhood ritual, you need to go out and, in one chapter, take a picture of a flower and then tag it. </seg>
<seg id="56"> In another chapter, you need to take a picture of a piece of bark and then tag that. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And what happens is that you actually create a digital collection of photographs that you can then put up online. </seg>
<seg id="58"> A child in London puts up a picture of a fox and says, "Oh, I saw a fox today." </seg>
<seg id="59"> A child in India says, "I saw a monkey today." </seg>
<seg id="60"> And it creates this kind of social network around a collection of digital photographs that you've actually taken. </seg>
<seg id="61"> In the possibilities of linking together magic, the earth and technology, there are multiple possibilities. </seg>
<seg id="62"> In the next book, we plan on having an interaction where you take your iPad out with the video on and through augmented reality, you see this layer of animated pixies appear on a houseplant that's outside your house. </seg>
<seg id="63"> At one point, your screen is filled up with leaves. </seg>
<seg id="64"> And so you need to make the sound of wind and blow them away and read the rest of the book. </seg>
<seg id="65"> We're moving, we're all moving here, to a world where the forces of nature come closer together to technology, and magic and technology can come closer together. </seg>
<seg id="66"> We're harnessing energy from the sun. </seg>
<seg id="67"> We're bringing our children and ourselves closer to the natural world and that magic and joy and childhood love that we had through the simple medium of a story. </seg>
<seg id="68"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1378" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/bryan_stevenson_we_need_to_talk_about_an_injustice.html</url>
<description>In an engaging and personal talk -- with cameo appearances from his grandmother and Rosa Parks -- human rights lawyer Bryan Stevenson shares some hard truths about America's justice system, starting with a massive imbalance along racial lines: a third of the country's black male population has been incarcerated at some point in their lives. These issues, which are wrapped up in America's unexamined history, are rarely talked about with this level of candor, insight and persuasiveness.</description>
<keywords>crime,culture,global issues,inequality,law</keywords>
<talkid>1378</talkid>
<title>Bryan Stevenson: We need to talk about an injustice</title>
<seg id="1"> Well this is a really extraordinary honor for me. </seg>
<seg id="2"> I spend most of my time in jails, in prisons, on death row. </seg>
<seg id="3"> I spend most of my time in very low-income communities in the projects and places where there's a great deal of hopelessness. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And being here at TED and seeing the stimulation, hearing it, has been very, very energizing to me. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And one of the things that's emerged in my short time here is that TED has an identity. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And you can actually say things here that have impacts around the world. </seg>
<seg id="7"> And sometimes when it comes through TED, it has meaning and power that it doesn't have when it doesn't. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And I mention that because I think identity is really important. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And we've had some fantastic presentations. </seg>
<seg id="10"> And I think what we've learned is that, if you're a teacher your words can be meaningful, but if you're a compassionate teacher, they can be especially meaningful. </seg>
<seg id="11"> If you're a doctor you can do some good things, but if you're a caring doctor you can do some other things. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And so I want to talk about the power of identity. </seg>
<seg id="13"> And I didn't learn about this actually practicing law and doing the work that I do. </seg>
<seg id="14"> I actually learned about this from my grandmother. </seg>
<seg id="15"> I grew up in a house that was the traditional African American home that was dominated by a matriarch, and that matriarch was my grandmother. </seg>
<seg id="16"> She was tough, she was strong, she was powerful. </seg>
<seg id="17"> She was the end of every argument in our family. </seg>
<seg id="18"> She was the beginning of a lot of arguments in our family. </seg>
<seg id="19"> She was the daughter of people who were actually enslaved. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Her parents were born in slavery in Virginia in the 1840's. </seg>
<seg id="21"> She was born in the 1880's and the experience of slavery very much shaped the way she saw the world. </seg>
<seg id="22"> And my grandmother was tough, but she was also loving. </seg>
<seg id="23"> When I would see her as a little boy, she'd come up to me and she'd give me these hugs. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And she'd squeeze me so tight I could barely breathe and then she'd let me go. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And an hour or two later, if I saw her, she'd come over to me and she'd say, "Bryan, do you still feel me hugging you?" </seg>
<seg id="26"> And if I said, "No," she'd assault me again, and if I said, "Yes," she'd leave me alone. </seg>
<seg id="27"> And she just had this quality that you always wanted to be near her. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And the only challenge was that she had 10 children. </seg>
<seg id="29"> My mom was the youngest of her 10 kids. </seg>
<seg id="30"> And sometimes when I would go and spend time with her, it would be difficult to get her time and attention. </seg>
<seg id="31"> My cousins would be running around everywhere. </seg>
<seg id="32"> And I remember, when I was about eight or nine years old, waking up one morning, going into the living room, and all of my cousins were running around. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And my grandmother was sitting across the room staring at me. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And at first I thought we were playing a game. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And I would look at her and I'd smile, but she was very serious. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And after about 15 or 20 minutes of this, she got up and she came across the room and she took me by the hand and she said, "Come on, Bryan. You and I are going to have a talk." </seg>
<seg id="37"> And I remember this just like it happened yesterday. </seg>
<seg id="38"> I never will forget it. </seg>
<seg id="39"> She took me out back and she said, "Bryan, I'm going to tell you something, but you don't tell anybody what I tell you." </seg>
<seg id="40"> I said, "Okay, Mama." </seg>
<seg id="41"> She said, "Now you make sure you don't do that." I said, "Sure." </seg>
<seg id="42"> Then she sat me down and she looked at me and she said, "I want you to know I've been watching you." </seg>
<seg id="43"> And she said, "I think you're special." </seg>
<seg id="44"> She said, "I think you can do anything you want to do." </seg>
<seg id="45"> I will never forget it. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And then she said, "I just need you to promise me three things, Bryan." </seg>
<seg id="47"> I said, "Okay, Mama." </seg>
<seg id="48"> She said, "The first thing I want you to promise me is that you'll always love your mom." </seg>
<seg id="49"> She said, "That's my baby girl, and you have to promise me now you'll always take care of her." </seg>
<seg id="50"> Well I adored my mom, so I said, "Yes, Mama. I'll do that." </seg>
<seg id="51"> Then she said, "The second thing I want you to promise me is that you'll always do the right thing even when the right thing is the hard thing." </seg>
<seg id="52"> And I thought about it and I said, "Yes, Mama. I'll do that." </seg>
<seg id="53"> Then finally she said, "The third thing I want you to promise me is that you'll never drink alcohol." </seg>
<seg id="54"> Well I was nine years old, so I said, "Yes, Mama. I'll do that." </seg>
<seg id="55"> I grew up in the country in the rural South, and I have a brother a year older than me and a sister a year younger. </seg>
<seg id="56"> When I was about 14 or 15, one day my brother came home and he had this six-pack of beer -- I don't know where he got it -- and he grabbed me and my sister and we went out in the woods. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And we were kind of just out there doing the stuff we crazily did. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And he had a sip of this beer and he gave some to my sister and she had some, and they offered it to me. </seg>
<seg id="59"> I said, "No, no, no. That's okay. You all go ahead. I'm not going to have any beer." </seg>
<seg id="60"> My brother said, "Come on. We're doing this today; you always do what we do. </seg>
<seg id="61"> I had some, your sister had some. Have some beer." </seg>
<seg id="62"> I said, "No, I don't feel right about that. Y'all go ahead. Y'all go ahead." </seg>
<seg id="63"> And then my brother started staring at me. </seg>
<seg id="64"> He said, "What's wrong with you? Have some beer." </seg>
<seg id="65"> Then he looked at me real hard and he said, "Oh, I hope you're not still hung up on that conversation Mama had with you." </seg>
<seg id="66"> I said, "Well, what are you talking about?" </seg>
<seg id="67"> He said, "Oh, Mama tells all the grandkids that they're special." </seg>
<seg id="68"> I was devastated. </seg>
<seg id="69"> And I'm going to admit something to you. </seg>
<seg id="70"> I'm going to tell you something I probably shouldn't. </seg>
<seg id="71"> I know this might be broadcast broadly. </seg>
<seg id="72"> But I'm 52 years old, and I'm going to admit to you that I've never had a drop of alcohol. </seg>
<seg id="73"> I don't say that because I think that's virtuous; I say that because there is power in identity. </seg>
<seg id="74"> When we create the right kind of identity, we can say things to the world around us that they don't actually believe makes sense. </seg>
<seg id="75"> We can get them to do things that they don't think they can do. </seg>
<seg id="76"> When I thought about my grandmother, of course she would think all her grandkids were special. </seg>
<seg id="77"> My grandfather was in prison during prohibition. </seg>
<seg id="78"> My male uncles died of alcohol-related diseases. </seg>
<seg id="79"> And these were the things she thought we needed to commit to. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Well I've been trying to say something about our criminal justice system. </seg>
<seg id="81"> This country is very different today than it was 40 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="82"> In 1972, there were 300,000 people in jails and prisons. </seg>
<seg id="83"> Today, there are 2.3 million. </seg>
<seg id="84"> The United States now has the highest rate of incarceration in the world. </seg>
<seg id="85"> We have seven million people on probation and parole. </seg>
<seg id="86"> And mass incarceration, in my judgment, has fundamentally changed our world. </seg>
<seg id="87"> In poor communities, in communities of color there is this despair, there is this hopelessness, that is being shaped by these outcomes. </seg>
<seg id="88"> One out of three black men between the ages of 18 and 30 is in jail, in prison, on probation or parole. </seg>
<seg id="89"> In urban communities across this country -- Los Angeles, Philadelphia, Baltimore, Washington -- 50 to 60 percent of all young men of color are in jail or prison or on probation or parole. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Our system isn't just being shaped in these ways that seem to be distorting around race, they're also distorted by poverty. </seg>
<seg id="91"> We have a system of justice in this country that treats you much better if you're rich and guilty than if you're poor and innocent. </seg>
<seg id="92"> Wealth, not culpability, shapes outcomes. </seg>
<seg id="93"> And yet, we seem to be very comfortable. </seg>
<seg id="94"> The politics of fear and anger have made us believe that these are problems that are not our problems. </seg>
<seg id="95"> We've been disconnected. </seg>
<seg id="96"> It's interesting to me. </seg>
<seg id="97"> We're looking at some very interesting developments in our work. </seg>
<seg id="98"> My state of Alabama, like a number of states, actually permanently disenfranchises you if you have a criminal conviction. </seg>
<seg id="99"> Right now in Alabama 34 percent of the black male population has permanently lost the right to vote. </seg>
<seg id="100"> We're actually projecting in another 10 years the level of disenfranchisement will be as high as it's been since prior to the passage of the Voting Rights Act. </seg>
<seg id="101"> And there is this stunning silence. </seg>
<seg id="102"> I represent children. </seg>
<seg id="103"> A lot of my clients are very young. </seg>
<seg id="104"> The United States is the only country in the world where we sentence 13-year-old children to die in prison. </seg>
<seg id="105"> We have life imprisonment without parole for kids in this country. </seg>
<seg id="106"> And we're actually doing some litigation. </seg>
<seg id="107"> The only country in the world. </seg>
<seg id="108"> I represent people on death row. </seg>
<seg id="109"> It's interesting, this question of the death penalty. </seg>
<seg id="110"> In many ways, we've been taught to think that the real question is, do people deserve to die for the crimes they've committed? </seg>
<seg id="111"> And that's a very sensible question. </seg>
<seg id="112"> But there's another way of thinking about where we are in our identity. </seg>
<seg id="113"> The other way of thinking about it is not, do people deserve to die for the crimes they commit, but do we deserve to kill? </seg>
<seg id="114"> I mean, it's fascinating. </seg>
<seg id="115"> Death penalty in America is defined by error. </seg>
<seg id="116"> For every nine people who have been executed, we've actually identified one innocent person who's been exonerated and released from death row. </seg>
<seg id="117"> A kind of astonishing error rate -- one out of nine people innocent. </seg>
<seg id="118"> I mean, it's fascinating. </seg>
<seg id="119"> In aviation, we would never let people fly on airplanes if for every nine planes that took off one would crash. </seg>
<seg id="120"> But somehow we can insulate ourselves from this problem. </seg>
<seg id="121"> It's not our problem. </seg>
<seg id="122"> It's not our burden. </seg>
<seg id="123"> It's not our struggle. </seg>
<seg id="124"> I talk a lot about these issues. </seg>
<seg id="125"> I talk about race and this question of whether we deserve to kill. </seg>
<seg id="126"> And it's interesting, when I teach my students about African American history, I tell them about slavery. </seg>
<seg id="127"> I tell them about terrorism, the era that began at the end of reconstruction that went on to World War II. </seg>
<seg id="128"> We don't really know very much about it. </seg>
<seg id="129"> But for African Americans in this country, that was an era defined by terror. </seg>
<seg id="130"> In many communities, people had to worry about being lynched. </seg>
<seg id="131"> They had to worry about being bombed. </seg>
<seg id="132"> It was the threat of terror that shaped their lives. </seg>
<seg id="133"> And these older people come up to me now and they say, "Mr. Stevenson, you give talks, you make speeches, you tell people to stop saying we're dealing with terrorism for the first time in our nation's history after 9/11." </seg>
<seg id="134"> They tell me to say, "No, tell them that we grew up with that." </seg>
<seg id="135"> And that era of terrorism, of course, was followed by segregation and decades of racial subordination and apartheid. </seg>
<seg id="136"> And yet, we have in this country this dynamic where we really don't like to talk about our problems. </seg>
<seg id="137"> We don't like to talk about our history. </seg>
<seg id="138"> And because of that, we really haven't understood what it's meant to do the things we've done historically. </seg>
<seg id="139"> We're constantly running into each other. </seg>
<seg id="140"> We're constantly creating tensions and conflicts. </seg>
<seg id="141"> We have a hard time talking about race, and I believe it's because we are unwilling to commit ourselves to a process of truth and reconciliation. </seg>
<seg id="142"> In South Africa, people understood that we couldn't overcome apartheid without a commitment to truth and reconciliation. </seg>
<seg id="143"> In Rwanda, even after the genocide, there was this commitment, but in this country we haven't done that. </seg>
<seg id="144"> I was giving some lectures in Germany about the death penalty. </seg>
<seg id="145"> It was fascinating because one of the scholars stood up after the presentation and said, "Well you know it's deeply troubling to hear what you're talking about." </seg>
<seg id="146"> He said, "We don't have the death penalty in Germany. </seg>
<seg id="147"> And of course, we can never have the death penalty in Germany." </seg>
<seg id="148"> And the room got very quiet, and this woman said, "There's no way, with our history, we could ever engage in the systematic killing of human beings. </seg>
<seg id="149"> It would be unconscionable for us to, in an intentional and deliberate way, set about executing people." </seg>
<seg id="150"> And I thought about that. </seg>
<seg id="151"> What would it feel like to be living in a world where the nation state of Germany was executing people, especially if they were disproportionately Jewish? </seg>
<seg id="152"> I couldn't bear it. </seg>
<seg id="153"> It would be unconscionable. </seg>
<seg id="154"> And yet, in this country, in the states of the Old South, we execute people -- where you're 11 times more likely to get the death penalty if the victim is white than if the victim is black, 22 times more likely to get it if the defendant is black and the victim is white -- in the very states where there are buried in the ground the bodies of people who were lynched. </seg>
<seg id="155"> And yet, there is this disconnect. </seg>
<seg id="156"> Well I believe that our identity is at risk. </seg>
<seg id="157"> That when we actually don't care about these difficult things, the positive and wonderful things are nonetheless implicated. </seg>
<seg id="158"> We love innovation. </seg>
<seg id="159"> We love technology. We love creativity. </seg>
<seg id="160"> We love entertainment. </seg>
<seg id="161"> But ultimately, those realities are shadowed by suffering, abuse, degradation, marginalization. </seg>
<seg id="162"> And for me, it becomes necessary to integrate the two. </seg>
<seg id="163"> Because ultimately we are talking about a need to be more hopeful, more committed, more dedicated to the basic challenges of living in a complex world. </seg>
<seg id="164"> And for me that means spending time thinking and talking about the poor, the disadvantaged, those who will never get to TED. </seg>
<seg id="165"> But thinking about them in a way that is integrated in our own lives. </seg>
<seg id="166"> You know ultimately, we all have to believe things we haven't seen. </seg>
<seg id="167"> We do. As rational as we are, as committed to intellect as we are. </seg>
<seg id="168"> Innovation, creativity, development comes not from the ideas in our mind alone. </seg>
<seg id="169"> They come from the ideas in our mind that are also fueled by some conviction in our heart. </seg>
<seg id="170"> And it's that mind-heart connection that I believe compels us to not just be attentive to all the bright and dazzly things, but also the dark and difficult things. </seg>
<seg id="171"> Vaclav Havel, the great Czech leader, talked about this. </seg>
<seg id="172"> He said, "When we were in Eastern Europe and dealing with oppression, we wanted all kinds of things, but mostly what we needed was hope, an orientation of the spirit, a willingness to sometimes be in hopeless places and be a witness." </seg>
<seg id="173"> Well that orientation of the spirit is very much at the core of what I believe even TED communities have to be engaged in. </seg>
<seg id="174"> There is no disconnect around technology and design that will allow us to be fully human until we pay attention to suffering, to poverty, to exclusion, to unfairness, to injustice. </seg>
<seg id="175"> Now I will warn you that this kind of identity is a much more challenging identity than ones that don't pay attention to this. </seg>
<seg id="176"> It will get to you. </seg>
<seg id="177"> I had the great privilege, when I was a young lawyer, of meeting Rosa Parks. </seg>
<seg id="178"> And Ms. Parks used to come back to Montgomery every now and then, and she would get together with two of her dearest friends, these older women, Johnnie Carr who was the organizer of the Montgomery bus boycott -- amazing African American woman -- and Virginia Durr, a white woman, whose husband, Clifford Durr, represented Dr. King. </seg>
<seg id="179"> And these women would get together and just talk. </seg>
<seg id="180"> And every now and then Ms. Carr would call me, and she'd say, "Bryan, Ms. Parks is coming to town. We're going to get together and talk. </seg>
<seg id="181"> Do you want to come over and listen?" </seg>
<seg id="182"> And I'd say, "Yes, Ma'am, I do." </seg>
<seg id="183"> And she'd say, "Well what are you going to do when you get here?" </seg>
<seg id="184"> I said, "I'm going to listen." </seg>
<seg id="185"> And I'd go over there and I would, I would just listen. </seg>
<seg id="186"> It would be so energizing and so empowering. </seg>
<seg id="187"> And one time I was over there listening to these women talk, and after a couple of hours Ms. Parks turned to me and she said, "Now Bryan, tell me what the Equal Justice Initiative is. </seg>
<seg id="188"> Tell me what you're trying to do." </seg>
<seg id="189"> And I began giving her my rap. </seg>
<seg id="190"> I said, "Well we're trying to challenge injustice. </seg>
<seg id="191"> We're trying to help people who have been wrongly convicted. </seg>
<seg id="192"> We're trying to confront bias and discrimination in the administration of criminal justice. </seg>
<seg id="193"> We're trying to end life without parole sentences for children. </seg>
<seg id="194"> We're trying to do something about the death penalty. </seg>
<seg id="195"> We're trying to reduce the prison population. </seg>
<seg id="196"> We're trying to end mass incarceration." </seg>
<seg id="197"> I gave her my whole rap, and when I finished she looked at me and she said, "Mmm mmm mmm." </seg>
<seg id="198"> She said, "That's going to make you tired, tired, tired." </seg>
<seg id="199"> And that's when Ms. Carr leaned forward, she put her finger in my face, she said, "That's why you've got to be brave, brave, brave." </seg>
<seg id="200"> And I actually believe that the TED community needs to be more courageous. </seg>
<seg id="201"> We need to find ways to embrace these challenges, these problems, the suffering. </seg>
<seg id="202"> Because ultimately, our humanity depends on everyone's humanity. </seg>
<seg id="203"> I've learned very simple things doing the work that I do. </seg>
<seg id="204"> It's just taught me very simple things. </seg>
<seg id="205"> that each of us is more than the worst thing we've ever done. </seg>
<seg id="206"> I believe that for every person on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="207"> I think if somebody tells a lie, they're not just a liar. </seg>
<seg id="208"> I think if somebody takes something that doesn't belong to them, they're not just a thief. </seg>
<seg id="209"> I think even if you kill someone, you're not just a killer. </seg>
<seg id="210"> And because of that there's this basic human dignity that must be respected by law. </seg>
<seg id="211"> I also believe that in many parts of this country, and certainly in many parts of this globe, that the opposite of poverty is not wealth. </seg>
<seg id="212"> I don't believe that. </seg>
<seg id="213"> I actually think, in too many places, the opposite of poverty is justice. </seg>
<seg id="214"> And finally, I believe that, despite the fact that it is so dramatic and so beautiful and so inspiring and so stimulating, we will ultimately not be judged by our technology, we won't be judged by our design, we won't be judged by our intellect and reason. </seg>
<seg id="215"> Ultimately, you judge the character of a society, not by how they treat their rich and the powerful and the privileged, but by how they treat the poor, the condemned, the incarcerated. </seg>
<seg id="216"> Because it's in that nexus that we actually begin to understand truly profound things about who we are. </seg>
<seg id="217"> I sometimes get out of balance. I'll end with this story. </seg>
<seg id="218"> I sometimes push too hard. </seg>
<seg id="219"> I do get tired, as we all do. </seg>
<seg id="220"> Sometimes those ideas get ahead of our thinking in ways that are important. </seg>
<seg id="221"> And I've been representing these kids who have been sentenced to do these very harsh sentences. </seg>
<seg id="222"> And I go to the jail and I see my client who's 13 and 14, and he's been certified to stand trial as an adult. </seg>
<seg id="223"> I start thinking, well, how did that happen? </seg>
<seg id="224"> How can a judge turn you into something that you're not? </seg>
<seg id="225"> And the judge has certified him as an adult, but I see this kid. </seg>
<seg id="226"> And I was up too late one night and I starting thinking, well gosh, if the judge can turn you into something that you're not, the judge must have magic power. </seg>
<seg id="227"> Yeah, Bryan, the judge has some magic power. </seg>
<seg id="228"> You should ask for some of that. </seg>
<seg id="229"> And because I was up too late, wasn't thinking real straight, I started working on a motion. </seg>
<seg id="230"> And I had a client who was 14 years old, a young, poor black kid. </seg>
<seg id="231"> And I started working on this motion, and the head of the motion was: "Motion to try my poor, 14-year-old black male client like a privileged, white 75-year-old corporate executive." </seg>
<seg id="232"> And I put in my motion that there was prosecutorial misconduct and police misconduct and judicial misconduct. </seg>
<seg id="233"> There was a crazy line in there about how there's no conduct in this county, it's all misconduct. </seg>
<seg id="234"> And the next morning, I woke up and I thought, now did I dream that crazy motion, or did I actually write it? </seg>
<seg id="235"> And to my horror, not only had I written it, but I had sent it to court. </seg>
<seg id="236"> A couple months went by, and I had just forgotten all about it. </seg>
<seg id="237"> And I finally decided, oh gosh, I've got to go to the court and do this crazy case. </seg>
<seg id="238"> And I got into my car and I was feeling really overwhelmed -- overwhelmed. </seg>
<seg id="239"> And I got in my car and I went to this courthouse. </seg>
<seg id="240"> And I was thinking, this is going to be so difficult, so painful. </seg>
<seg id="241"> And I finally got out of the car and I started walking up to the courthouse. </seg>
<seg id="242"> And as I was walking up the steps of this courthouse, there was an older black man who was the janitor in this courthouse. </seg>
<seg id="243"> When this man saw me, he came over to me and he said, "Who are you?" </seg>
<seg id="244"> I said, "I'm a lawyer." He said, "You're a lawyer?" I said, "Yes, sir." </seg>
<seg id="245"> And this man came over to me and he hugged me. </seg>
<seg id="246"> And he whispered in my ear. </seg>
<seg id="247"> He said, "I'm so proud of you." </seg>
<seg id="248"> And I have to tell you, it was energizing. </seg>
<seg id="249"> It connected deeply with something in me about identity, about the capacity of every person to contribute to a community, to a perspective that is hopeful. </seg>
<seg id="250"> Well I went into the courtroom. </seg>
<seg id="251"> And as soon as I walked inside, the judge saw me coming in. </seg>
<seg id="252"> He said, "Mr. Stevenson, did you write this crazy motion?" </seg>
<seg id="253"> I said, "Yes, sir. I did." And we started arguing. </seg>
<seg id="254"> And people started coming in because they were just outraged. </seg>
<seg id="255"> I had written these crazy things. </seg>
<seg id="256"> And police officers were coming in and assistant prosecutors and clerk workers. </seg>
<seg id="257"> And before I knew it, the courtroom was filled with people angry that we were talking about race, that we were talking about poverty, that we were talking about inequality. </seg>
<seg id="258"> And out of the corner of my eye, I could see this janitor pacing back and forth. </seg>
<seg id="259"> And he kept looking through the window, and he could hear all of this holler. </seg>
<seg id="260"> He kept pacing back and forth. </seg>
<seg id="261"> And finally, this older black man with this very worried look on his face came into the courtroom and sat down behind me, almost at counsel table. </seg>
<seg id="262"> About 10 minutes later the judge said we would take a break. </seg>
<seg id="263"> And during the break there was a deputy sheriff who was offended that the janitor had come into court. </seg>
<seg id="264"> And this deputy jumped up and he ran over to this older black man. </seg>
<seg id="265"> He said, "Jimmy, what are you doing in this courtroom?" </seg>
<seg id="266"> And this older black man stood up and he looked at that deputy and he looked at me and he said, "I came into this courtroom to tell this young man, keep your eyes on the prize, hold on." </seg>
<seg id="267"> I've come to TED because I believe that many of you understand that the moral arc of the universe is long, but it bends toward justice. </seg>
<seg id="268"> That we cannot be full evolved human beings until we care about human rights and basic dignity. </seg>
<seg id="269"> That all of our survival is tied to the survival of everyone. </seg>
<seg id="270"> That our visions of technology and design and entertainment and creativity have to be married with visions of humanity, compassion and justice. </seg>
<seg id="271"> And more than anything, for those of you who share that, I've simply come to tell you to keep your eyes on the prize, hold on. </seg>
<seg id="272"> So you heard and saw an obvious desire by this audience, this community, to help you on your way and to do something on this issue. </seg>
<seg id="273"> Other than writing a check, what could we do? </seg>
<seg id="274"> Well there are opportunities all around us. </seg>
<seg id="275"> If you live in the state of California, for example, there's a referendum coming up this spring where actually there's going to be an effort to redirect some of the money we spend on the politics of punishment. </seg>
<seg id="276"> For example, here in California we're going to spend one billion dollars on the death penalty in the next five years -- one billion dollars. </seg>
<seg id="277"> And yet, 46 percent of all homicide cases don't result in arrest. </seg>
<seg id="278"> 56 percent of all rape cases don't result. </seg>
<seg id="279"> So there's an opportunity to change that. </seg>
<seg id="280"> And this referendum would propose having those dollars go to law enforcement and safety. </seg>
<seg id="281"> And I think that opportunity exists all around us. </seg>
<seg id="282"> There's been this huge decline in crime in America over the last three decades. </seg>
<seg id="283"> And part of the narrative of that is sometimes that it's about increased incarceration rates. </seg>
<seg id="284"> What would you say to someone who believed that? </seg>
<seg id="285"> Well actually the violent crime rate has remained relatively stable. </seg>
<seg id="286"> The great increase in mass incarceration in this country wasn't really in violent crime categories. </seg>
<seg id="287"> It was this misguided war on drugs. </seg>
<seg id="288"> That's where the dramatic increases have come in our prison population. </seg>
<seg id="289"> And we got carried away with the rhetoric of punishment. </seg>
<seg id="290"> And so we have three strikes laws that put people in prison forever for stealing a bicycle, for low-level property crimes, rather than making them give those resources back to the people who they victimized. </seg>
<seg id="291"> I believe we need to do more to help people who are victimized by crime, not do less. </seg>
<seg id="292"> And I think our current punishment philosophy does nothing for no one. </seg>
<seg id="293"> And I think that's the orientation that we have to change. </seg>
<seg id="294"> Bryan, you've struck a massive chord here. </seg>
<seg id="295"> You're an inspiring person. </seg>
<seg id="296"> Thank you so much for coming to TED. Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1375" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/peter_diamandis_abundance_is_our_future.html</url>
<description>Onstage at TED2012, Peter Diamandis makes a case for optimism -- that we'll invent, innovate and create ways to solve the challenges that loom over us. "I'm not saying we don't have our set of problems; we surely do. But ultimately, we knock them down."</description>
<keywords>cities,invention,sustainability,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1375</talkid>
<title> Abundance is our future</title>
<seg id="1"> Threats, in the wake of Bin Laden's death, have spiked. </seg>
<seg id="2"> Famine in Somalia. Police pepper spray. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Vicious cartels. Announcer Five: Caustic cruise lines. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Societal decay. 65 dead. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Tsunami warning. Cyber-attacks. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Drug war. Mass destruction. Tornado. </seg>
<seg id="7"> Recession. Default. Doomsday. Egypt. Syria. </seg>
<seg id="8"> Crisis. Death. Disaster. </seg>
<seg id="9"> Oh, my God. </seg>
<seg id="10"> So those are just a few of the clips I collected over the last six months -- could have easily been the last six days or the last six years. </seg>
<seg id="11"> The point is that the news media preferentially feeds us negative stories because that's what our minds pay attention to. </seg>
<seg id="12"> And there's a very good reason for that. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Every second of every day, our senses bring in way too much data than we can possibly process in our brains. </seg>
<seg id="14"> And because nothing is more important to us than survival, the first stop of all of that data is an ancient sliver of the temporal lobe called the amygdala. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Now the amygdala is our early warning detector, our danger detector. </seg>
<seg id="16"> It sorts and scours through all of the information looking for anything in the environment that might harm us. </seg>
<seg id="17"> So given a dozen news stories, we will preferentially look at the negative news. </seg>
<seg id="18"> And that old newspaper saying, "If it bleeds it leads," is very true. </seg>
<seg id="19"> So given all of our digital devices that are bringing all the negative news to us seven days a week, 24 hours a day, it's no wonder that we're pessimistic. </seg>
<seg id="20"> It's no wonder that people think that the world is getting worse. </seg>
<seg id="21"> But perhaps that's not the case. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Perhaps instead, of what's really going on. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Perhaps the tremendous progress we've made over the last century by a series of forces are, in fact, accelerating to a point that we have the potential in the next three decades to create a world of abundance. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Now I'm not saying we don't have our set of problems -- climate crisis, species extinction, water and energy shortage -- we surely do. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And as humans, we are far better at seeing the problems way in advance, but ultimately we knock them down. </seg>
<seg id="26"> So let's look at what this last century has been to see where we're going. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Over the last hundred years, the average human lifespan has more than doubled, average per capita income adjusted for inflation around the world has tripled. </seg>
<seg id="28"> Childhood mortality has come down a factor of 10. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Add to that the cost of food, electricity, transportation, communication have dropped 10 to 1,000-fold. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Steve Pinker has showed us that, in fact, we're living during the most peaceful time ever in human history. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And Charles Kenny that global literacy has gone from 25 percent to over 80 percent in the last 130 years. </seg>
<seg id="32"> We truly are living in an extraordinary time. </seg>
<seg id="33"> And many people forget this. </seg>
<seg id="34"> And we keep setting our expectations higher and higher. </seg>
<seg id="35"> In fact, we redefine what poverty means. </seg>
<seg id="36"> Think of this, in America today, the majority of people under the poverty line still have electricity, water, toilets, refrigerators, television, mobile phones, air conditioning and cars. </seg>
<seg id="37"> The wealthiest robber barons of the last century, the emperors on this planet, could have never dreamed of such luxuries. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Underpinning much of this is technology, and of late, exponentially growing technologies. </seg>
<seg id="39"> My good friend Ray Kurzweil showed that any tool that becomes an information technology jumps on this curve, on Moore's Law, and experiences price performance doubling every 12 to 24 months. </seg>
<seg id="40"> That's why the cellphone in your pocket is literally a million times cheaper and a thousand times faster than a supercomputer of the '70s. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Now look at this curve. </seg>
<seg id="42"> This is Moore's Law over the last hundred years. </seg>
<seg id="43"> I want you to notice two things from this curve. </seg>
<seg id="44"> Number one, how smooth it is -- through good time and bad time, war time and peace time, recession, depression and boom time. </seg>
<seg id="45"> This is the result of faster computers being used to build faster computers. </seg>
<seg id="46"> It doesn't slow for any of our grand challenges. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And also, even though it's plotted on a log curve on the left, it's curving upwards. </seg>
<seg id="48"> The rate at which the technology is getting faster is itself getting faster. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And on this curve, riding on Moore's Law, are a set of extraordinarily powerful technologies available to all of us. </seg>
<seg id="50"> Cloud computing, what my friends at Autodesk call infinite computing; sensors and networks; robotics; 3D printing, which is the ability to democratize and distribute personalized production around the planet; synthetic biology; fuels, vaccines and foods; digital medicine; nanomaterials; and A.I. </seg>
<seg id="51"> I mean, how many of you saw the winning of Jeopardy by IBM's Watson? </seg>
<seg id="52"> I mean, that was epic. </seg>
<seg id="53"> In fact, I scoured the headlines looking for the best headline in a newspaper I could. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And I love this: "Watson Vanquishes Human Opponents." </seg>
<seg id="55"> Jeopardy's not an easy game. </seg>
<seg id="56"> It's about the nuance of human language. </seg>
<seg id="57"> And imagine if you would A.I.'s like this on the cloud available to every person with a cellphone. </seg>
<seg id="58"> Four years ago here at TED, Ray Kurzweil and I started a new university called Singularity University. </seg>
<seg id="59"> And we teach our students all of these technologies, and particularly how they can be used to solve humanity's grand challenges. </seg>
<seg id="60"> And every year we ask them to start a company or a product or a service that can affect positively the lives of a billion people within a decade. </seg>
<seg id="61"> Think about that, the fact that, literally, a group of students can touch the lives of a billion people today. </seg>
<seg id="62"> 30 years ago that would have sounded ludicrous. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Today we can point at dozens of companies that have done just that. </seg>
<seg id="64"> When I think about creating abundance, it's not about creating a life of luxury for everybody on this planet; it's about creating a life of possibility. </seg>
<seg id="65"> It is about taking that which was scarce and making it abundant. </seg>
<seg id="66"> You see, scarcity is contextual, and technology is a resource-liberating force. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Let me give you an example. </seg>
<seg id="68"> So this is a story of Napoleon III in the mid-1800s. </seg>
<seg id="69"> He's the dude on the left. </seg>
<seg id="70"> He invited over to dinner the king of Siam. </seg>
<seg id="71"> All of Napoleon's troops were fed with silver utensils, Napoleon himself with gold utensils. </seg>
<seg id="72"> But the King of Siam, he was fed with aluminum utensils. </seg>
<seg id="73"> You see, aluminum was the most valuable metal on the planet, worth more than gold and platinum. </seg>
<seg id="74"> It's the reason that the tip of the Washington Monument is made of aluminum. </seg>
<seg id="75"> You see, even though aluminum is 8.3 percent of the Earth by mass, it doesn't come as a pure metal. </seg>
<seg id="76"> It's all bound by oxygen and silicates. </seg>
<seg id="77"> But then the technology of electrolysis came along and literally made aluminum so cheap that we use it with throw-away mentality. </seg>
<seg id="78"> So let's project this analogy going forward. </seg>
<seg id="79"> We think about energy scarcity. </seg>
<seg id="80"> Ladies and gentlemen, we are on a planet that is bathed with 5,000 times more energy than we use in a year. </seg>
<seg id="81"> 16 terawatts of energy hits the Earth's surface every 88 minutes. </seg>
<seg id="82"> It's not about being scarce, it's about accessibility. </seg>
<seg id="83"> And there's good news here. </seg>
<seg id="84"> For the first time, this year the cost of solar-generated electricity is 50 percent that of diesel-generated electricity in India -- 8.8 rupees versus 17 rupees. </seg>
<seg id="85"> The cost of solar dropped 50 percent last year. </seg>
<seg id="86"> Last month, MIT put out a study showing that by the end of this decade, in the sunny parts of the United States, solar electricity will be six cents a kilowatt hour compared to 15 cents as a national average. </seg>
<seg id="87"> And if we have abundant energy, we also have abundant water. </seg>
<seg id="88"> Now we talk about water wars. </seg>
<seg id="89"> Do you remember when Carl Sagan turned the Voyager spacecraft back towards the Earth, in 1990 after it just passed Saturn? </seg>
<seg id="90"> He took a famous photo. What was it called? </seg>
<seg id="91"> "A Pale Blue Dot." </seg>
<seg id="92"> Because we live on a water planet. </seg>
<seg id="93"> We live on a planet 70 percent covered by water. </seg>
<seg id="94"> Yes, 97.5 percent is saltwater, two percent is ice, and we fight over a half a percent of the water on this planet, but here too there is hope. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And there is technology coming online, not 10, 20 years from now, right now. </seg>
<seg id="96"> There's nanotechnology coming on, nanomaterials. </seg>
<seg id="97"> And the conversation I had with Dean Kamen this morning, one of the great DIY innovators, I'd like to share with you -- he gave me permission to do so -- his technology called Slingshot that many of you may have heard of, it is the size of a small dorm room refrigerator. </seg>
<seg id="98"> It's able to generate a thousand liters of clean drinking water a day out of any source -- saltwater, polluted water, latrine -- at less than two cents a liter. </seg>
<seg id="99"> The chairman of Coca-Cola has just agreed to do a major test of hundreds of units of this in the developing world. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And if that pans out, which I have every confidence it will, Coca-Cola will deploy this globally to 206 countries around the planet. </seg>
<seg id="101"> This is the kind of innovation, empowered by this technology, that exists today. </seg>
<seg id="102"> And we've seen this in cellphones. </seg>
<seg id="103"> My goodness, we're going to hit 70 percent penetration of cellphones in the developing world by the end of 2013. </seg>
<seg id="104"> Think about it, that a Masai warrior on a cellphone in the middle of Kenya has better mobile comm than President Reagan did 25 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="105"> And if they're on a smartphone on Google, they've got access to more knowledge and information than President Clinton did 15 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="106"> They're living in a world of information and communication abundance that no one could have ever predicted. </seg>
<seg id="107"> Better than that, the things that you and I spent tens and hundreds of thousands of dollars for -- GPS, HD video and still images, libraries of books and music, medical diagnostic technology -- are now literally dematerializing and demonetizing into your cellphone. </seg>
<seg id="108"> Probably the best part of it is what's coming down the pike in health. </seg>
<seg id="109"> Last month, I had the pleasure of announcing with Qualcomm Foundation something called the $10 million Qualcomm Tricorder X Prize. </seg>
<seg id="110"> We're challenging teams around the world to basically combine these technologies into a mobile device that you can speak to, because it's got A.I., you can cough on it, you can do a finger blood prick. </seg>
<seg id="111"> And to win, it needs to be able to diagnose you better than a team of board-certified doctors. </seg>
<seg id="112"> So literally, imagine this device in the middle of the developing world where there are no doctors, 25 percent of the disease burden and 1.3 percent of the health care workers. </seg>
<seg id="113"> When this device sequences an RNA or DNA virus that it doesn't recognize, it calls the CDC and prevents the pandemic from happening in the first place. </seg>
<seg id="114"> But here, here is the biggest force for bringing about a world of abundance. </seg>
<seg id="115"> I call it the rising billion. </seg>
<seg id="116"> So the white lines here are population. </seg>
<seg id="117"> We just passed the seven billion mark on Earth. </seg>
<seg id="118"> And by the way, the biggest protection against a population explosion is making the world educated and healthy. </seg>
<seg id="119"> In 2010, we had just short of two billion people online, connected. </seg>
<seg id="120"> By 2020, that's going from two billion to five billion Internet users. </seg>
<seg id="121"> Three billion new minds who have never been heard from before are connecting to the global conversation. </seg>
<seg id="122"> What will these people want? </seg>
<seg id="123"> What will they consume? What will they desire? </seg>
<seg id="124"> And rather than having economic shutdown, we're about to have the biggest economic injection ever. </seg>
<seg id="125"> These people represent tens of trillions of dollars injected into the global economy. </seg>
<seg id="126"> And they will get healthier by using the Tricorder, and they'll become better educated by using the Khan Academy, and by literally being able to use 3D printing and infinite computing [become] more productive than ever before. </seg>
<seg id="127"> So what could three billion rising, healthy, educated, productive members of humanity bring to us? </seg>
<seg id="128"> How about a set of voices that have never been heard from before. </seg>
<seg id="129"> What about giving the oppressed, wherever they might be, the voice to be heard and the voice to act for the first time ever? </seg>
<seg id="130"> What will these three billion people bring? </seg>
<seg id="131"> What about contributions we can't even predict? </seg>
<seg id="132"> The one thing I've learned at the X Prize is that small teams driven by their passion with a clear focus can do extraordinary things, things that large corporations and governments could only do in the past. </seg>
<seg id="133"> Let me share and close with a story that really got me excited. </seg>
<seg id="134"> There is a program that some of you might have heard of. </seg>
<seg id="135"> It's a game called Foldit. </seg>
<seg id="136"> It came out of the University of Washington in Seattle. </seg>
<seg id="137"> And this is a game where individuals can actually take a sequence of amino acids and figure out how the protein is going to fold. </seg>
<seg id="138"> And how it folds dictates its structure and its functionality. </seg>
<seg id="139"> And it's very important for research in medicine. </seg>
<seg id="140"> And up until now, it's been a supercomputer problem. </seg>
<seg id="141"> And this game has been played by university professors and so forth. </seg>
<seg id="142"> And it's literally, hundreds of thousands of people came online and started playing it. </seg>
<seg id="143"> And it showed that, in fact, today, the human pattern recognition machinery is better at folding proteins than the best computers. </seg>
<seg id="144"> And when these individuals went and looked at who was the best protein folder in the world, it wasn't an MIT professor, it wasn't a CalTech student, it was a person from England, from Manchester, a woman who, during the day, was an executive assistant at a rehab clinic and, at night, was the world's best protein folder. </seg>
<seg id="145"> Ladies and gentlemen, what gives me tremendous confidence in the future is the fact that we are now more empowered as individuals to take on the grand challenges of this planet. </seg>
<seg id="146"> We have the tools with this exponential technology. </seg>
<seg id="147"> We have the passion of the DIY innovator. </seg>
<seg id="148"> We have the capital of the techno-philanthropist. </seg>
<seg id="149"> And we have three billion new minds coming online to work with us to solve the grand challenges, to do that which we must do. </seg>
<seg id="150"> We are living into extraordinary decades ahead. </seg>
<seg id="151"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1337" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/brian_goldman_doctors_make_mistakes_can_we_talk_about_that.html</url>
<description>Every doctor makes mistakes. But, says physician Brian Goldman, medicine's culture of denial keeps doctors from ever talking about those mistakes, or using them to learn and improve. Telling stories from his own long practice, he calls on doctors to start talking about being wrong. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
<keywords>communication,culture,medicine</keywords>
<talkid>1337</talkid>
<title>Brian Goldman: Doctors make mistakes. Can we talk about that?</title>
<seg id="1"> I think we have to do something about a piece of the culture of medicine that has to change. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And I think it starts with one physician, and that's me. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And maybe I've been around long enough that I can afford to give away some of my false prestige to be able to do that. </seg>
<seg id="4"> Before I actually begin the meat of my talk, let's begin with a bit of baseball. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Hey, why not? </seg>
<seg id="6"> We're near the end, we're getting close to the World Series. </seg>
<seg id="7"> We all love baseball, don't we? </seg>
<seg id="8"> Baseball is filled with some amazing statistics. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And there's hundreds of them. </seg>
<seg id="10"> "Moneyball" is about to come out, and it's all about statistics and using statistics to build a great baseball team. </seg>
<seg id="11"> I'm going to focus on one stat that I hope a lot of you have heard of. </seg>
<seg id="12"> It's called batting average. </seg>
<seg id="13"> So we talk about a 300, a batter who bats 300. </seg>
<seg id="14"> That means that ballplayer batted safely, hit safely three times out of 10 at bats. </seg>
<seg id="15"> That means hit the ball into the outfield, it dropped, it didn't get caught, and whoever tried to throw it to first base didn't get there in time and the runner was safe. </seg>
<seg id="16"> Three times out of 10. </seg>
<seg id="17"> Do you know what they call a 300 hitter in Major League Baseball? </seg>
<seg id="18"> Good, really good, maybe an all-star. </seg>
<seg id="19"> Do you know what they call a 400 baseball hitter? </seg>
<seg id="20"> That's somebody who hit, by the way, four times safely out of every 10. </seg>
<seg id="21"> Legendary -- as in Ted Williams legendary -- the last Major League Baseball player to hit over 400 during a regular season. </seg>
<seg id="22"> Now let's take this back into my world of medicine where I'm a lot more comfortable, or perhaps a bit less comfortable after what I'm going to talk to you about. </seg>
<seg id="23"> Suppose you have appendicitis and you're referred to a surgeon who's batting 400 on appendectomies. </seg>
<seg id="24"> Somehow this isn't working out, is it? </seg>
<seg id="25"> Now suppose you live in a certain part of a certain remote place and you have a loved one who has blockages in two coronary arteries and your family doctor refers that loved one to a cardiologist who's batting 200 on angioplasties. </seg>
<seg id="26"> But, but, you know what? </seg>
<seg id="27"> She's doing a lot better this year. She's on the comeback trail. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And she's hitting a 257. </seg>
<seg id="29"> Somehow this isn't working. </seg>
<seg id="30"> But I'm going to ask you a question. </seg>
<seg id="31"> What do you think a batting average for a cardiac surgeon or a nurse practitioner or an orthopedic surgeon, an OBGYN, a paramedic is supposed to be? </seg>
<seg id="32"> 1,000, very good. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Now truth of the matter is, nobody knows in all of medicine what a good surgeon or physician or paramedic is supposed to bat. </seg>
<seg id="34"> What we do though is we send each one of them, including myself, out into the world with the admonition, be perfect. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Never ever, ever make a mistake, but you worry about the details, about how that's going to happen. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And that was the message that I absorbed when I was in med school. </seg>
<seg id="37"> I was an obsessive compulsive student. </seg>
<seg id="38"> In high school, a classmate once said that Brian Goldman would study for a blood test. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And so I did. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And I studied in my little garret at the nurses' residence at Toronto General Hospital, not far from here. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And I memorized everything. </seg>
<seg id="42"> I memorized in my anatomy class the origins and exertions of every muscle, every branch of every artery that came off the aorta, differential diagnoses obscure and common. </seg>
<seg id="43"> I even knew the differential diagnosis in how to classify renal tubular acidosis. </seg>
<seg id="44"> And all the while, I was amassing more and more knowledge. </seg>
<seg id="45"> And I did well, I graduated with honors, cum laude. </seg>
<seg id="46"> And I came out of medical school with the impression that if I memorized everything and knew everything, or as much as possible, as close to everything as possible, that it would immunize me against making mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And it worked for a while, until I met Mrs. Drucker. </seg>
<seg id="48"> I was a resident at a teaching hospital here in Toronto when Mrs. Drucker was brought to the emergency department of the hospital where I was working. </seg>
<seg id="49"> At the time I was assigned to the cardiology service on a cardiology rotation. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And it was my job, when the emergency staff called for a cardiology consult, to see that patient in emerg. </seg>
<seg id="51"> and to report back to my attending. </seg>
<seg id="52"> And I saw Mrs. Drucker, and she was breathless. </seg>
<seg id="53"> And when I listened to her, she was making a wheezy sound. </seg>
<seg id="54"> And when I listened to her chest with a stethoscope, I could hear crackly sounds on both sides that told me that she was in congestive heart failure. </seg>
<seg id="55"> This is a condition in which the heart fails, and instead of being able to pump all the blood forward, some of the blood backs up into the lung, the lungs fill up with blood, and that's why you have shortness of breath. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And that wasn't a difficult diagnosis to make. </seg>
<seg id="57"> I made it and I set to work treating her. </seg>
<seg id="58"> I gave her aspirin. I gave her medications to relieve the strain on her heart. </seg>
<seg id="59"> I gave her medications that we call diuretics, water pills, to get her to pee out the access fluid. </seg>
<seg id="60"> And over the course of the next hour and a half or two, she started to feel better. </seg>
<seg id="61"> And I felt really good. </seg>
<seg id="62"> And that's when I made my first mistake; I sent her home. </seg>
<seg id="63"> Actually, I made two more mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="64"> I sent her home without speaking to my attending. </seg>
<seg id="65"> I didn't pick up the phone and do what I was supposed to do, which was call my attending and run the story by him so he would have a chance to see her for himself. </seg>
<seg id="66"> And he knew her, he would have been able to furnish additional information about her. </seg>
<seg id="67"> Maybe I did it for a good reason. </seg>
<seg id="68"> Maybe I didn't want to be a high-maintenance resident. </seg>
<seg id="69"> Maybe I wanted to be so successful and so able to take responsibility that I would do so and I would be able to take care of my attending's patients without even having to contact him. </seg>
<seg id="70"> The second mistake that I made was worse. </seg>
<seg id="71"> In sending her home, I disregarded a little voice deep down inside that was trying to tell me, "Goldman, not a good idea. Don't do this." </seg>
<seg id="72"> In fact, so lacking in confidence was I that I actually asked the nurse who was looking after Mrs. Drucker, "Do you think it's okay if she goes home?" </seg>
<seg id="73"> And the nurse thought about it and said very matter-of-factly, "Yeah, I think she'll do okay." </seg>
<seg id="74"> I can remember that like it was yesterday. </seg>
<seg id="75"> So I signed the discharge papers, and an ambulance came, paramedics came to take her home. </seg>
<seg id="76"> And I went back to my work on the wards. </seg>
<seg id="77"> All the rest of that day, that afternoon, I had this kind of gnawing feeling inside my stomach. </seg>
<seg id="78"> But I carried on with my work. </seg>
<seg id="79"> And at the end of the day, I packed up to leave the hospital and walked to the parking lot to take my car and drive home when I did something that I don't usually do. </seg>
<seg id="80"> I walked through the emergency department on my way home. </seg>
<seg id="81"> And it was there that another nurse, not the nurse who was looking after Mrs. Drucker before, but another nurse, said three words to me that are the three words that most emergency physicians I know dread. </seg>
<seg id="82"> Others in medicine dread them as well, but there's something particular about emergency medicine because we see patients so fleetingly. </seg>
<seg id="83"> The three words are: Do you remember? </seg>
<seg id="84"> "Do you remember that patient you sent home?" </seg>
<seg id="85"> the other nurse asked matter-of-factly. </seg>
<seg id="86"> "Well she's back," in just that tone of voice. </seg>
<seg id="87"> Well she was back all right. </seg>
<seg id="88"> She was back and near death. </seg>
<seg id="89"> About an hour after she had arrived home, after I'd sent her home, she collapsed and her family called 911 and the paramedics brought her back to the emergency department where she had a blood pressure of 50, which is in severe shock. </seg>
<seg id="90"> And she was barely breathing and she was blue. </seg>
<seg id="91"> And the emerg. staff pulled out all the stops. </seg>
<seg id="92"> They gave her medications to raise her blood pressure. </seg>
<seg id="93"> They put her on a ventilator. </seg>
<seg id="94"> And I was shocked and shaken to the core. </seg>
<seg id="95"> And I went through this roller coaster, because after they stabilized her, she went to the intensive care unit, and I hoped against hope that she would recover. </seg>
<seg id="96"> And over the next two or three days, it was clear that she was never going to wake up. </seg>
<seg id="97"> She had irreversible brain damage. </seg>
<seg id="98"> And the family gathered. </seg>
<seg id="99"> And over the course of the next eight or nine days, they resigned themselves to what was happening. </seg>
<seg id="100"> And at about the nine day mark, they let her go -- Mrs. Drucker, a wife, a mother and a grandmother. </seg>
<seg id="101"> They say you never forget the names of those who die. </seg>
<seg id="102"> And that was my first time to be acquainted with that. </seg>
<seg id="103"> Over the next few weeks, I beat myself up and I experienced for the first time the unhealthy shame that exists in our culture of medicine -- where I felt alone, isolated, not feeling the healthy kind of shame that you feel, because you can't talk about it with your colleagues. </seg>
<seg id="104"> You know that healthy kind, when you betray a secret that a best friend made you promise never to reveal and then you get busted and then your best friend confronts you and you have terrible discussions, but at the end of it all that sick feeling guides you and you say, I'll never make that mistake again. </seg>
<seg id="105"> And you make amends and you never make that mistake again. </seg>
<seg id="106"> That's the kind of shame that is a teacher. </seg>
<seg id="107"> The unhealthy shame I'm talking about is the one that makes you so sick inside. </seg>
<seg id="108"> It's the one that says, not that what you did was bad, but that you are bad. </seg>
<seg id="109"> And it was what I was feeling. </seg>
<seg id="110"> And it wasn't because of my attending; he was a doll. </seg>
<seg id="111"> He talked to the family, and I'm quite sure that he smoothed things over and made sure that I didn't get sued. </seg>
<seg id="112"> And I kept asking myself these questions. </seg>
<seg id="113"> Why didn't I ask my attending? Why did I send her home? </seg>
<seg id="114"> And then at my worst moments: Why did I make such a stupid mistake? </seg>
<seg id="115"> Why did I go into medicine? </seg>
<seg id="116"> Slowly but surely, it lifted. </seg>
<seg id="117"> I began to feel a bit better. </seg>
<seg id="118"> And on a cloudy day, there was a crack in the clouds and the sun started to come out and I wondered, maybe I could feel better again. </seg>
<seg id="119"> And I made myself a bargain that if only I redouble my efforts to be perfect and never make another mistake again, please make the voices stop. </seg>
<seg id="120"> And they did. </seg>
<seg id="121"> And I went back to work. </seg>
<seg id="122"> And then it happened again. </seg>
<seg id="123"> Two years later I was an attending in the emergency department at a community hospital just north of Toronto, and I saw a 25 year-old man with a sore throat. </seg>
<seg id="124"> It was busy, I was in a bit of a hurry. </seg>
<seg id="125"> He kept pointing here. </seg>
<seg id="126"> I looked at his throat, it was a little bit pink. </seg>
<seg id="127"> And I gave him a prescription for penicillin and sent him on his way. </seg>
<seg id="128"> And even as he was walking out the door, he was still sort of pointing to his throat. </seg>
<seg id="129"> And two days later I came to do my next emergency shift, and that's when my chief asked to speak to me quietly in her office. </seg>
<seg id="130"> And she said the three words: Do you remember? </seg>
<seg id="131"> "Do you remember that patient you saw with the sore throat?" </seg>
<seg id="132"> Well it turns out, he didn't have a strep throat. </seg>
<seg id="133"> He had a potentially life-threatening condition called epiglottitis. </seg>
<seg id="134"> You can Google it, but it's an infection, not of the throat, but of the upper airway, and it can actually cause the airway to close. </seg>
<seg id="135"> And fortunately he didn't die. </seg>
<seg id="136"> He was placed on intravenous antibiotics and he recovered after a few days. </seg>
<seg id="137"> And I went through the same period of shame and recriminations and felt cleansed and went back to work, until it happened again and again and again. </seg>
<seg id="138"> Twice in one emergency shift, I missed appendicitis. </seg>
<seg id="139"> Now that takes some doing, especially when you work in a hospital that at the time saw but 14 people a night. </seg>
<seg id="140"> Now in both cases, I didn't send them home and I don't think there was any gap in their care. </seg>
<seg id="141"> One I thought had a kidney stone. </seg>
<seg id="142"> I ordered a kidney X-ray. When it turned out to be normal, my colleague who was doing a reassessment of the patient noticed some tenderness in the right lower quadrant and called the surgeons. </seg>
<seg id="143"> The other one had a lot of diarrhea. </seg>
<seg id="144"> I ordered some fluids to rehydrate him and asked my colleague to reassess him. </seg>
<seg id="145"> And he did and when he noticed some tenderness in the right lower quadrant, called the surgeons. </seg>
<seg id="146"> In both cases, they had their operations and they did okay. </seg>
<seg id="147"> But each time, they were gnawing at me, eating at me. </seg>
<seg id="148"> And I'd like to be able to say to you that my worst mistakes only happened in the first five years of practice as many of my colleagues say, which is total B.S. </seg>
<seg id="149"> Some of my doozies have been in the last five years. </seg>
<seg id="150"> Alone, ashamed and unsupported. </seg>
<seg id="151"> Here's the problem: If I can't come clean and talk about my mistakes, if I can't find the still-small voice that tells me what really happened, how can I share it with my colleagues? </seg>
<seg id="152"> How can I teach them about what I did so that they don't do the same thing? </seg>
<seg id="153"> If I were to walk into a room -- like right now, I have no idea what you think of me. </seg>
<seg id="154"> When was the last time you heard somebody talk about failure after failure after failure? </seg>
<seg id="155"> Oh yeah, you go to a cocktail party and you might hear about some other doctor, but you're not going to hear somebody talking about their own mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="156"> If I were to walk into a room filled with my colleages and ask for their support right now and start to tell what I've just told you right now, I probably wouldn't get through two of those stories before they would start to get really uncomfortable, somebody would crack a joke, they'd change the subject and we would move on. </seg>
<seg id="157"> And in fact, if I knew and my colleagues knew that one of my orthopedic colleagues took off the wrong leg in my hospital, believe me, I'd have trouble making eye contact with that person. </seg>
<seg id="158"> That's the system that we have. </seg>
<seg id="159"> It's a complete denial of mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="160"> It's a system in which there are two kinds of physicians -- those who make mistakes and those who don't, those who can't handle sleep deprivation and those who can, those who have lousy outcomes and those who have great outcomes. </seg>
<seg id="161"> And it's almost like an ideological reaction, like the antibodies begin to attack that person. </seg>
<seg id="162"> And we have this idea that if we drive the people who make mistakes out of medicine, what will we be left with, but a safe system. </seg>
<seg id="163"> But there are two problems with that. </seg>
<seg id="164"> In my 20 years or so of medical broadcasting and journalism, I've made a personal study of medical malpractice and medical errors to learn everything I can, from one of the first articles I wrote for the Toronto Star to my show "White Coat, Black Art." </seg>
<seg id="165"> And what I've learned is that errors are absolutely ubiquitous. </seg>
<seg id="166"> We work in a system where errors happen every day, where one in 10 medications are either the wrong medication given in hospital or at the wrong dosage, where hospital-acquired infections are getting more and more numerous, causing havoc and death. </seg>
<seg id="167"> In this country, as many as 24,000 Canadians die of preventable medical errors. </seg>
<seg id="168"> In the United States, the Institute of Medicine pegged it at 100,000. </seg>
<seg id="169"> In both cases, these are gross underestimates, because we really aren't ferreting out the problem as we should. </seg>
<seg id="170"> And here's the thing. </seg>
<seg id="171"> In a hospital system where medical knowledge is doubling every two or three years, we can't keep up with it. </seg>
<seg id="172"> Sleep deprivation is absolutely pervasive. </seg>
<seg id="173"> We can't get rid of it. </seg>
<seg id="174"> We have our cognitive biases, so that I can take a perfect history on a patient with chest pain. </seg>
<seg id="175"> Now take the same patient with chest pain, make them moist and garrulous and put a little bit of alcohol on their breath, and suddenly my history is laced with contempt. </seg>
<seg id="176"> I don't take the same history. </seg>
<seg id="177"> I'm not a robot; I don't do things the same way each time. </seg>
<seg id="178"> And my patients aren't cars; they don't tell me their symptoms in the same way each time. </seg>
<seg id="179"> Given all of that, mistakes are inevitable. </seg>
<seg id="180"> So if you take the system, as I was taught, and weed out all the error-prone health professionals, well there won't be anybody left. </seg>
<seg id="181"> And you know that business about people not wanting to talk about their worst cases? </seg>
<seg id="182"> On my show, on "White Coat, Black Art," I made it a habit of saying, "Here's my worst mistake," I would say to everybody from paramedics to the chief of cardiac surgery, "Here's my worst mistake," blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, "What about yours?" and I would point the microphone towards them. </seg>
<seg id="183"> And their pupils would dilate, they would recoil, then they would look down and swallow hard and start to tell me their stories. </seg>
<seg id="184"> They want to tell their stories. They want to share their stories. </seg>
<seg id="185"> They want to be able to say, "Look, don't make the same mistake I did." </seg>
<seg id="186"> What they need is an environment to be able to do that. </seg>
<seg id="187"> What they need is a redefined medical culture. </seg>
<seg id="188"> And it starts with one physician at a time. </seg>
<seg id="189"> The redefined physician is human, knows she's human, accepts it, isn't proud of making mistakes, but strives to learn one thing from what happened that she can teach to somebody else. </seg>
<seg id="190"> She shares her experience with others. </seg>
<seg id="191"> She's supportive when other people talk about their mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="192"> And she points out other people's mistakes, not in a gotcha way, but in a loving, supportive way so that everybody can benefit. </seg>
<seg id="193"> And she works in a culture of medicine that acknowledges that human beings run the system, and when human beings run the system, they will make mistakes from time to time. </seg>
<seg id="194"> So the system is evolving to create backups that make it easier to detect those mistakes that humans inevitably make and also fosters in a loving, supportive way places where everybody who is observing in the health care system can actually point out things that could be potential mistakes and is rewarded for doing so, and especially people like me, when we do make mistakes, we're rewarded for coming clean. </seg>
<seg id="195"> My name is Brian Goldman. </seg>
<seg id="196"> I am a redefined physician. </seg>
<seg id="197"> I'm human. I make mistakes. </seg>
<seg id="198"> I'm sorry about that, but I strive to learn one thing that I can pass on to other people. </seg>
<seg id="199"> I still don't know what you think of me, but I can live with that. </seg>
<seg id="200"> And let me close with three words of my own: I do remember. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1373" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_pauly_the_ocean_s_shifting_baseline.html</url>
<description>The ocean has degraded within our lifetimes, as shown in the decreasing average size of fish. And yet, as Daniel Pauly shows us onstage at Mission Blue, each time the baseline drops, we call it the new "normal." At what point do we stop readjusting downward?</description>
<keywords>data,oceans,science</keywords>
<talkid>1373</talkid>
<title>Daniel Pauly: The ocean's shifting baseline</title>
<seg id="1"> I'm going to speak about a tiny, little idea. </seg>
<seg id="2"> And this is about shifting baseline. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And because the idea can be explained in one minute, I will tell you three stories before to fill in the time. </seg>
<seg id="4"> And the first story is about Charles Darwin, one of my heroes. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And he was here, as you well know, in '35. </seg>
<seg id="6"> And you'd think he was chasing finches, but he wasn't. </seg>
<seg id="7"> He was actually collecting fish. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And he described one of them as very "common." </seg>
<seg id="9"> This was the sailfin grouper. </seg>
<seg id="10"> A big fishery was run on it until the '80s. </seg>
<seg id="11"> Now the fish is on the IUCN Red List. </seg>
<seg id="12"> Now this story, we have heard it lots of times on Galapagos and other places, so there is nothing particular about it. </seg>
<seg id="13"> But the point is, we still come to Galapagos. </seg>
<seg id="14"> We still think it is pristine. </seg>
<seg id="15"> The brochures still say it is untouched. </seg>
<seg id="16"> So what happens here? </seg>
<seg id="17"> The second story, also to illustrate another concept, is called shifting waistline. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Because I was there in '71, studying a lagoon in West Africa. </seg>
<seg id="19"> I was there because I grew up in Europe and I wanted later to work in Africa. </seg>
<seg id="20"> And I thought I could blend in. </seg>
<seg id="21"> And I got a big sunburn, and I was convinced that I was really not from there. </seg>
<seg id="22"> This was my first sunburn. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And the lagoon was surrounded by palm trees, as you can see, and a few mangrove. </seg>
<seg id="24"> And it had tilapia about 20 centimeters, a species of tilapia called blackchin tilapia. </seg>
<seg id="25"> And the fisheries for this tilapia sustained lots of fish and they had a good time and they earned more than average in Ghana. </seg>
<seg id="26"> When I went there 27 years later, the fish had shrunk to half of their size. </seg>
<seg id="27"> They were maturing at five centimeters. </seg>
<seg id="28"> They had been pushed genetically. </seg>
<seg id="29"> There were still fishes. </seg>
<seg id="30"> They were still kind of happy. </seg>
<seg id="31"> And the fish also were happy to be there. </seg>
<seg id="32"> So nothing has changed, but everything has changed. </seg>
<seg id="33"> My third little story is that I was an accomplice in the introduction of trawling in Southeast Asia. </seg>
<seg id="34"> In the '70s -- well, beginning in the '60s -- Europe did lots of development projects. </seg>
<seg id="35"> Fish development meant imposing on countries that had already 100,000 fishers And this boat, quite ugly, is called the Mutiara 4. </seg>
<seg id="36"> And I went sailing on it, and we did surveys throughout the southern South China sea and especially the Java Sea. </seg>
<seg id="37"> And what we caught, we didn't have words for it. </seg>
<seg id="38"> What we caught, I know now, is the bottom of the sea. </seg>
<seg id="39"> And 90 percent of our catch were sponges, other animals that are fixed on the bottom. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And actually most of the fish, they are a little spot on the debris, the piles of debris, were coral reef fish. </seg>
<seg id="41"> Essentially the bottom of the sea came onto the deck and then was thrown down. </seg>
<seg id="42"> And these pictures are extraordinary because this transition is very rapid. </seg>
<seg id="43"> Within a year, you do a survey and then commercial fishing begins. </seg>
<seg id="44"> The bottom is transformed from, in this case, a hard bottom or soft coral into a muddy mess. </seg>
<seg id="45"> This is a dead turtle. </seg>
<seg id="46"> They were not eaten, they were thrown away because they were dead. </seg>
<seg id="47"> And one time we caught a live one. </seg>
<seg id="48"> It was not drowned yet. </seg>
<seg id="49"> And then they wanted to kill it because it was good to eat. </seg>
<seg id="50"> This mountain of debris is actually collected by fishers every time they go into an area that's never been fished. </seg>
<seg id="51"> But it's not documented. </seg>
<seg id="52"> We transform the world, but we don't remember it. </seg>
<seg id="53"> We adjust our baseline to the new level, and we don't recall what was there. </seg>
<seg id="54"> If you generalize this, something like this happens. </seg>
<seg id="55"> You have on the y axis some good thing: biodiversity, numbers of orca, the greenness of your country, the water supply. </seg>
<seg id="56"> And over time it changes -- it changes because people do things, or naturally. </seg>
<seg id="57"> Every generation will use the images that they got at the beginning of their conscious lives as a standard and will extrapolate forward. </seg>
<seg id="58"> And the difference then, they perceive as a loss. </seg>
<seg id="59"> But they don't perceive what happened before as a loss. </seg>
<seg id="60"> You can have a succession of changes. </seg>
<seg id="61"> At the end you want to sustain miserable leftovers. </seg>
<seg id="62"> And that, to a large extent, is what we want to do now. </seg>
<seg id="63"> We want to sustain things that are gone or things that are not the way they were. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Now one should think this problem affected people certainly when in predatory societies, they killed animals and they didn't know they had done so after a few generations. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Because, obviously, an animal that is very abundant, before it gets extinct, it becomes rare. </seg>
<seg id="66"> So you don't lose abundant animals. </seg>
<seg id="67"> You always lose rare animals. </seg>
<seg id="68"> And therefore they're not perceived as a big loss. </seg>
<seg id="69"> Over time, we concentrate on large animals, and in a sea that means the big fish. </seg>
<seg id="70"> They become rarer because we fish them. </seg>
<seg id="71"> Over time we have a few fish left and we think this is the baseline. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And the question is, why do people accept this? </seg>
<seg id="73"> Well because they don't know that it was different. </seg>
<seg id="74"> And in fact, lots of people, scientists, will contest that it was really different. </seg>
<seg id="75"> And they will contest this because the evidence presented in an earlier mode is not in the way they would like the evidence presented. </seg>
<seg id="76"> For example, the anecdote that some present, as Captain so-and-so observed lots of fish in this area cannot be used or is usually not utilized by fishery scientists, because it's not "scientific." </seg>
<seg id="77"> So you have a situation where people don't know the past, even though we live in literate societies, because they don't trust the sources of the past. </seg>
<seg id="78"> And hence, the enormous role that a marine protected area can play. </seg>
<seg id="79"> Because with marine protected areas, we actually recreate the past. </seg>
<seg id="80"> We recreate the past that people cannot conceive because the baseline has shifted and is extremely low. </seg>
<seg id="81"> That is for people who can see a marine protected area and who can benefit from the insight that it provides, which enables them to reset their baseline. </seg>
<seg id="82"> How about the people who can't do that because they have no access -- the people in the Midwest for example? </seg>
<seg id="83"> There I think that the arts and film can perhaps fill the gap, and simulation. </seg>
<seg id="84"> This is a simulation of Chesapeake Bay. </seg>
<seg id="85"> There were gray whales in Chesapeake Bay a long time ago -- 500 years ago. </seg>
<seg id="86"> And you will have noticed that the hues and tones are like "Avatar." </seg>
<seg id="87"> And if you think about "Avatar," if you think of why people were so touched by it -- never mind the Pocahontas story -- why so touched by the imagery? </seg>
<seg id="88"> Because it evokes something that in a sense has been lost. </seg>
<seg id="89"> And so my recommendation, it's the only one I will provide, is for Cameron to do "Avatar II" underwater. </seg>
<seg id="90"> Thank you very much. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1328" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/mikko_hypponen_three_types_of_online_attack.html</url>
<description>Cybercrime expert Mikko Hypponen talks us through three types of online attack on our privacy and data -- and only two are considered crimes. "Do we blindly trust any future government? Because any right we give away, we give away for good." &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
<keywords>Internet,crime,data,politics,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1328</talkid>
<title>Mikko Hypponen: Three types of online attack</title>
<seg id="1"> In the 1980s in the communist Eastern Germany, if you owned a typewriter, you had to register it with the government. </seg>
<seg id="2"> You had to register a sample sheet of text out of the typewriter. </seg>
<seg id="3"> And this was done so the government could track where text was coming from. </seg>
<seg id="4"> If they found a paper which had the wrong kind of thought, they could track down who created that thought. </seg>
<seg id="5"> And we in the West couldn't understand how anybody could do this, how much this would restrict freedom of speech. </seg>
<seg id="6"> We would never do that in our own countries. </seg>
<seg id="7"> But today in 2011, if you go and buy a color laser printer from any major laser printer manufacturer and print a page, that page will end up having slight yellow dots printed on every single page in a pattern which makes the page unique to you and to your printer. </seg>
<seg id="8"> This is happening to us today. </seg>
<seg id="9"> And nobody seems to be making a fuss about it. </seg>
<seg id="10"> And this is an example of the ways that our own governments are using technology against us, the citizens. </seg>
<seg id="11"> And this is one of the main three sources of online problems today. </seg>
<seg id="12"> If we take a look at what's really happening in the online world, we can group the attacks based on the attackers. </seg>
<seg id="13"> We have three main groups. </seg>
<seg id="14"> We have online criminals. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Like here, we have Mr. Dimitry Golubov from the city of Kiev in Ukraine. </seg>
<seg id="16"> And the motives of online criminals are very easy to understand. </seg>
<seg id="17"> These guys make money. </seg>
<seg id="18"> They use online attacks to make lots of money, and lots and lots of it. </seg>
<seg id="19"> We actually have several cases of millionaires online, multimillionaires, who made money with their attacks. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Here's Vladimir Tsastsin form Tartu in Estonia. </seg>
<seg id="21"> This is Alfred Gonzalez. </seg>
<seg id="22"> This is Stephen Watt. </seg>
<seg id="23"> This is Bjorn Sundin. </seg>
<seg id="24"> This is Matthew Anderson, Tariq Al-Daour and so on and so on. </seg>
<seg id="25"> These guys make their fortunes online, but they make it through the illegal means of using things like banking trojans to steal money from our bank accounts while we do online banking, or with keyloggers to collect our credit card information while we are doing online shopping from an infected computer. </seg>
<seg id="26"> The U.S. Secret Service, two months ago, froze the Swiss bank account of Mr. Sam Jain right here, and that bank account had 14.9 million U.S. dollars on it when it was frozen. </seg>
<seg id="27"> Mr. Jain himself is on the loose; nobody knows where he is. </seg>
<seg id="28"> And I claim it's already today that it's more likely for any of us to become the victim of a crime online than here in the real world. </seg>
<seg id="29"> And it's very obvious that this is only going to get worse. </seg>
<seg id="30"> In the future, the majority of crime will be happening online. </seg>
<seg id="31"> The second major group of attackers that we are watching today are not motivated by money. </seg>
<seg id="32"> They're motivated by something else -- motivated by protests, motivated by an opinion, motivated by the laughs. </seg>
<seg id="33"> Groups like Anonymous have risen up over the last 12 months and have become a major player in the field of online attacks. </seg>
<seg id="34"> So those are the three main attackers: criminals who do it for the money, hacktivists like Anonymous doing it for the protest, but then the last group are nation states, governments doing the attacks. </seg>
<seg id="35"> And then we look at cases like what happened in DigiNotar. </seg>
<seg id="36"> This is a prime example of what happens when governments attack against their own citizens. </seg>
<seg id="37"> DigiNotar is a Certificate Authority from The Netherlands -- or actually, it was. </seg>
<seg id="38"> It was running into bankruptcy last fall because they were hacked into. </seg>
<seg id="39"> Somebody broke in and they hacked it thoroughly. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And I asked last week in a meeting with Dutch government representatives, I asked one of the leaders of the team whether he found plausible that people died because of the DigiNotar hack. </seg>
<seg id="41"> And his answer was yes. </seg>
<seg id="42"> So how do people die as the result of a hack like this? </seg>
<seg id="43"> Well DigiNotar is a C.A. </seg>
<seg id="44"> They sell certificates. </seg>
<seg id="45"> What do you do with certificates? </seg>
<seg id="46"> Well you need a certificate if you have a website that has https, SSL encrypted services, services like Gmail. </seg>
<seg id="47"> Now we all, or a big part of us, use Gmail or one of their competitors, but these services are especially popular in totalitarian states like Iran, where dissidents use foreign services like Gmail because they know they are more trustworthy than the local services and they are encrypted over SSL connections, so the local government can't snoop on their discussions. </seg>
<seg id="48"> Except they can if they hack into a foreign C.A. </seg>
<seg id="49"> and issue rogue certificates. </seg>
<seg id="50"> And this is exactly what happened with the case of DigiNotar. </seg>
<seg id="51"> What about Arab Spring and things that have been happening, for example, in Egypt? </seg>
<seg id="52"> Well in Egypt, the rioters looted the headquarters of the Egyptian secret police in April 2011, and when they were looting the building they found lots of papers. </seg>
<seg id="53"> Among those papers, was this binder entitled "FINFISHER." </seg>
<seg id="54"> And within that binder were notes from a company based in Germany which had sold the Egyptian government a set of tools for intercepting -- and in very large scale -- all the communication of the citizens of the country. </seg>
<seg id="55"> They had sold this tool for 280,000 Euros to the Egyptian government. </seg>
<seg id="56"> The company headquarters are right here. </seg>
<seg id="57"> So Western governments are providing totalitarian governments with tools to do this against their own citizens. </seg>
<seg id="58"> But Western governments are doing it to themselves as well. </seg>
<seg id="59"> For example, in Germany, just a couple of weeks ago the so-called State Trojan was found, which was a trojan used by German government officials to investigate their own citizens. </seg>
<seg id="60"> If you are a suspect in a criminal case, well it's pretty obvious, your phone will be tapped. </seg>
<seg id="61"> But today, it goes beyond that. </seg>
<seg id="62"> They will tap your Internet connection. </seg>
<seg id="63"> They will even use tools like State Trojan to infect your computer with a trojan, which enables them to watch all your communication, to listen to your online discussions, to collect your passwords. </seg>
<seg id="64"> Now when we think deeper about things like these, the obvious response from people should be that, "Okay, that sounds bad, but that doesn't really affect me because I'm a legal citizen. </seg>
<seg id="65"> Why should I worry? </seg>
<seg id="66"> Because I have nothing to hide." </seg>
<seg id="67"> And this is an argument, which doesn't make sense. </seg>
<seg id="68"> Privacy is implied. </seg>
<seg id="69"> Privacy is not up for discussion. </seg>
<seg id="70"> This is not a question between privacy against security. </seg>
<seg id="71"> It's a question of freedom against control. </seg>
<seg id="72"> And while we might trust our governments right now, right here in 2011, any right we give away will be given away for good. </seg>
<seg id="73"> And do we trust, do we blindly trust, any future government, a government we might have 50 years from now? </seg>
<seg id="74"> And these are the questions that we have to worry about for the next 50 years. </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="1404" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/ayah_bdeir_building_blocks_that_blink_beep_and_teach.html</url>
<description>Imagine a set of electronics as easy to play with as Legos. Fellow Ayah Bdeir introduces littleBits, a set of simple, interchangeable blocks that make programming as simple and important a part of creativity as snapping blocks together.</description>
<keywords>creativity,education,technology</keywords>
<talkid>1404</talkid>
<title>Ayah Bdeir: Building blocks that blink, beep and teach</title>
<seg id="1"> This may sound strange, but I'm a big fan of the concrete block. </seg>
<seg id="2"> The first concrete blocks were manufactured in 1868 with a very simple idea: modules made of cement of a fixed measurement that fit together. </seg>
<seg id="3"> Very quickly concrete blocks became the most-used construction unit in the world. </seg>
<seg id="4"> They enabled us to to build things that were larger than us, buildings, bridges, one brick at a time. </seg>
<seg id="5"> Essentially concrete blocks had become the building block of our time. </seg>
<seg id="6"> Almost a hundred years later in 1947, LEGO came up with this. </seg>
<seg id="7"> It was called the Automatic Binding Brick. </seg>
<seg id="8"> And in a few short years, LEGO bricks took place in every household. </seg>
<seg id="9"> It's estimated that over 400 billion bricks have been produced -- or 75 bricks for every person on the planet. </seg>
<seg id="10"> You don't have to be an engineer to make beautiful houses, beautiful bridges, beautiful buildings. </seg>
<seg id="11"> LEGO made it accessible. </seg>
<seg id="12"> LEGO has essentially taken the concrete block, the building block of the world, and made it into the building block of our imagination. </seg>
<seg id="13"> Meanwhile the exact same year, at Bell Labs the next revolution was about to be announced, the next building block. </seg>
<seg id="14"> The transistor was a small plastic unit that would take us from a world of static bricks piled on top of each other to a world where everything was interactive. </seg>
<seg id="15"> Like the concrete block, the transistor allows you to build much larger, more complex circuits, one brick at a time. </seg>
<seg id="16"> But there's a main difference: The transistor was only for experts. </seg>
<seg id="17"> I personally don't accept this, that the building block of our time is reserved for experts, so I decided to change that. </seg>
<seg id="18"> Eight years ago when I was at the Media Lab, I started exploring this idea of how to put the power of engineers in the hands of artists and designers. </seg>
<seg id="19"> A few years ago I started developing littleBits. </seg>
<seg id="20"> Let me show you how they work. </seg>
<seg id="21"> LittleBits are electronic modules with each one specific function. </seg>
<seg id="22"> They're pre-engineered to be light, sound, motors and sensors. </seg>
<seg id="23"> And the best part about it is they snap together with magnets. </seg>
<seg id="24"> So you can't put them the wrong way. </seg>
<seg id="25"> The bricks are color-coded. </seg>
<seg id="26"> Green is output, blue is power, pink is input and orange is wire. </seg>
<seg id="27"> So all you need to do is snap a blue to a green and very quickly you can start making larger circuits. </seg>
<seg id="28"> You put a blue to a green, you can make light. </seg>
<seg id="29"> You can put a knob in between and now you've made a little dimmer. </seg>
<seg id="30"> Switch out the knob for a pulse module, which is here, and now you've made a little blinker. </seg>
<seg id="31"> Add this buzzer for some extra punch and you've created a noise machine. </seg>
<seg id="32"> I'm going to stop that. </seg>
<seg id="33"> So beyond simple play, littleBits are actually pretty powerful. </seg>
<seg id="34"> Instead of having to program, to wire, to solder, littleBits allow you to program using very simple intuitive gestures. </seg>
<seg id="35"> So to make this blink faster or slower, you would just turn this knob and basically make it pulse faster or slower. </seg>
<seg id="36"> The idea behind littleBits is that it's a growing library. </seg>
<seg id="37"> We want to make every single interaction in the world into a ready-to-use brick. </seg>
<seg id="38"> Lights, sounds, solar panels, motors -- everything should be accessible. </seg>
<seg id="39"> We've been giving littleBits to kids and seeing them play with them. </seg>
<seg id="40"> And it's been an incredible experience. </seg>
<seg id="41"> The nicest thing is how they start to understand the electronics around them from everyday that they don't learn at schools. </seg>
<seg id="42"> For example, how a nightlight works, or why an elevator door stays open, or how an iPod responds to touch. </seg>
<seg id="43"> We've also been taking littleBits to design schools. </seg>
<seg id="44"> So for example, we've had designers with no experience with electronics whatsoever start to play with littleBits as a material. </seg>
<seg id="45"> Here you see, with felt and paper water bottles, we have Geordie making ... </seg>
<seg id="46"> A few weeks ago we took littleBits to RISD and gave them to some designers with no experience in engineering whatsoever -- just cardboard, wood and paper -- and told them "Make something." </seg>
<seg id="47"> Here's an example of a project they made, a motion-activated confetti canon ball. </seg>
<seg id="48"> But wait, this is actually my favorite project. </seg>
<seg id="49"> It's a lobster made of playdough that's afraid of the dark. </seg>
<seg id="50"> To these non-engineers, littleBits became another material, electronics became just another material. </seg>
<seg id="51"> And we want to make this material accessible to everyone. </seg>
<seg id="52"> So littleBits is open-source. </seg>
<seg id="53"> You can go on the website, download all the design files, make them yourself. </seg>
<seg id="54"> We want to encourage a world of creators, of inventors, of contributors, because this world that we live in, this interactive world, is ours. </seg>
<seg id="55"> So go ahead and start inventing. </seg>
<seg id="56"> Thank you. </seg>
</doc>
</refset>
</mteval>
